[
  {
    "id": "66ecff43-bf0a-481c-b5da-db3ca64fed39",
    "front": "**Def**: put your name on an official list (enrol = register to join a course, school, etc.).\n**Farsi**: ثبت نام کردن",
    "back": "register (at/for/with sth)",
    "examples": [
      "How do I register with a GP?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1819ed4b-95bd-4323-a82c-133cbf91d844",
    "front": "**Def**: be in charge of (a meeting).\n**Farsi**: ریاست (جلسه) را بر عهده داشتن",
    "back": "chair (a meeting) V",
    "examples": [
      "He also chairs meetings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "021af7b0-b5e8-44a6-b69b-2a2e9cde80d1",
    "front": "**Def**: a lawyer who gives legal advice and prepares documents.\n**Farsi**: وکیل دادگستری",
    "back": "solicitor",
    "examples": [
      "right to legal advice from a solicitor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef2137e7-bfd4-4515-9be2-3a5d35904af3",
    "front": "**Def**: send sb away from court until their trial (remanded in custody = sent to prison until the trial).\n**Farsi**: بازداشت موقت کردن، به زندان فرستادن (تا محاکمه)",
    "back": "remand sb",
    "examples": [
      "whether you should be remanded in custody"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c756d576-f713-4581-88fa-c676a49239cf",
    "front": "**Def**: commonly used in reference to things within a country (syn domestic).\n**Farsi**: خارجی (یا داخلی در متون اقتصادی و سیاسی)",
    "back": "external",
    "examples": [
      "She focuses on external affairs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5d68d6bf-ae9b-4375-81f8-729d08eb2205",
    "front": "**Def**: not needing or depending on other people or things.\n**Farsi**: خودکفا، مستقل",
    "back": "self-contained",
    "examples": [
      "The system operates in five self-contained communities."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "207e8859-94f6-441a-818c-175968125faa",
    "front": "**Def**: (AME) the practice of ordering people to serve in the armed forces (syn conscription).\n**Farsi**: سربازی اجباری (بیشتر آمریکایی)",
    "back": "the draft",
    "examples": [
      "He avoided the draft by leaving the country."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "712d902a-8815-423e-b17c-c84f2c91be77",
    "front": "**Def**: An investigation (probe) into an agreement to sell weapons (arms deal).\n**Farsi**: تحقیق در مورد معامله تسلیحاتی",
    "back": "Arms deal probe",
    "examples": [
      "The newspaper reported an arms deal probe."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "feffef3f-307b-4df6-8986-02920ebfdb78",
    "front": "**Def**: prove that somebody is innocent of doing something wrong.\n**Farsi**: تبرئه کردن",
    "back": "clear sb of sth",
    "examples": [
      "The doctor was cleared of negligence."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "23710e33-60d9-4b19-815f-506ab846fbe7",
    "front": "**Def**: unfairly changing the agreed rules or conditions during a course of action.\n**Farsi**: تغییر ناعادلانه قوانین (در میانه بازی)",
    "back": "moving the goalposts",
    "examples": [
      "MPs are now accusing the government of moving the goalposts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "456b9d20-542c-4835-99ab-7467423e70f8",
    "front": "**Def**: fixed or stuck in something.\n**Farsi**: گیر کردن، جاسازی شدن",
    "back": "lodge (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "A piece of glass lodged in the tyre."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ebb8432d-9663-4757-a55a-464f6c17b9af",
    "front": "**Def**: spend more than someone else.\n**Farsi**: بیشتر خرج کردن",
    "back": "outspend (prefix out-)",
    "examples": [
      "Men over 50 outspend women."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e304650-781e-4588-9c99-6c737710b109",
    "front": "**Def**: if something happens against all odds, it happens or succeeds although it seemed impossible or very unlikely.\n**Farsi**: با وجود تمام مشکلات و شانس‌های کم",
    "back": "against all (the) odds",
    "examples": [
      "He survived against all odds."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "10aaafbb-3048-440c-8ba9-789b85fb8776",
    "front": "**Def**: try to find information about people's private lives.\n**Farsi**: سرک کشیدن، فضولی کردن",
    "back": "pry into sth",
    "examples": [
      "Do they pry into the private lives of people?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7f09e845-bd24-449a-b5a1-8b89d4691e08",
    "front": "**Def**: if somebody allegedly does something, another person says they have done it, even though this has not been proved.\n**Farsi**: به ادعای، ظاهراً",
    "back": "allegedly",
    "examples": [
      "He allegedly lost all his money."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "30380380-cdf3-455b-be71-2239eefe2982",
    "front": "**Def**: be faced with a new and difficult task that you're not prepared for.\n**Farsi**: با کار دشوار و ناگهانی روبرو شدن",
    "back": "deep end (thrown in at the deep end)",
    "examples": [
      "They were thrown in at the deep end."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9aceb02d-6843-4d60-b8f2-351d5a4351a6",
    "front": "**Def**: If your mouth waters, you produce saliva and want to eat. mouth-watering ADJ.\n**Farsi**: آب دهان راه افتادن، هوس کردن",
    "back": "mouth water (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "The smells... were making my mouth water."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1ed7c94a-1f56-4ca9-8d4d-c7765e7e1bc0",
    "front": "**Def**: an illness in a part of the body.\n**Farsi**: اختلال/عارضه",
    "back": "disorder",
    "examples": [
      "Possible side effects may include stomach disorders."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef1a8fca-af55-4379-a2ea-8f175fad8787",
    "front": "**Def**: a quality that makes other people like you and be attracted to you. charismatic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: جذابیت/کشش",
    "back": "charisma",
    "examples": [
      "Does she have the necessary charisma?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c3fea71-f16b-4f7c-afbd-6ab28073355a",
    "front": "**Def**: tell sb personal information because you trust them.\n**Farsi**: راز دل گفتن/اعتماد کردن",
    "back": "confide in sb",
    "examples": [
      "She confided in me about her problems with her husband.",
      "I hope you know that you can always confide in me.",
      "They're prepared to confide in me now."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f232bb54-31f5-47c6-b338-93ff68201e43",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb information about sth, especially sth that has been secret.\n**Farsi**: افشا کردن/فاش ساختن",
    "back": "disclose sth (to sb) (SYN reveal sth)",
    "examples": [
      "if you disclose too much about yourself."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e275249b-ccd2-4753-a72d-ca682fdb99ee",
    "front": "**Def**: does her fair share of the work or effort (implies she is competent).\n**Farsi**: وظیفه‌اش را به طور کامل انجام می‌دهد، سهم خود را ادا می‌کند",
    "back": "pulls her weight",
    "examples": [
      "She's great, and she always pulls her weight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "15f6b397-4fc6-46fe-9f53-02f37aff831e",
    "front": "**Def**: the hard work and effort that sb puts into an activity because they care about it. dedicate sth/yourself to sth/sb v. dedicated ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فداکاری/تعهد",
    "back": "dedication (N)",
    "examples": [
      "I admired him for his dedication."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a985249c-adc7-4817-9e57-37e203eddf20",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: دیدن/تلقی کردن",
    "back": "view (v, FML)",
    "examples": [
      "talking with your mouth full is viewed as being discourteous."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "22322435-7af0-472d-bc7d-f70728374f22",
    "front": "**Def**: encourage someone to behave badly.\n**Farsi**: به بیراهه کشاندن، منحرف کردن",
    "back": "lead sb astray",
    "examples": [
      "His older friends led him astray."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d6cabff6-9f0a-4b96-884b-688a9ef744fb",
    "front": "**Def**: an effect or influence on sth.\n**Farsi**: تأثیر/نفوذ",
    "back": "impact (on sth)",
    "examples": [
      "various factors have an impact on our lives."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "feddb988-ac3a-49ba-a8e4-8118bd4395bb",
    "front": "**Def**: be involved and influential in developing sth.\n**Farsi**: نقش داشتن/مؤثر بودن",
    "back": "play a part (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Parents play a crucial part."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c6f8ab32-095e-4a9b-b56f-68fb22c149c2",
    "front": "**Def**: be very interested in sth as a hobby.\n**Farsi**: شدیداً به چیزی علاقه داشتن",
    "back": "be into sth (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "They're both into extreme sports."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fcc4e92c-3226-41a8-a4ff-1ccb29964da5",
    "front": "**Def**: a negative response to something because you're angry you can't have it.\n**Farsi**: حسادت، انگور ترش (انتقاد از چیزی که نمی‌توانید داشته باشید)",
    "back": "sour grapes (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "He was only rude about the party because he wasn't invited. It was just sour grapes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "22e1d901-1850-409c-9076-7f95a2a74868",
    "front": "**Def**: cook quickly by stirring in a small amount of hot oil.\n**Farsi**: تفت دادن (با حرارت بالا و روغن کم)",
    "back": "stir-fry",
    "examples": [
      "I like to stir-fry vegetables."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b5dd35a-94dc-458f-9c0b-a3b85131a2a9",
    "front": "**Def**: relax.\n**Farsi**: راحت بودن، سخت نگرفتن",
    "back": "take it easy (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "We just want to take it easy and do very little."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "440ec442-50ee-4268-9a8d-2d8117674245",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who feels uneasy and out of place in their surroundings.\n**Farsi**: ماهی بیرون از آب (احساس ناراحتی و بی‌جایی)",
    "back": "a fish out of water (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "Frankly, I felt like a fish out of water."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e693633-f5f4-4b45-80af-f45d1486017d",
    "front": "**Def**: be beaten and can no longer take part. SYN knock sb out of sth (usually passive).\n**Farsi**: حذف شدن (از مسابقات)",
    "back": "eliminate sb from sth",
    "examples": [
      "If you are eliminated, that is the end of your competition."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3bcb435f-2686-4630-bfa4-009ad9b7896c",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to be cured. OPP incurable.\n**Farsi**: قابل درمان",
    "back": "curable ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from cure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "754f9c66-271c-4b45-8e87-219b860b9da5",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth happen. SYNS create sth, cause sth.\n**Farsi**: موجب شدن، به وجود آوردن",
    "back": "bring sth about",
    "examples": [
      "aims to bring about sweeping... changes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dc82a570-c245-4d73-ab16-4a47a3a0be2d",
    "front": "**Def**: become very nervous or upset and unable to perform.\n**Farsi**: از هم پاشیدن، دستپاچه شدن",
    "back": "go to pieces (idiom, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "When the opposition put us under pressure, we just went to pieces."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "63abbd28-95ed-4eb2-994a-d833b77ec894",
    "front": "**Def**: (of an actor) not suitable for the role they have been given.\n**Farsi**: انتخاب نامناسب بازیگر (برای نقش)",
    "back": "miscast",
    "examples": [
      "Jack Burns was totally miscast as the romantic lead."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d449399d-e1f6-4d07-ac88-03973ca55343",
    "front": "**Def**: a line of bushes growing close together around a garden or field.\n**Farsi**: پرچین، شمشاد",
    "back": "hedge",
    "examples": [
      "Tidy hedges and fallen leaves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dc0cb545-a226-45eb-b8bd-5755f501a8e3",
    "front": "**Def**: Not able to be cured.\n**Farsi**: لاعلاج",
    "back": "incurable ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from cure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "935b7b1d-a3ac-4989-9a34-a9669eba036b",
    "front": "**Def**: a sudden desire to do something without thinking about the results (buy sth on impulse).\n**Farsi**: انگیزه ناگهانی، تصمیم آنی",
    "back": "impulse (to do sth)",
    "examples": [
      "I always buy things on impulse."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e62a9c6a-498a-4be5-8ec3-7bbed0140046",
    "front": "**Def**: forming a small group and not letting others join in. clique N.\n**Farsi**: باندباز، گروه گرا",
    "back": "cliquey (adj, INF, DISAPPROVING)",
    "examples": [
      "Her friends are all a bit cliquey as well."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "407adc3a-ca8e-408a-84c4-d478f1cf5a61",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth that has been decided start to happen. SYNS carry out sth, put sth into practice.\n**Farsi**: اجرا کردن، به کار بستن",
    "back": "implement sth",
    "examples": [
      "have their support before they are implemented."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd41cf5d-a020-4658-b52d-78b3d189da4e",
    "front": "**Def**: unwanted email advertisements; you block spam (= prevent it) with anti-spam filters.\n**Farsi**: هرزنامه، اسپم",
    "back": "spam",
    "examples": [
      "I hate spam"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "467657aa-5ea2-4462-80ab-c31e76a521b0",
    "front": "**Def**: destroy or get rid of sth (bad) completely. SYN wipe sth out.\n**Farsi**: ریشه کن کردن، از بین بردن",
    "back": "eradicate sth",
    "examples": [
      "Vaccines have almost eradicated some of these conditions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "12f82455-194f-4fda-9db5-4b25a6c96cd5",
    "front": "**Def**: limit the size, number, or amount of sth.\n**Farsi**: محدود کردن، منحصر کردن",
    "back": "restrict sth (to sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Diagnostic tools were restricted to stethoscopes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e5ef57fc-6cb6-40ce-8e80-4f340311fcc7",
    "front": "**Def**: a substance which is put into the blood and protects the body from disease.\n**Farsi**: واکسن",
    "back": "vaccine",
    "examples": [
      "Vaccines have almost eradicated some of these conditions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0f5b1726-69ab-44c0-9e8d-2d1a0c94a999",
    "front": "**Def**: use a computer to connect secretly to sb else's computer and find or change information on it.\n**Farsi**: نفوذ کردن (هک کردن)",
    "back": "hack into sth",
    "examples": [
      "They hacked into the bank and stole thousands."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4962520e-5ab8-459e-bb81-182c38fc66bb",
    "front": "**Def**: be made to leave the place where you live and go somewhere else.\n**Farsi**: ریشه‌کن شدن، آواره شدن",
    "back": "be uprooted",
    "examples": [
      "Following the flooding, many villagers were uprooted."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b087686-5f4a-4571-9525-6c45e294e31d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to happen.\n**Farsi**: محتمل، در شرف وقوع",
    "back": "on the cards",
    "examples": [
      "A takeover bid is on the cards."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b78dc0e0-a5f0-41ec-8c21-856fecfd5a2f",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a person or policy) creating or controlling a situation by making things happen, rather than waiting for things to happen.\n**Farsi**: کنش‌گرا، پیشگیرانه",
    "back": "proactive",
    "examples": [
      "This would be proactive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c3566ff4-473e-4e9a-8410-ab19b07a9b52",
    "front": "**Def**: spend less money because there will be less available.\n**Farsi**: صرفه‌جویی کردن، کمربندها را بستن",
    "back": "tighten your belt",
    "examples": [
      "We will all have to tighten our belts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "778a6349-b2b5-4b76-b21c-03dd5accbf02",
    "front": "**Def**: with the ability to understand a situation only after it has happened (with the benefit of hindsight).\n**Farsi**: با در نظر گرفتن نتیجه/با نگاه عقل پس از واقعه",
    "back": "with hindsight",
    "examples": [
      "With hindsight, I should have seen the warning signs.",
      "It's easy to criticize with the benefit of hindsight.",
      "With hindsight I should've worked harder."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f8b75852-9e2d-4e00-9f93-ef8f259edb8c",
    "front": "**Def**: twist or change facts, etc. so that they are no longer true.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تحریف کردن/دگرگون کردن",
    "back": "distort sth",
    "examples": [
      "He distorted the facts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "32518fef-413d-4031-8fcb-a52df4b7b76b",
    "front": "**Def**: an annoying person or situation. (SYN a pain in the neck).\n**Farsi**: مایه عذاب/مزاحم",
    "back": "a (real) pain (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Yeah, he was a pain, wasn't he?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "211e7bb3-83c9-4d14-9c2f-0bea3bae1437",
    "front": "**Def**: used to express doubts about a surprisingly good situation.\n**Farsi**: باور نکردنی (از خوشحالی زیاد)/خیلی خوب است که واقعی باشد",
    "back": "too good to be true",
    "examples": [
      "Sounds too good to be true, doesn't it?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "317febed-0834-4c09-ab8e-346055578ab1",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that you think sth cannot be true and must be a joke. (SYNS You're joking, You can't be serious).\n**Farsi**: شوخی می‌کنی/جدی نمی‌گویی",
    "back": "You're kidding",
    "examples": [
      "Rani's going out with a film star. You're kidding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "355d1b3b-fc6a-424e-a210-e3a917482cea",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that you can never be certain about future events, so anything is possible.\n**Farsi**: هیچ وقت معلوم نیست",
    "back": "you never know",
    "examples": [
      "I may get the job – you never know."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a767331a-1409-4f91-9ca7-2c02645f14dc",
    "front": "**Def**: Having a high rank.\n**Farsi**: ارشد",
    "back": "senior OPP",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from junior"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd21331f-1290-48e6-abe8-15343c5fb26f",
    "front": "**Def**: given permission to leave (hospital).\n**Farsi**: مرخص شدن",
    "back": "discharged",
    "examples": [
      "He was discharged from the hospital yesterday.",
      "She was discharged from the army after ten years of service.",
      "The patient was discharged after making a full recovery."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "832ae589-33ad-4a62-93fb-21b1933c8442",
    "front": "**Def**: taken there and treated.\n**Farsi**: بستری شدن در بیمارستان",
    "back": "admitted to hospital",
    "examples": [
      "I was admitted to the ward"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d31a5c88-91cd-424d-873c-06dd480ff46f",
    "front": "**Def**: spend time recovering. SYN recuperate.\n**Farsi**: نقاهت کردن، بهبودی یافتن",
    "back": "convalesce V",
    "examples": [
      "Then you may go home to convalesce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7ceb1976-81fd-4b21-8938-8245a18e94ad",
    "front": "**Def**: To recover from illness.\n**Farsi**: بهبودی یافتن",
    "back": "recuperate V SYN",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from convalesce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4ff055b1-f5f3-4091-8be6-ecf97560fbb0",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of recovering.\n**Farsi**: دوران نقاهت",
    "back": "convalescence N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from convalesce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "20bfe6ca-cf40-4583-b71a-6e1d26c9b30f",
    "front": "**Def**: persuade them to do it.\n**Farsi**: کسی را برای انجام کاری متقاعد کردن",
    "back": "talk someone into doing something",
    "examples": [
      "If you talk someone into doing something, you persuade them to do it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "19058da4-4ed1-4fc5-9c5f-4b0224bdffd2",
    "front": "**Def**: a bad memory.\n**Farsi**: حافظه ضعیف/مثل آبکش (ذهن)",
    "back": "mind like a sieve",
    "examples": [
      "Sometimes I've got a mind like a sieve."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d0311de6-f6b6-4dbd-bf3a-1fd4ca23f5bb",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely dry.\n**Farsi**: مثل استخوان خشک",
    "back": "as dry as a bone",
    "examples": [
      "The ground is as dry as a bone."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "841cf609-1526-49b2-b876-5c36033c7ab9",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of recovering.\n**Farsi**: بهبودی، نقاهت",
    "back": "recuperation N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from convalesce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6070c807-dbfd-4253-9939-88d178acfb13",
    "front": "**Def**: related to the inside of something, including the body.\n**Farsi**: داخلی",
    "back": "internal",
    "examples": [
      "The car suffered internal damage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "50e06084-80f2-439a-84a4-d38cc96e4bb2",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth should happen soon or should have happened already. (SYN it's high time).\n**Farsi**: وقتش رسیده است (که...)",
    "back": "it's about time",
    "examples": [
      "It's about time I started a pension."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d843288f-adcc-42e5-bdbc-b0d2dd8ea5fe",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that is not worth what you pay for it. (V: rip sb off).\n**Farsi**: گرانفروشی/کلاهبرداری",
    "back": "rip-off (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "A bit of a rip-off."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9ba2a291-50a7-4afa-8c8f-d9d581ae9b41",
    "front": "**Def**: spend your time imagining things, and not be aware of things around you.\n**Farsi**: در عالم خود بودن/غرق در تخیلات بودن",
    "back": "live/be in a world of your own",
    "examples": [
      "He lives in a world of his own."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "459cbe9e-151e-48d8-a7a6-6e458d92c613",
    "front": "**Def**: used ironically to say you don't believe what sb has told you.\n**Farsi**: داستان احتمالی (کنایه: دروغ محضه)",
    "back": "A likely story",
    "examples": [
      "Sal said she's too busy to help us. A likely story."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ab27e143-a2f2-4d06-818e-bc2ac23604f0",
    "front": "**Def**: Sent to prison until the trial.\n**Farsi**: در بازداشت موقت بودن",
    "back": "remanded in custody",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from remand"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de5963cd-2327-49f5-99be-b2dcad04d25c",
    "front": "**Def**: handing over a criminal to another jurisdiction.\n**Farsi**: استرداد مجرم",
    "back": "extradition",
    "examples": [
      "They requested his extradition from France."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de3f28bf-b183-47f2-847d-b8a5a9674033",
    "front": "**Def**: the thin pointed end of something.\n**Farsi**: نوک، سر",
    "back": "tip (of sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The pencil tip was lodged in her brain."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "145834be-591d-4af2-bf4b-9aff5a257241",
    "front": "**Def**: dissuade them from doing it.\n**Farsi**: کسی را از انجام کاری منصرف کردن",
    "back": "talk someone out of doing something",
    "examples": [
      "If you talk someone out of doing something, you dissuade them from doing it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e5ce5a0b-1b36-489d-a341-efba6eeed4f0",
    "front": "**Def**: disappear suddenly or in a way you cannot explain.\n**Farsi**: غیب شدن، ناپدید شدن",
    "back": "vanish into thin air (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "ran off and vanished into thin air."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "be8cba32-4c52-454c-90ae-93329e362fa4",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them for a very short time and not clearly or completely.\n**Farsi**: لحظه‌ای دیدن، نگاهی اجمالی انداختن",
    "back": "catch a glimpse of sth/sb (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "We caught a glimpse of the actress."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "777b6095-2e0c-428b-a294-38aabe01fbd2",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them suddenly, often when you have been hoping to see them.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان دیدن، چشمش به چیزی افتادن",
    "back": "catch sight of sb/sth (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "She caught sight of her cousin in the crowd."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a06eee0-3fda-4a07-b362-70cef993cd96",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them suddenly, especially when they are hard to see.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان دیدن (در شرایط دشوار)",
    "back": "spot sb/sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "I spotted several mistakes in my work."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b55a58dd-7a90-4262-9c94-548d49e07af1",
    "front": "**Def**: rub or knead the body’s muscles.\n**Farsi**: ماساژ دادن",
    "back": "massage (V/N)",
    "examples": [
      "Massage the scalp vigorously."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f0449857-ad07-46c4-9869-3d130c05c6b4",
    "front": "**Def**: move or make sth move easily over a smooth or wet surface.\n**Farsi**: لغزیدن، سُر خوردن",
    "back": "slide (V)",
    "examples": [
      "sliding steadily up and over the forehead."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5a38e125-7159-475b-873c-f8efbdf21e32",
    "front": "**Def**: press on sth hard with your hand, foot, etc.\n**Farsi**: فشار وارد کردن",
    "back": "apply pressure to sth (PHR)",
    "examples": [
      "Apply gentle pressure to the temples."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "29830eee-561d-478c-b24a-638ff4965c12",
    "front": "**Def**: touch sth lightly several times with your hand flat.\n**Farsi**: ضربه آرام زدن، دستمالی کردن (آرام)",
    "back": "pat sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "gently patting the cheeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1435a2ac-1c56-4260-9dc7-e8068e1d4cd6",
    "front": "**Def**: hold sth tightly between the thumb and finger.\n**Farsi**: نیشگون گرفتن",
    "back": "pinch sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "lightly pinch the skin along the line of the jaw."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "34d85fb8-f595-4e44-89cd-e5322af2045b",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling you have if your muscles are tight and not relaxed (release the tension = allow or cause the muscles to relax).\n**Farsi**: تنش، گرفتگی عضلانی",
    "back": "tension (N)",
    "examples": [
      "To release tension around the eyes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "12de5e5c-b0a1-4c34-a1e2-a03f2221fb63",
    "front": "**Def**: press sth firmly with your fingers.\n**Farsi**: فشار دادن، چلاندن",
    "back": "squeeze sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "firmly squeeze the eyebrows with your fingertips."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ead84e5b-7190-4702-904c-59ca0d55cf35",
    "front": "**Def**: describe soft, relaxed movements.\n**Farsi**: به آرامی، ملایم",
    "back": "gently (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Start by gently stroking the whole face."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "780667da-1efe-4c3c-8716-a5b149b19877",
    "front": "**Def**: with much stronger force.\n**Farsi**: محکم، قاطعانه",
    "back": "firmly (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "firmly squeeze the eyebrows."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "36b16fbc-d429-41ae-a400-5d2047665fa9",
    "front": "**Def**: regular, controlled movements.\n**Farsi**: پیوسته، با ثبات",
    "back": "steadily (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "sliding steadily up and over the forehead."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a000966-2d6c-410d-b880-c4aa7de71806",
    "front": "**Def**: light and pleasant. SYN subtle.\n**Farsi**: طعم/عطر لطیف",
    "back": "delicate flavour/fragrance (N)",
    "examples": [
      "What a delicate flavour/fragrance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d92edd1b-fbf6-4716-9a51-298b0e377c6a",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant smell. fragrant ADJ.\n**Farsi**: عطر، بوی خوش",
    "back": "fragrance (N)",
    "examples": [
      "What a delicate fragrance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ae7570b1-2039-4aab-aa99-be01804635ac",
    "front": "**Def**: just possible to smell, see, or hear.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، کم‌رنگ",
    "back": "faint (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "It has a faint smell of pear."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "43ba693b-608a-44c0-adf3-634de6b080cf",
    "front": "**Def**: making you feel hungry. OPP unappetizing.\n**Farsi**: اشتها‌آور",
    "back": "appetizing (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "lots of appetizing recipes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1e7f5c13-ab79-48be-b922-9b8c5db280c6",
    "front": "**Def**: describe soft, relaxed movements.\n**Farsi**: به آرامی، سبک",
    "back": "lightly (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Use your fingertips to lightly pinch the skin."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8b0ba15-68d0-4cad-9eff-c67c925c59c6",
    "front": "**Def**: not having much taste. SYN bland.\n**Farsi**: بی‌مزه، بی‌طعم",
    "back": "insipid (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "This soup is insipid."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f8061c65-7af9-4b38-bf5c-c44a2a62a79c",
    "front": "**Def**: very strong smelling.\n**Farsi**: تند، زننده (بو)",
    "back": "pungent (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "Garlic has a pungent smell."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0ab009df-e316-4199-baff-1cb902700eb6",
    "front": "**Def**: smelling unpleasant or damp; without freshness. SYN dank.\n**Farsi**: کهنه، نمور، بوی گندیده",
    "back": "musty (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "The house has a musty odour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ff672a5c-7ff9-4526-8b9b-aae2834a9bde",
    "front": "**Def**: a smell, especially an unpleasant one.\n**Farsi**: بو (بوی نامطبوع)",
    "back": "odour (N)",
    "examples": [
      "The house has a musty odour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2d42eff4-33ae-413b-9a23-febaf4b5ec5d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of food and drink) go bad and be unfit to eat or drink.\n**Farsi**: فاسد شدن (غذا)",
    "back": "go off (PHR V)",
    "examples": [
      "I think it's gone off."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "affea6f1-06ac-4256-a589-0d896527036e",
    "front": "**Def**: making you feel you want to vomit.\n**Farsi**: حالت تهوع‌آور",
    "back": "nauseating (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "a nauseating stench in the basement."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c8930e6-afff-4329-96f4-745f4a1a40b7",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong, very unpleasant smell.\n**Farsi**: بوی گند، بوی تعفن",
    "back": "stench (N)",
    "examples": [
      "a nauseating stench in the basement."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d5f7a874-0c4c-43dc-9ecc-d5b084056197",
    "front": "**Def**: a very bad headache.\n**Farsi**: سردرد شدید/وحشتناک",
    "back": "splitting headache",
    "examples": [
      "I've got a splitting headache."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2c80d6c3-2289-4e3b-ba52-95ea6e67361d",
    "front": "**Def**: an allergy affecting the nose, eyes, and throat, caused by pollen from plants.\n**Farsi**: تب یونجه (حساسیت فصلی)",
    "back": "hay fever",
    "examples": [
      "I suffer from hay fever in the summer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "854f9625-4314-44ac-a0f0-849724729f0c",
    "front": "**Def**: small sore areas inside the mouth, usually lasting a few days.\n**Farsi**: آفت دهان",
    "back": "mouth ulcers",
    "examples": [
      "Why does he get mouth ulcers?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c7ca9c62-721d-48a3-97ad-1fabe8071a45",
    "front": "**Def**: put a bone out of its normal position.\n**Farsi**: در رفتن استخوان",
    "back": "dislocate sth",
    "examples": [
      "He dislocated his shoulder."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "caa1556d-630c-4631-87a0-c0a443edc91b",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant (also a nasty accident).\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/بد",
    "back": "nasty",
    "examples": [
      "That's a nasty rash on your arm."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42b31110-2012-4e1e-93c0-68424844fc05",
    "front": "**Def**: a stomach problem causing sickness or diarrhoea.\n**Farsi**: ناراحتی معده",
    "back": "upset stomach",
    "examples": [
      "I had an upset stomach this morning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1e71fd89-28c2-4e1a-a9f3-a59e09c51dca",
    "front": "**Def**: passing waste from the body too often and in liquid form.\n**Farsi**: اسهال",
    "back": "diarrhoea",
    "examples": [
      "(Implied definition)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "72608933-acc1-4f33-8350-02b86629b4ef",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to move waste material from the body. constipation N.\n**Farsi**: دچار یبوست",
    "back": "constipated",
    "examples": [
      "I often get constipated on holiday."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4630ff1e-90e7-40ef-b156-24a211cc3b39",
    "front": "**Def**: the pressure of the blood as it moves round the body. (High and low blood pressure are problem conditions.)\n**Farsi**: فشار خون بالا",
    "back": "high blood pressure",
    "examples": [
      "My mother's got high blood pressure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1da82616-6a2f-4020-a452-217f7ed13f4a",
    "front": "**Def**: injure a part of the body (usually the wrist or ankle) by turning it suddenly.\n**Farsi**: رگ به رگ شدن/پیچ خوردن",
    "back": "sprain sth (SYN twist sth)",
    "examples": [
      "I sprained my ankle running."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "98ae9560-6831-416f-bc96-a7f4090d4880",
    "front": "**Def**: injure a muscle by stretching it too much.\n**Farsi**: کشیدگی عضله",
    "back": "pull a muscle",
    "examples": [
      "He pulled a muscle in training."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c7c03f61-ee34-4920-97e8-4dbb04df2787",
    "front": "**Def**: a sore swelling on the surface of the skin (here on the back of the foot) often caused by rubbing or burning.\n**Farsi**: تاول",
    "back": "blister",
    "examples": [
      "I've got a blister on my heel."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "08c6d5fe-87d1-427e-9007-aed4c4d003fa",
    "front": "**Def**: (If sth is soluble it can be dissolved, e.g. soluble aspirin.)\n**Farsi**: حل شدنی",
    "back": "soluble",
    "examples": [
      "(Definition only)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fce11f19-5fc0-45fb-b3d7-4d5fb72f67d7",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of not having any energy to do things. lethargic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: بی‌حالی/کسالت",
    "back": "lethargy",
    "examples": [
      "This product can cause lethargy or drowsiness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "551eff4f-3fc0-4ef0-8ea8-453a271f96e0",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of feeling tired and almost asleep. drowsy ADJ.\n**Farsi**: خواب‌آلودگی",
    "back": "drowsiness",
    "examples": [
      "This product can cause lethargy or drowsiness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e612bfa6-6535-4b56-8519-32d6a72c4bd4",
    "front": "**Def**: lasting only a short period, e.g. a short-term solution. OPP long-term.\n**Farsi**: کوتاه‌مدت",
    "back": "short-term",
    "examples": [
      "For short-term use only."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7dd25d54-c4c2-4c59-a265-3fc14381001f",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of a medicine that you take at any one time.\n**Farsi**: دوز/مقدار مصرف",
    "back": "dose (or dosage)",
    "examples": [
      "Do not exceed the stated dose."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3255970a-6826-4f3f-8dd9-db3b75139020",
    "front": "**Def**: included inside sth else, usually inside a letter or packet.\n**Farsi**: ضمیمه شده",
    "back": "enclosed",
    "examples": [
      "Please read the enclosed leaflet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6bc23e6c-6560-4e88-800a-9c35ed618ee5",
    "front": "**Def**: one or several pages of information about sth.\n**Farsi**: بروشور/راهنما",
    "back": "leaflet",
    "examples": [
      "Please read the enclosed leaflet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "85e05203-2cb9-4f0b-a2e4-ab0fa65e42e6",
    "front": "**Def**: be greater than a number, amount, or quality.\n**Farsi**: بیش از/فراتر از",
    "back": "in excess of",
    "examples": [
      "The cost won't be in excess of $5,000."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f552f01c-22be-4743-97b9-cc498a449686",
    "front": "**Def**: acting in an open and natural way, without worrying about what you say or do. spontaneity N.\n**Farsi**: خودجوش/بی‌نقشه",
    "back": "spontaneous (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm a spontaneous sort of person."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2b80cdfd-4d82-4595-af13-943f43e1dc19",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of being spontaneous.\n**Farsi**: خودجوشی",
    "back": "spontaneity (N)",
    "examples": [
      "I think spontaneity is a positive attribute."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a2aa55f2-4868-4638-b8a5-859842b5cd50",
    "front": "**Def**: not caring or worrying about the future.\n**Farsi**: بی‌خیال/فارغ از غم",
    "back": "happy-go-lucky",
    "examples": [
      "I'm a happy-go-lucky sort of person."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c869e720-d2fd-499c-9e42-08870c2be154",
    "front": "**Def**: sensible and realistic in things you say or think.\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بین/منطقی",
    "back": "down-to-earth",
    "examples": [
      "I'm pretty down-to-earth too."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5bb540e-0468-403e-9d64-b82b21c20a7e",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who talks a lot. chatty ADJ.\n**Farsi**: وراج/پر حرف",
    "back": "chatterbox (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "My friends say I'm a real chatterbox."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f43f2534-acf8-4c66-b02c-96f19c3cdec7",
    "front": "**Def**: very enthusiastic or interested in sth. passion (for sth) N.\n**Farsi**: پرشور/علاقه‌مند",
    "back": "passionate (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm truly passionate about people."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1a1ca1c2-d5dd-4874-97d3-f991896de2ed",
    "front": "**Def**: be prepared to try sth. SYN have a go, give sth a try.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را امتحان کردن",
    "back": "give sth a go (SYN have a go)",
    "examples": [
      "I'll give anything a go."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "38995b6a-befe-4838-984d-f8630c67afb4",
    "front": "**Def**: according to what is practical, possible, or sensible.\n**Farsi**: در حد معقول/منطقی",
    "back": "within reason",
    "examples": [
      "I'll give anything a go, within reason!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a96a525-b7a3-421a-9e9b-5fb53bd6f91a",
    "front": "**Def**: be attracted to sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جذب چیزی/کسی شدن",
    "back": "be drawn to sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "I'm drawn to men who are considerate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3777ab-6ffa-46d6-b903-709f63f85c18",
    "front": "**Def**: always thinking about other people's wishes and feelings. OPP inconsiderate.\n**Farsi**: با ملاحظه/متفکر",
    "back": "considerate (SYN thoughtful)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm drawn to men who are considerate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c36fde28-9afb-46ff-a08c-09ebaa1721d0",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling of liking or caring about sth/sb. affectionate ADJ.\n**Farsi**: محبت/علاقه",
    "back": "affection",
    "examples": [
      "happy to show affection."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf3e8253-9e8c-4899-a493-bc972f75fb92",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles.\n**Farsi**: درستکاری/صداقت",
    "back": "integrity",
    "examples": [
      "A guy with integrity."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f21b4f3d-c69c-4023-a6f4-db47304f820e",
    "front": "**Def**: trying to appear important, intelligent, etc. to impress others.\n**Farsi**: متظاهر/پر ادعا",
    "back": "pretentious",
    "examples": [
      "NOT pretentious."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3c3059d3-da99-44c0-8f46-0ad8669daedc",
    "front": "**Def**: = What's your impression of sb/sth?\n**Farsi**: نظر شما در مورد کسی/چیزی چیست؟",
    "back": "What do you make of sb/sth?",
    "examples": [
      "What did you make of the two candidates for the job?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbc26ffb-5f94-48a8-9e0d-01ec06320d64",
    "front": "**Def**: An interesting or unusual person can be called a character (or a real character).\n**Farsi**: آدم خاص/فرد جالب",
    "back": "character (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Joe Pascoe was a real character."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e5d74ee1-bfaf-4b80-b856-a4959d30be1c",
    "front": "**Def**: able to think quickly; intelligent.\n**Farsi**: باهوش/حاضر جواب",
    "back": "quick-witted",
    "examples": [
      "Joe Pascoe was quick-witted, and shrewd."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a2fbe57-2de6-41b8-9885-de2d95669974",
    "front": "**Def**: good at judging people and situations.\n**Farsi**: زیرک/تیزبین",
    "back": "shrewd (SYN astute)",
    "examples": [
      "Joe Pascoe was quick-witted, and shrewd."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa7a1a38-7732-4b6c-b655-b07029804019",
    "front": "**Def**: determined to get what you want and not caring about others.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحم/سنگدل",
    "back": "ruthless",
    "examples": [
      "I'd say pretty ruthless too."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c4a08d8-98c6-41f7-b583-2a2feb8218c7",
    "front": "**Def**: start liking sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: از کسی/چیزی خوش آمدن",
    "back": "take to sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "I didn't take to him personally."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a826f919-d2fa-4d39-9b3b-4e0d9ad67591",
    "front": "**Def**: make a particular impression.\n**Farsi**: به نظر رسیدن/برداشت خاصی ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "come across (as)",
    "examples": [
      "He came across as rather pushy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5853eb82-cf2c-44d4-ae80-a688b6745051",
    "front": "**Def**: trying hard to get what you want, especially in a rude manner.\n**Farsi**: سمج/زورگو",
    "back": "pushy (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He came across as rather pushy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b6c8769a-be62-460b-b3aa-fe620d2cdc99",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb a particular impression.\n**Farsi**: به نظر رسیدن (برداشتی ایجاد کردن)",
    "back": "strike sb (as sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Catherine actually struck me as being more suitable."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "30a5c34e-e6dd-4239-9c43-29b22864313d",
    "front": "**Def**: taking care to do things carefully and correctly.\n**Farsi**: وظیفه‌شناس/باوجدان",
    "back": "conscientious",
    "examples": [
      "She certainly seemed very conscientious."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a60be563-cca9-47fc-81cf-ef2021d34853",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be relied on as good, honest, etc.\n**Farsi**: قابل اعتماد",
    "back": "trustworthy",
    "examples": [
      "very conscientious and trustworthy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8858010-f6da-41ad-a776-79709096dc4b",
    "front": "**Def**: the date after which sth should not be used. expire v.\n**Farsi**: تاریخ انقضا",
    "back": "expiry date",
    "examples": [
      "Do not use after expiry date."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a4d8976a-57fb-4880-9cc0-748c37d0af6d",
    "front": "**Def**: when not looked at or thought about carefully.\n**Farsi**: ظاهراً/در ظاهر",
    "back": "on the surface",
    "examples": [
      "someone appears on the surface."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2e0726c8-5dc1-4347-99c9-5af74103dc24",
    "front": "**Def**: not friendly towards others.\n**Farsi**: گوشه‌گیر/فاصله‌گیر",
    "back": "aloof (SYNS distant, stand-offish)",
    "examples": [
      "A person who seems aloof."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5087eba2-b7c3-415b-a7b1-3f64ce8f8323",
    "front": "**Def**: not confident; not wanting to talk about yourself.\n**Farsi**: کمرو/متواضع",
    "back": "diffident (SYN shy)",
    "examples": [
      "may just be shy and diffident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "245bf86c-ed37-40cc-bf0d-0bfb35c77660",
    "front": "**Def**: don't form an opinion of sth/sb by their appearance only.\n**Farsi**: از روی ظاهر قضاوت نکن",
    "back": "don't judge a book by its cover (SAYING)",
    "examples": [
      "As they say: don't judge a book by its cover."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "72f3ba61-f48e-42fd-8968-30372c26c3f9",
    "front": "**Def**: a feature of sb's character.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی/خصوصیت اخلاقی",
    "back": "trait",
    "examples": [
      "Other personality traits can be misleading."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ecdbac10-f7a0-4dea-8a1b-5e1202c656d5",
    "front": "**Def**: giving the wrong idea or impression.\n**Farsi**: گمراه‌کننده",
    "back": "misleading (SYN deceptive)",
    "examples": [
      "Other personality traits can be misleading."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eb6ea575-2f8c-4329-9fae-e5b41fbc088a",
    "front": "**Def**: a good or desirable quality. OPP vice. virtuous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فضیلت/حسنه",
    "back": "virtue",
    "examples": [
      "being cunning, or impulsive... may be a virtue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bd3d4595-b8d6-4583-ae3f-1109d840bc42",
    "front": "**Def**: doing things quickly, without thinking about the results.\n**Farsi**: تکانشی/بدون فکر",
    "back": "impulsive (SYNS impetuous, rash)",
    "examples": [
      "being cunning, or impulsive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "85155b2e-c022-4f9b-82c1-923041a2ffb5",
    "front": "**Def**: lacking experience of life, and trusting others too easily. naivety N.\n**Farsi**: ساده‌لوح/خام",
    "back": "naive",
    "examples": [
      "or naive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a99cdab-d8e4-4b9f-8a9c-30cb7f0ec49f",
    "front": "**Def**: you are not confident that it is true or will happen. scepticism N.\n**Farsi**: شکاک/تردیدآمیز",
    "back": "sceptical",
    "examples": [
      "I'm very sceptical about the results of this survey."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "84c1668d-0057-40fe-8653-3b6abef77a32",
    "front": "**Def**: feeling extremely happy because of a success.\n**Farsi**: شادمان/مسرور",
    "back": "jubilant",
    "examples": [
      "The jubilant fans were cheering."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a79927a9-fcba-455e-99d5-8b47e983cc82",
    "front": "**Def**: crying (close to tears = nearly crying).\n**Farsi**: گریان/اشک‌ریزان",
    "back": "in tears",
    "examples": [
      "She was in tears by the time we got to the hospital."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe5f572b-3a3b-400b-881c-031b9bc35e7e",
    "front": "**Def**: become very angry.\n**Farsi**: از کوره در رفتن/عصبانی شدن",
    "back": "lose your temper (SYN go mad INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He completely lost his temper."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "60260cc2-384a-4d00-94f1-60c38dcf9410",
    "front": "**Def**: become very angry.\n**Farsi**: خیلی عصبانی شدن",
    "back": "hit the roof (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He'll hit the roof when he sees it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f86b66d1-f178-41b3-ae2a-c80570a91d2d",
    "front": "**Def**: very disappointed.\n**Farsi**: خیلی ناامید/داغون",
    "back": "gutted (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I was gutted when we lost the match."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9a30df8a-0a4e-463c-9708-4ca829cd308b",
    "front": "**Def**: being in a state of extreme distress or excitement and crying, laughing, or shouting, etc.\n**Farsi**: هیستریک (از شدت هیجان یا ناراحتی)",
    "back": "hysterical",
    "examples": [
      "Her mother became hysterical."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e18925b3-9803-40ea-918d-17969a19979e",
    "front": "**Def**: shocked and surprised.\n**Farsi**: مبهوت/شوکه",
    "back": "stunned (SYN gobsmacked INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I was stunned when they gave me the prize."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1d681339-a7bb-4a94-b39d-009e5495d921",
    "front": "**Def**: shocked because sth is very unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: وحشت‌زده/متحیر (از بدی چیزی)",
    "back": "appalled (SYN horrified)",
    "examples": [
      "I was appalled by the conditions they had to live in."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "45b13e8b-94b6-4cf2-aa6b-0f21cd72253a",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely anxious.\n**Farsi**: درمانده/مضطرب",
    "back": "desperate",
    "examples": [
      "Karen was desperate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "833bda63-3fcc-4e0e-a547-ed4a1b8e01f1",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely unhappy.\n**Farsi**: به شدت/با درماندگی",
    "back": "desperately (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "He was desperately unhappy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "70a370ee-1c6e-45a5-bee5-91c47294709b",
    "front": "**Def**: stop yourself showing negative emotions or feelings, especially over a long time (bottle up your emotions).\n**Farsi**: احساسات را سرکوب کردن/درون ریختن",
    "back": "bottle sth up",
    "examples": [
      "Are you the kind of person who bottles up their emotions?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "83203042-7c1f-46f5-969c-16c2b497427b",
    "front": "**Def**: make your feelings obvious to others.\n**Farsi**: احساسات خود را آشکار کردن",
    "back": "wear your heart on your sleeve",
    "examples": [
      "Do you wear your heart on your sleeve?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "add56078-e782-4d54-9897-15229404d7a7",
    "front": "**Def**: annoy sb very much.\n**Farsi**: روی اعصاب کسی رفتن/عصبانی کردن",
    "back": "get up sb's nose (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He's not the kind of person who'd get up people's noses."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4205bfbf-c85e-4f10-9cdc-d0d05f3c38e1",
    "front": "**Def**: slightly nervous, embarrassed, or worried.\n**Farsi**: ناراحت/معذب",
    "back": "uneasy (SYN uncomfortable)",
    "examples": [
      "I feel a bit uneasy when people pour out their thoughts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e2c534f-7be7-4d68-a43f-4b8a2d1a73a4",
    "front": "**Def**: express all your feelings, often because you are unhappy.\n**Farsi**: بیرون ریختن (احساسات)",
    "back": "pour sth out",
    "examples": [
      "people pour out their innermost thoughts to me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f71e1b33-22e3-4753-9359-d93fb3d1ab1c",
    "front": "**Def**: the thoughts which are most personal and private.\n**Farsi**: درونی‌ترین افکار",
    "back": "innermost thoughts",
    "examples": [
      "people pour out their innermost thoughts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0cf63106-1be1-4d30-a516-f4e4c60d7f89",
    "front": "**Def**: careful not to give too much information.\n**Farsi**: محتاط/تودار",
    "back": "guarded (SYN cautious)",
    "examples": [
      "My own instinct is to be quite guarded."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8daaee34-9bcd-41c0-b5f5-135c4041d1cd",
    "front": "**Def**: tell people secret information.\n**Farsi**: لو دادن/افشا کردن",
    "back": "give sth away",
    "examples": [
      "not give away too much about how I feel."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e11c1c09-fe92-408e-8f1a-c0874eff298b",
    "front": "**Def**: (of emotions, energy, etc.) held back; not shown or expressed.\n**Farsi**: تلنبار شده/فروخورده",
    "back": "pent-up",
    "examples": [
      "release your pent-up emotions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "381619cf-4393-4a39-89e5-43c1e8f91dd1",
    "front": "**Def**: I wasn't interested in or enthusiastic about it.\n**Farsi**: واقعاً به آن علاقه‌مند نبودم",
    "back": "my heart wasn't really in it",
    "examples": [
      "my heart wasn't really in it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d0856b0e-7815-4a35-b3f7-e1a4a8a39a27",
    "front": "**Def**: I was unable to tell her she'd failed, because I knew she'd be upset.\n**Farsi**: دلش نیامد/طاقت نداشت",
    "back": "didn't have the heart to",
    "examples": [
      "I didn't have the heart to tell her she'd failed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "67fcc272-7a92-4cd1-8a05-1d4bbd846710",
    "front": "**Def**: Emotionally, I felt I should help him.\n**Farsi**: حس قلبی‌ام گفت",
    "back": "my heart told me",
    "examples": [
      "My heart told me to help him."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7313fff3-1514-4bbc-b2e5-796b82341670",
    "front": "**Def**: dislike sb as soon as you meet them.\n**Farsi**: فوراً از کسی بدش آمدن",
    "back": "take an instant dislike to sb",
    "examples": [
      "they took an instant dislike to me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5f9a39b9-4c04-4881-a4ab-841e5f468c0d",
    "front": "**Def**: unfriendly and aggressive. hostility N.\n**Farsi**: خصمانه/دشمنانه",
    "back": "hostile (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "they were openly hostile."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7d336c39-ce87-4ed6-af8f-452cc9a29d8d",
    "front": "**Def**: If you say sth to sb's face, you say it to them directly.\n**Farsi**: مستقیم به کسی",
    "back": "to sb's face",
    "examples": [
      "nice enough to my face."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a7156774-446d-49de-91ae-1f5dbe4ef6c3",
    "front": "**Def**: saying nice things about sb.\n**Farsi**: تعریف‌آمیز/تمجیدآمیز",
    "back": "complimentary (about sb)",
    "examples": [
      "not so complimentary behind my back."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "09e5b7b6-34ad-4ac8-b04e-1f3326a0cd29",
    "front": "**Def**: If you say or do sth behind sb's back, you say or do it without their knowledge, and usually it is bad or unkind.\n**Farsi**: پشت سر کسی",
    "back": "behind sb's back",
    "examples": [
      "behind my back."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e19cc3f1-4515-4aed-8fcb-12563c0fc399",
    "front": "**Def**: create pressure and anxiety for sb; create tension in a relationship.\n**Farsi**: فشار آوردن/تنش ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "put a strain on sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "it put a strain on my relationship."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "049ac2ae-fcc7-4032-b5cd-a2a07ff01a11",
    "front": "**Def**: support and defend sb if they are criticized.\n**Farsi**: حمایت کردن از کسی",
    "back": "stick up for sb",
    "examples": [
      "he stuck up for me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "46cf99f3-12e9-4bb8-ac17-cc0dbdca2205",
    "front": "**Def**: over a period of time.\n**Farsi**: با گذشت زمان",
    "back": "as time went by",
    "examples": [
      "as time went by, things settled down."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e977fdc-985f-4854-ae15-ab73d73d334c",
    "front": "**Def**: become calmer and more relaxed.\n**Farsi**: آرام شدن/به روال افتادن",
    "back": "settle down",
    "examples": [
      "things settled down a bit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f321da47-ed66-4243-a882-53bca574f555",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. difficult: It's a tough decision. 2. strict: tough new driving laws. 3. able to deal with difficult situations: She's tough.\n**Farsi**: سخت/دشوار/قوی",
    "back": "tough",
    "examples": [
      "It was a tough time."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ee303df8-d740-4b7e-9b27-ba7a11767e30",
    "front": "**Def**: used to talk about a situation or life in general.\n**Farsi**: اوضاع/شرایط",
    "back": "things (PL)",
    "examples": [
      "Now, two years on, things are looking up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "91aaf09d-0a18-4903-8c5b-0c8fd846d636",
    "front": "**Def**: start to become better.\n**Farsi**: بهتر شدن (وضعیت)",
    "back": "look up (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "things are looking up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c4d9aaa9-08ea-4bcd-a329-47195b4ff69a",
    "front": "**Def**: in the beginning. initial ADJ.\n**Farsi**: در ابتدا",
    "back": "initially (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Initially the kids were reluctant to accept me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4525a03b-3dff-46e6-ae81-4cd94a7c2b26",
    "front": "**Def**: not wanting to do sth. reluctance N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌میل/ناراضی",
    "back": "reluctant (SYN unwilling)",
    "examples": [
      "the kids were reluctant to accept me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7440c8e4-f6fd-44d5-b362-08b6cadafe22",
    "front": "**Def**: a connection between people based on shared feelings or experiences.\n**Farsi**: پیوند/ارتباط عاطفی",
    "back": "bond",
    "examples": [
      "helped to create a closer bond."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9215a21c-f3a3-4e0c-a995-6a3e7db75040",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of admiration for sb because of their qualities. respect v.\n**Farsi**: احترام",
    "back": "respect (for sb)",
    "examples": [
      "I've gained their respect."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ab37c30a-7cc8-4f28-bee4-a2cc26e11b4a",
    "front": "**Def**: weak and easily hurt, physically or emotionally.\n**Farsi**: آسیب‌پذیر",
    "back": "vulnerable",
    "examples": [
      "make yourself rather vulnerable."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c3503bfd-3557-43ca-a69c-13f344684c9d",
    "front": "**Def**: give up sth important or valuable in order to do sth that seems more important. sacrifice sth v.\n**Farsi**: فداکاری کردن",
    "back": "make a sacrifice",
    "examples": [
      "he appreciates the sacrifices I've made."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "126e1446-012b-4e19-84ff-624f7720beaf",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. allow sb to be part of a group; 2. agree to sth; 3. believe that sth is true; 4. admit you did sth wrong.\n**Farsi**: پذیرفتن/قبول کردن",
    "back": "accept (v)",
    "examples": [
      "They accepted me as one of the family."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8c0ccd8d-0186-43c6-8a00-ccd2ac7abfd3",
    "front": "**Def**: a woman you admire for her ability or personal qualities (hero for a man).\n**Farsi**: قهرمان زن",
    "back": "heroine (N) (SYN idol)",
    "examples": [
      "My heroine was Mother Theresa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f8b3ab48-10f1-45f6-bfcd-728e6aa7ab02",
    "front": "**Def**: the ability to do sth, even though it is dangerous, frightening, or very difficult. courageous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: شجاعت/شهامت",
    "back": "courage (N)",
    "examples": [
      "I admired her courage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "273cef5f-6922-4056-b7e6-0b9862f2bf0c",
    "front": "**Def**: a calm, controlled manner in a difficult situation. dignified ADJ.\n**Farsi**: وقار/عزت نفس",
    "back": "dignity (N)",
    "examples": [
      "I admired her dignity."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5e080d1b-a097-4321-b516-6e939d2d1e9d",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of not believing you are better or more important than others. humble ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فروتنی/تواضع",
    "back": "humility (N)",
    "examples": [
      "I admired her humility."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "205585a6-0f38-4b13-8c96-05284569f995",
    "front": "**Def**: admire or love sb very much.\n**Farsi**: پرستیدن/شدیداً تحسین کردن",
    "back": "idolize sb (SYN worship sb)",
    "examples": [
      "I used to idolize David Beckham."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "19f74de2-6d34-4ad9-97e4-898bc500ab21",
    "front": "**Def**: say unkind things or complain about sb.\n**Farsi**: انتقاد کردن/سرزنش کردن",
    "back": "have a go at sb (INF) (SYN criticize sb)",
    "examples": [
      "when the press had a go at him."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e6a69515-c818-4f29-8a9c-36d475966140",
    "front": "**Def**: admire and respect sb, often sb who is older or in a higher position.\n**Farsi**: احترام گذاشتن/تحسین کردن",
    "back": "look up to sb",
    "examples": [
      "I really looked up to my grandfather."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fdf9f4d9-9475-48f3-a27a-e946cf52596d",
    "front": "**Def**: do the same work or be as successful as sb before you.\n**Farsi**: راه کسی را ادامه دادن/دنبال کردن",
    "back": "follow in sb's footsteps",
    "examples": [
      "I hope to follow in his footsteps."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "26eb67df-e2b4-42c6-b939-d26344003619",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who opposes people in authority. rebel v. rebellious ADJ.\n**Farsi**: شورشی/یاغی",
    "back": "rebel (N)",
    "examples": [
      "Pop stars who start off as rebels."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "35b2907f-727f-4cbb-b24b-d9ab36d3f5c2",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who believes the world can be perfect. idealistic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: آرمان‌گرا",
    "back": "idealist (N)",
    "examples": [
      "Pop stars who start off as idealists."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "296c53ee-81a4-4700-8f54-c5775aea2e91",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who says they have strong principles but does not act according to these principles. hypocrisy N. hypocritical ADJ.\n**Farsi**: ریاکار/متظاهر",
    "back": "hypocrite (N)",
    "examples": [
      "What hypocrites!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "96343152-7024-4040-8c55-366b6ab4819e",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who thinks they are better than people in lower social classes.\n**Farsi**: خودبرتربین/متکبر طبقاتی",
    "back": "snob (N)",
    "examples": [
      "Snobs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe6380c9-ee74-4834-a9eb-d8ff875c7128",
    "front": "**Def**: think that you are better than sb.\n**Farsi**: با تحقیر نگاه کردن/خود را برتر دانستن",
    "back": "look down on sb",
    "examples": [
      "people who look down on others."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f50224ae-e07f-400a-bec5-1740479d40cc",
    "front": "**Def**: not polite, elegant, or having good taste.\n**Farsi**: مبتذل/بی‌ادب/زننده",
    "back": "vulgar (SYNS coarse, crude)",
    "examples": [
      "think they're vulgar."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "86436ad3-5e94-4563-9fbc-1496c5cd477e",
    "front": "**Def**: be hurt or frightened by sb who is bigger and stronger (the person who does the bullying is a bully).\n**Farsi**: مورد قلدری قرار گرفتن",
    "back": "be bullied",
    "examples": [
      "I was bullied at school."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5a27d0a8-8c90-4bf5-b51c-ca761691aa33",
    "front": "**Def**: hate and have no respect for sb/sth. despicable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: تحقیر کردن/نفرت داشتن",
    "back": "despise sb/sth (v)",
    "examples": [
      "I've always despised bullies."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b604aa63-8055-4c35-9dec-3c3805ca5631",
    "front": "**Def**: deserving hatred and contempt.\n**Farsi**: نفرت‌انگیز/پست",
    "back": "despicable (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "just despicable in my opinion."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "01cd3190-8b70-423a-a3de-fc49f6d767a3",
    "front": "**Def**: showing hatred and the desire to hurt people's feelings. malice N.\n**Farsi**: بدخواه/مغرض",
    "back": "malicious (ADJ) (SYNS spiteful)",
    "examples": [
      "malicious gossip."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c28f20ba-2018-404a-a84d-02131f0c514f",
    "front": "**Def**: stories about other people's private lives, which may be unkind or untrue. gossip v (also spread gossip).\n**Farsi**: شایعه/سخن‌چینی",
    "back": "gossip (N/V)",
    "examples": [
      "People who spread malicious gossip."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "35a6c10b-9e98-4c40-b148-29effd537129",
    "front": "**Def**: strong beliefs that influence how you behave.\n**Farsi**: اصول/مبانی",
    "back": "principles (PL)",
    "examples": [
      "with strong moral principles."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5321253f-6450-4a51-a8e8-8505ffd029bd",
    "front": "**Def**: beliefs about what is right and important in life.\n**Farsi**: ارزش‌ها",
    "back": "values (PL)",
    "examples": [
      "their values change completely."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f434d2d0-3b93-40c4-aa16-c0ffe683ff94",
    "front": "**Def**: the basic character of a person.\n**Farsi**: طبیعت/ذات",
    "back": "nature (N)",
    "examples": [
      "Is it nature or nurture?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "98b82d72-8151-48ef-badb-a9c729a7a0cb",
    "front": "**Def**: the care and attention given to help sb develop. nurture sb v.\n**Farsi**: تربیت/پرورش",
    "back": "nurture (N)",
    "examples": [
      "Is it nature or nurture?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c2f21941-90a5-418d-933d-a5f456f6cd33",
    "front": "**Def**: the influence on your behaviour of people around you of the same age.\n**Farsi**: فشار همسالان",
    "back": "peer pressure",
    "examples": [
      "Peer pressure is a significant factor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "10082005-3eb5-4d6e-87f7-9b9cc378f9a4",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that encourages you to work harder, do sth, etc.\n**Farsi**: انگیزه/محرک",
    "back": "incentive (to do sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Positive incentives are effective."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4e3c2ab4-e2d8-485a-9aab-3cb86cff09ee",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that makes you less likely to do sth. deter sb v.\n**Farsi**: عامل بازدارنده",
    "back": "deterrent",
    "examples": [
      "deterrents aren't effective."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "73b87324-28b8-4946-b150-24d4d3f75117",
    "front": "**Def**: without sufficient food, education, or money. deprivation N.\n**Farsi**: محروم",
    "back": "deprived",
    "examples": [
      "deprived childhood."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d6e232f1-8c23-4991-a819-249bcabc911f",
    "front": "**Def**: a very negative effect.\n**Farsi**: اثر مخرب/زیان‌آور",
    "back": "detrimental effect (on sth) (OPP beneficial effect)",
    "examples": [
      "A broken home needn't have a detrimental effect."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "396f15c0-f7da-45c7-b71e-e29fe537b2f2",
    "front": "**Def**: dirty or untidy. mess N.\n**Farsi**: شلخته/نامرتب",
    "back": "messy (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "Getting messy teens."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cb971a02-7e44-403a-8875-e5e16b842019",
    "front": "**Def**: keep talking (about sth or to sb) in a boring way.\n**Farsi**: ادامه دادن (به صحبت خسته‌کننده)",
    "back": "go on and on (about sth, at sb)",
    "examples": [
      "You can go on and on about the state of your bedroom."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "36af45fd-9d67-4541-9472-1b6920af8edb",
    "front": "**Def**: keep complaining about sb's behaviour.\n**Farsi**: نق زدن/ایراد گرفتن مداوم",
    "back": "nag (v)",
    "examples": [
      "(Implied context)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "56385c56-e958-44ab-99ab-31efd832d8bf",
    "front": "**Def**: not pleasant or attractive.\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/غیرجذاب",
    "back": "unappealing (OPP appealing)",
    "examples": [
      "Their room may be untidy and unappealing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bd1b8335-d3f9-43f9-a085-4d8b0dc8dd9d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to cause death (here it is being used humorously).\n**Farsi**: تهدیدکننده حیات",
    "back": "life-threatening",
    "examples": [
      "it's not life-threatening."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0aa2293b-1959-4c65-b002-3c2cf85a694a",
    "front": "**Def**: If you make a fuss about sth, you become angry and complain about sth which probably isn't important.\n**Farsi**: جنجال/هیاهو",
    "back": "fuss (N) (SYN kick up a fuss INF)",
    "examples": [
      "why make a fuss?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8b162e9f-5b6a-4565-b120-2245dfbf419f",
    "front": "**Def**: say officially what the rules are.\n**Farsi**: قانون وضع کردن",
    "back": "lay down rules",
    "examples": [
      "lay down rules for the rest of the home."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "13186e53-45d1-46e4-8764-387d0dda52f2",
    "front": "**Def**: behave in a way that others may copy.\n**Farsi**: الگو شدن/مثال زدن",
    "back": "set an (or a good/bad) example",
    "examples": [
      "Set an example by being tidy yourself."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1f6db233-d239-4d81-be2b-5b46141fcfac",
    "front": "**Def**: agree to do sth that you don't want to do.\n**Farsi**: تسلیم شدن/رضایت دادن",
    "back": "give in (to sb/sth) (SYN capitulate FML)",
    "examples": [
      "don't give in and clear up their mess."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c2dede2-e524-4c4b-96e9-396a57ca6f94",
    "front": "**Def**: To expect sth can mean to think it is right that sth should happen.\n**Farsi**: انتظار داشتن",
    "back": "expect (v)",
    "examples": [
      "Most parents expect high standards."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d29a4c9d-4e7b-4634-89bc-7c64cca4e7a5",
    "front": "**Def**: idiom used for saying you are not surprised by something, even though it is unpleasant or disappointing.\n**Farsi**: چه انتظاری داری؟",
    "back": "What do/can you expect?",
    "examples": [
      "Teenagers are often lazy... but what do you expect?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "56dd721d-add3-4210-9241-f848c7abf740",
    "front": "**Def**: the formal rules of correct or polite behaviour in society.\n**Farsi**: آداب/نزاکت",
    "back": "etiquette",
    "examples": [
      "Dining etiquette."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ea8b84a0-8d27-4f4e-a997-02728d74d86e",
    "front": "**Def**: behaviour that is considered polite in a particular society or culture.\n**Farsi**: آداب معاشرت/رفتار",
    "back": "manners (PL)",
    "examples": [
      "good manners to eat all the food on your plate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "69082884-c130-43a0-8014-01a30d7977d1",
    "front": "**Def**: (often passive) disapprove of sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: ناپسند شمردن/ایراد گرفتن",
    "back": "frown on/upon sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "wasting food is frowned upon."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "59d0572e-ff63-40d1-aa03-170cd7fda212",
    "front": "**Def**: having bad manners and not showing respect. courtesy N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌ادب/بی‌نزاکت",
    "back": "discourteous (FML) (OPP courteous)",
    "examples": [
      "talking with your mouth full is viewed as being discourteous."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf50e8a1-8da0-4a58-b1d2-c5dcc2637bb6",
    "front": "**Def**: usually done in a particular place or situation. custom N.\n**Farsi**: مرسوم/متعارف",
    "back": "customary (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "it's customary and respectful to pass food to the elderly first."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "910baffb-86ba-4a06-90a2-4a65d9333fca",
    "front": "**Def**: showing polite behaviour towards sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: محترمانه/مؤدب",
    "back": "respectful (OPP disrespectful)",
    "examples": [
      "it's customary and respectful to pass food to the elderly first."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "729aeb33-1b87-43a5-9286-fa8b921d7c1f",
    "front": "**Def**: moving or pointing towards a higher position.\n**Farsi**: به سمت بالا",
    "back": "upwards (OPP downwards)",
    "examples": [
      "leave them pointing upwards."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e664bc38-ad77-4cba-b66c-6ffe50b5d27d",
    "front": "**Def**: rude in a way that makes sb upset or annoyed.\n**Farsi**: توهین‌آمیز/زننده",
    "back": "offensive (OPP inoffensive)",
    "examples": [
      "It can also be offensive to remove rice with a spoon."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8c60c88c-08f4-4cb7-a981-9a7023516af0",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: تلقی کردن/در نظر گرفتن",
    "back": "consider (v, FML)",
    "examples": [
      "It is considered (to be) the correct thing to do."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7292c646-5c6e-45dd-b377-d27d7880c1e0",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: محسوب شدن",
    "back": "regard (v, FML)",
    "examples": [
      "this is regarded as extremely disrespectful."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e65ab98-ede6-418b-912c-1c9b48d3d692",
    "front": "**Def**: perfect (impeccable manners/behaviour/service).\n**Farsi**: بی‌عیب و نقص/عالی",
    "back": "impeccable",
    "examples": [
      "Felicity's manners are impeccable."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "251c5d46-9a28-47ae-b363-4b3556cd79b0",
    "front": "**Def**: excellent, and done in a way that others should copy.\n**Farsi**: نمونه/الگو",
    "back": "exemplary (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "exemplary manners."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7d49ae3f-5ffc-4bba-be6a-002a62cba0e7",
    "front": "**Def**: rude, often in an amusing way (often used by adults about children). cheek N.\n**Farsi**: گستاخ/پررو (بچه‌گانه)",
    "back": "cheeky (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "that brother of hers is a bit cheeky."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d730424a-8c6a-4c4d-b1b6-0c232cde0cd2",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely rude and disrespectful. insolence N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌شرم/اهانت‌آمیز",
    "back": "insolent",
    "examples": [
      "I'd call him insolent, actually."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "95287bd5-7a82-4b04-b932-d59d88014096",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize sth negative (downright rude/offensive).\n**Farsi**: کاملاً/به وضوح (برای تاکید منفی)",
    "back": "downright",
    "examples": [
      "or even downright rude."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f52419b5-0ba7-4d5a-bb2f-6e93c81d2f77",
    "front": "**Def**: be upset or offended.\n**Farsi**: ناراحت/رنجیده شدن",
    "back": "be put out (SYN take offence)",
    "examples": [
      "I don't think Julian will be put out."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "30d22479-c1e5-42e1-8504-daeda0d59d08",
    "front": "**Def**: say sth that offends or upsets sb.\n**Farsi**: سوتی دادن/حرف نامناسب زدن",
    "back": "put your foot in it (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I just don't want to put my foot in it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "217a5ee1-54d7-4085-95af-a9101533c49e",
    "front": "**Def**: considered to have the highest social status.\n**Farsi**: طبقه بالا",
    "back": "upper class",
    "examples": [
      "His family are very upper class."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d2fea909-98e8-4b7e-99e9-6c38d7d57604",
    "front": "**Def**: behave in the most polite way you can.\n**Farsi**: مؤدبانه رفتار کردن",
    "back": "be on your best behaviour",
    "examples": [
      "you'll just have to be on your best behaviour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2754e7cf-c3cf-42ae-ac57-9ffea923c35e",
    "front": "**Def**: object strongly to sth and be angry about it.\n**Farsi**: شدیداً اعتراض کردن/به دل گرفتن",
    "back": "take exception to sth",
    "examples": [
      "I really took exception to Arnold's remarks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f5afd3ac-64f6-42af-9ab0-ac26cb770d92",
    "front": "**Def**: a few words that give your opinion about sth.\n**Farsi**: نظر/سخن",
    "back": "remark (SYN comment)",
    "examples": [
      "Arnold's remarks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2c0a2ec0-9a2e-4663-958a-21b1ea033421",
    "front": "**Def**: very bad or unacceptable. disgrace N.\n**Farsi**: شرم‌آور/ننگین",
    "back": "disgraceful",
    "examples": [
      "I thought they were disgraceful."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "11a5f458-1556-4996-9988-b72f96beede1",
    "front": "**Def**: be offensive and not at all appropriate.\n**Farsi**: نامناسب/توهین‌آمیز",
    "back": "be in poor/bad taste",
    "examples": [
      "They really were in poor taste."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e25264d1-3d20-4174-9394-af5ec3f2d0fa",
    "front": "**Def**: create untidiness or a disordered situation.\n**Farsi**: خرابکاری کردن، ریخت و پاش کردن",
    "back": "make a mess",
    "examples": [
      "The children often make a mess."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf632d15-b532-43ca-9689-89811db214b6",
    "front": "**Def**: show excessive concern, excitement, or agitation about something.\n**Farsi**: سروصدا راه انداختن، هیاهو کردن",
    "back": "make a fuss",
    "examples": [
      "The children often make a fuss."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "33f1383b-7ad7-4bbf-ab45-bae7a2c45db9",
    "front": "**Def**: harmful; damaging.\n**Farsi**: مضر، زیان‌آور",
    "back": "detrimental",
    "examples": [
      "Does money have a detrimental effect on people?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ad97a362-720e-4d22-a19e-8fb005b6e200",
    "front": "**Def**: resulting in good; favourable or advantageous.\n**Farsi**: مفید، سودمند",
    "back": "beneficial",
    "examples": [
      "Does money have a beneficial effect on people?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c7e595cc-7de8-42ae-bfc7-5fa84888a450",
    "front": "**Def**: behaves in a way that others should copy.\n**Farsi**: الگوی خوبی است",
    "back": "sets a good example",
    "examples": [
      "She sets a good example."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "10427756-fa2e-4aab-a978-f7394f679ffa",
    "front": "**Def**: not attractive or interesting.\n**Farsi**: نامطلوب، ناخوشایند",
    "back": "unappealing",
    "examples": [
      "Nagging is an unappealing habit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e86b863d-5547-4da8-acaa-8fdab37fb71e",
    "front": "**Def**: yields or surrenders to (often after resisting).\n**Farsi**: تسلیم شدن، کوتاه آمدن (در برابر کسی/چیزی)",
    "back": "gives in to",
    "examples": [
      "He goes on and on at the children until he gives in to them."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf7c1262-9a8c-4f6f-adfb-fb8318d3eb96",
    "front": "**Def**: repeatedly asks or urges someone to do something.\n**Farsi**: نق زدن، سرزنش کردن مداوم",
    "back": "nags",
    "examples": [
      "He nags the children about doing their homework."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c793a916-e6e7-4444-b357-244364c9523d",
    "front": "**Def**: behaviour that causes problems or annoyance to other people.\n**Farsi**: رفتار ضد اجتماعی",
    "back": "anti-social behaviour",
    "examples": [
      "The council decided to address anti-social behaviour in the park."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "92b2600d-ef38-471d-a9e2-57d2a19f3659",
    "front": "**Def**: the action of staying away from school without permission.\n**Farsi**: غیبت غیرموجه (از مدرسه)",
    "back": "truancy",
    "examples": [
      "Truancy is a serious problem in some urban schools."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "697c87c2-1e07-4e66-8be4-7616fd81b560",
    "front": "**Def**: doing something dangerous and not worrying about the risks.\n**Farsi**: بی‌پروا، بی‌ملاحظه (رفتار)",
    "back": "reckless (behaviour)",
    "examples": [
      "His reckless behaviour almost caused an accident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2057e152-79ff-4cb2-bd3d-c03cb19a5aac",
    "front": "**Def**: tell someone officially that you disapprove of them.\n**Farsi**: توبیخ کردن، سرزنش کردن",
    "back": "reprimand sb",
    "examples": [
      "The teacher had to reprimand the noisy students."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "666116fd-f224-4b97-95ec-b795232b8f2e",
    "front": "**Def**: the person who leads others in mischievous or criminal activities.\n**Farsi**: سردسته، بانی",
    "back": "ringleader",
    "examples": [
      "The ringleader was punished more severely than the others."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e05c72c4-4b43-4105-b1a2-6871f7c381e7",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: دریافتن/ادراک کردن",
    "back": "perceive (v, FML)",
    "examples": [
      "It is perceived as the correct thing to do."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a8440b60-3ab9-4e5c-a328-b4efde1a2d9c",
    "front": "**Def**: objected strongly to (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: اعتراض کردن، ناخوشایند شمردن",
    "back": "took exception to (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "I took exception to his comments."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e41312ab-1eaa-4394-9d09-911d8ea500aa",
    "front": "**Def**: is disapproved of (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: مورد نقد و انتقاد قرار گرفتن، با اخم تلقی شدن",
    "back": "is frowned upon (phrasal verb)",
    "examples": [
      "Taking photos is frowned upon."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7a4c5436-84dc-425d-9c4e-c2551a9909d5",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say someone has been rude or disrespectful (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: چه رویی!، چه پررویی!",
    "back": "What a cheek! (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "What a cheek!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "46132382-5201-477d-a7e3-bdf59b96cebf",
    "front": "**Def**: said something embarrassing or inappropriate (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: گاف دادن، خراب کردن (با حرف نابجا)",
    "back": "put her foot in it (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "She put her foot in it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a0dc4f1-19f7-4d78-afe1-c7d21f945c7c",
    "front": "**Def**: polite and respectful (Positive remark, P).\n**Farsi**: با ادب، مؤدبانه",
    "back": "courteous",
    "examples": [
      "They're always courteous."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "448dbb04-978f-4ba8-930f-db827bccb9c7",
    "front": "**Def**: the physical area immediately surrounding someone (often related to invasion).\n**Farsi**: حریم خصوصی فیزیکی",
    "back": "personal space",
    "examples": [
      "He invaded my personal space by standing too close."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2c01ebcd-1ef7-491f-a2df-f0175e65de2c",
    "front": "**Def**: rude or impolite conduct.\n**Farsi**: رفتار ناشایست، بی‌ادبی",
    "back": "uncivil behaviour",
    "examples": [
      "The passengers complained about his uncivil behaviour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1dce323b-b598-42c4-80d8-ac29198ca6df",
    "front": "**Def**: rude, unfriendly, and uncooperative.\n**Farsi**: بدخلق، خشن، غیردوستانه",
    "back": "churlish",
    "examples": [
      "It would be churlish to refuse their invitation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "80c1a670-1a9c-484b-a48d-e3375b0fb25d",
    "front": "**Def**: behave in a reasonable and acceptable way.\n**Farsi**: شرم و حیا/نزاکت داشتن برای انجام کاری",
    "back": "have the decency to do sth (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "He didn't even have the decency to apologize."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd0e7ba0-0358-4e35-a098-88f0d3eacb1a",
    "front": "**Def**: an action or remark that is careless or inappropriate.\n**Farsi**: بی‌احتیاطی، عمل نسنجیده",
    "back": "indiscretion",
    "examples": [
      "She regretted the indiscretion of telling him her secret."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6f9c5b31-c79d-4377-8057-45cf86021d29",
    "front": "**Def**: a round fruit with thick skin and many seeds.\n**Farsi**: انار",
    "back": "pomegranate",
    "examples": [
      "I bought a pomegranate from the market."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "23832480-888d-4dcf-9b45-6b0f17a8d2d8",
    "front": "**Def**: a small round fruit with a purple or yellow skin, tropical.\n**Farsi**: پشن فروت",
    "back": "passion fruit",
    "examples": [
      "Passion fruit is great in cocktails."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f860edae-2507-408e-a60b-15c883226972",
    "front": "**Def**: a large oval tropical fruit.\n**Farsi**: پاپایا (خربزه درختی)",
    "back": "papaya",
    "examples": [
      "Papaya and pineapple are tropical fruits."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e136874-d6ab-4844-933a-422287273f7c",
    "front": "**Def**: small, red, round vegetables, eaten raw in salads.\n**Farsi**: تربچه",
    "back": "radishes",
    "examples": [
      "We grow radishes in our garden."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d529c887-a802-423e-9729-7206e709f9f5",
    "front": "**Def**: a round root vegetable with deep red skin and flesh.\n**Farsi**: چغندر قرمز",
    "back": "beetroot",
    "examples": [
      "I like boiled beetroot in salads."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ff472e4c-bd0a-4c2c-bf35-5e59ce0f9ac3",
    "front": "**Def**: young, newly-grown beans, often used in Asian cooking.\n**Farsi**: جوانه ماش/لوبیا",
    "back": "bean sprouts",
    "examples": [
      "Bean sprouts add crunch to stir-fries."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "09cb957b-dcc9-4fb6-b14d-a5c7c3a473a3",
    "front": "**Def**: a type of vegetable with hard skin (like pumpkin or courgette).\n**Farsi**: کدو حلوایی، کدو مسمایی",
    "back": "squash",
    "examples": [
      "We baked the winter squash for dinner."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ceeddf7f-dde1-4619-91cc-3eb091547ddf",
    "front": "**Def**: a plant with a crisp bulb and feathery leaves, eaten as a vegetable.\n**Farsi**: رازیانه، بادیان",
    "back": "fennel",
    "examples": [
      "Artichoke and fennel are vegetables."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c3431ae7-4889-47f5-8c6c-806697d34c98",
    "front": "**Def**: a round vegetable with thick, edible leaves.\n**Farsi**: کنگر فرنگی",
    "back": "artichoke",
    "examples": [
      "I steamed the artichokes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7f869c13-7ab5-44a0-a8f5-b6a220c74d48",
    "front": "**Def**: an oval edible nut.\n**Farsi**: بادام",
    "back": "almonds",
    "examples": [
      "Almonds and cashews are types of nut."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b40dc98b-2b69-43c2-b4ff-ea0d51e30cdf",
    "front": "**Def**: kidney-shaped edible nuts.\n**Farsi**: بادام هندی",
    "back": "cashews",
    "examples": [
      "Cashews are often used in Indian cuisine."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "05963d1c-f41a-4de1-8490-70f1cc3e1474",
    "front": "**Def**: small dried seeds (a type of pulse) used in stews and soups.\n**Farsi**: عدس",
    "back": "lentils",
    "examples": [
      "Lentils are a great source of protein."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aeb1a407-ec32-4bb8-a68b-57b79fd3e6ad",
    "front": "**Def**: a spicy root used in cooking and baking.\n**Farsi**: زنجبیل",
    "back": "ginger",
    "examples": [
      "Ginger and cinnamon are spices."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e0ac8d2e-fda8-4797-bf30-a317ef5c0b5f",
    "front": "**Def**: a sweet-smelling spice, bark of a tree.\n**Farsi**: دارچین",
    "back": "cinnamon",
    "examples": [
      "I put cinnamon on my oatmeal."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dabc399c-62c0-457e-adf2-8bb487d454e9",
    "front": "**Def**: an herb with grey-green leaves, used to flavour food.\n**Farsi**: مرزنجوش، مریم گلی",
    "back": "sage",
    "examples": [
      "Sage and coriander are herbs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b5d604c9-fe01-4ed1-bdbe-911891cba082",
    "front": "**Def**: an herb used to flavour food, also known as cilantro.\n**Farsi**: گشنیز",
    "back": "coriander",
    "examples": [
      "I added fresh coriander to the soup."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "20ff8657-b0f6-4f5c-aa39-41052ddb0480",
    "front": "**Def**: small, pale-coloured dried grapes (a type of dried fruit).\n**Farsi**: کشمش زرد، مویز روشن",
    "back": "sultanas",
    "examples": [
      "Sultanas and raisins are types of dried fruit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e722567d-2ed5-4c70-b8aa-bdc3ea5d08ed",
    "front": "**Def**: dried grapes (a type of dried fruit).\n**Farsi**: کشمش، مویز",
    "back": "raisins",
    "examples": [
      "Raisins and sultanas are dried fruits."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "02cdc59f-438b-40c2-bb9f-c545ba4b73d8",
    "front": "**Def**: cook over boiling water.\n**Farsi**: بخارپز کردن",
    "back": "steam",
    "examples": [
      "It's healthier to steam the vegetables."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "39b63ee6-9052-4c03-8ba5-a6f3b6c086da",
    "front": "**Def**: a kitchen appliance used to deep-fry fish and potatoes.\n**Farsi**: سرخ‌کن عمیق",
    "back": "deep fat fryer",
    "examples": [
      "She bought a deep fat fryer for making chips."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eed7dc7f-6afb-40e5-aa33-b086d9850aef",
    "front": "**Def**: fry food in a large amount of hot fat or oil.\n**Farsi**: سرخ کردن عمیق",
    "back": "deep-fry",
    "examples": [
      "Don't deep-fry the fish for too long."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "688174c5-b031-4cb7-a642-edf50576f71f",
    "front": "**Def**: a large, deep dish used for cooking meat and vegetables slowly in liquid (also the name of the dish itself).\n**Farsi**: قابلمه چدنی (برای آرام‌پز کردن)، خوراک آرام‌پز",
    "back": "casserole",
    "examples": [
      "We prepared a meat casserole in the evening."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1145ee69-5e55-4060-b35f-34d249a44342",
    "front": "**Def**: cook meat slowly in liquid in a closed container.\n**Farsi**: آرام‌پز کردن، تفت دادن (و سپس آرام پختن)",
    "back": "braise/stew",
    "examples": [
      "Braising the meat makes it very tender."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "034e22d3-7d1b-43da-b059-143105d6a16b",
    "front": "**Def**: an appliance used to chop, slice, and mix meat, vegetables, etc.\n**Farsi**: غذا ساز",
    "back": "food processor",
    "examples": [
      "I used the food processor to chop the onions quickly."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "89ea6150-2a00-44a4-a6b0-9a1a84029aca",
    "front": "**Def**: cut food into small pieces.\n**Farsi**: خرد کردن",
    "back": "chop",
    "examples": [
      "Chop the herbs finely."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9a3c6926-bb58-46b7-9717-29c1f9f57c0d",
    "front": "**Def**: a utensil used to beat eggs, cream, or other liquids rapidly.\n**Farsi**: همزن دستی",
    "back": "whisk",
    "examples": [
      "Use a whisk to beat the eggs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "efaec7dc-acb1-4c9a-8eb5-544dcfce94be",
    "front": "**Def**: mix rapidly to incorporate air.\n**Farsi**: زدن، هم زدن (تخم مرغ، خامه)",
    "back": "beat",
    "examples": [
      "Beat the eggs until they are frothy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "434cacd6-298e-46d0-89e0-907ad808e8f0",
    "front": "**Def**: a bowl-shaped container with holes, used to drain vegetables that have been washed or cooked.\n**Farsi**: آبکش",
    "back": "colander",
    "examples": [
      "Place the cooked pasta in a colander."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e16001cd-ea2a-4b53-a232-9a7ef43b9452",
    "front": "**Def**: remove the liquid from food or containers.\n**Farsi**: آبکش کردن، آب اضافی را خارج کردن",
    "back": "drain",
    "examples": [
      "Drain vegetables cooked in water."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2a0a6466-046d-4b5c-9b9a-f0043a883370",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to grate cheese (e.g., parmesan).\n**Farsi**: رنده",
    "back": "grater",
    "examples": [
      "I need a grater for the cheese."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1773c199-a21f-4b05-90e1-561121f01cfc",
    "front": "**Def**: shred food into small pieces using a grater.\n**Farsi**: رنده کردن",
    "back": "grate",
    "examples": [
      "Grate the cheese over the pasta."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4f980fa7-5208-41a8-81aa-c629e1d8d490",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to crush garlic.\n**Farsi**: سیر له کن",
    "back": "garlic crusher",
    "examples": [
      "The recipe calls for a crushed clove of garlic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b09523f0-d153-42cf-a896-89f7116f4935",
    "front": "**Def**: press or squeeze forcefully so as to break or distort.\n**Farsi**: له کردن، کوبیدن",
    "back": "crush",
    "examples": [
      "Crush the fresh garlic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0e64b83-0542-4f20-aa24-80d149646c99",
    "front": "**Def**: a utensil used to separate solids from liquid or larger solids from smaller ones (e.g., flour).\n**Farsi**: الک، صافی",
    "back": "sieve (tool)",
    "examples": [
      "Use a sieve to remove lumps in flour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f1b6e105-229e-4bbb-8734-5ba6a1c92868",
    "front": "**Def**: pass food through a sieve.\n**Farsi**: الک کردن، صاف کردن",
    "back": "sieve (action)",
    "examples": [
      "You need to sieve the flour before mixing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c0fe948e-8439-43c7-abd2-73c814196c63",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to peel vegetables (e.g., potatoes).\n**Farsi**: پوست‌کن",
    "back": "peeler",
    "examples": [
      "Where is the potato peeler?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9c57fa3e-09e3-49b0-984e-84d97c3059b1",
    "front": "**Def**: remove the outer skin or rind of a fruit or vegetable.\n**Farsi**: پوست کندن",
    "back": "peel",
    "examples": [
      "Peel the potatoes before boiling them."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6f690ca7-d958-4840-b318-aeecabd3c4c1",
    "front": "**Def**: a small tool used to squeeze lemons or limes.\n**Farsi**: آب‌لیمو/آب‌مرکبات‌گیر",
    "back": "lemon squeezer",
    "examples": [
      "She bought a lemon squeezer for the cocktail."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5fa6637f-dc97-46db-bb9a-9a32d5d85ae2",
    "front": "**Def**: press firmly, typically with one's fingers.\n**Farsi**: فشردن، آب گرفتن",
    "back": "squeeze",
    "examples": [
      "Squeeze the lemons to get the juice."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4ca0b548-dd8d-498f-bedc-7255586c790c",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to open wine bottles by pulling out the cork.\n**Farsi**: چوب‌پنبه‌بازکن",
    "back": "corkscrew",
    "examples": [
      "I need a corkscrew to open a bottle of wine."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ccf334-e136-471d-aeda-f503b68d3bb4",
    "front": "**Def**: a large long-handled spoon with a cup-shaped bowl, used to serve soup.\n**Farsi**: ملاقه",
    "back": "ladle",
    "examples": [
      "Use the ladle to serve soup."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eb5dd268-7987-4935-8102-e74c110c56af",
    "front": "**Def**: present food or drink to someone.\n**Farsi**: سرو کردن",
    "back": "serve",
    "examples": [
      "Serve the dinner immediately."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "21fb5cb9-ddf6-4d93-8c63-339f7d5d26cd",
    "front": "**Def**: an instrument used to weigh all types of food.\n**Farsi**: ترازوی آشپزخانه",
    "back": "kitchen scales",
    "examples": [
      "I weighed the flour on the kitchen scales."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8273230b-4400-4d7b-8835-fa07ae274b48",
    "front": "**Def**: find out how heavy something is.\n**Farsi**: وزن کردن",
    "back": "weigh",
    "examples": [
      "Weigh the ingredients accurately."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2b3a8694-ce1c-4b18-905e-b571ef331ec0",
    "front": "**Def**: go badly wrong and be very unsuccessful.\n**Farsi**: به مشکل خوردن، خراب شدن (نقشه، برنامه)",
    "back": "go pear-shaped (idiom, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I said the plan would work, but it all went pear-shaped."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f0116645-a516-40c3-a5f1-dbe9dd468f56",
    "front": "**Def**: admit that something you said was wrong.\n**Farsi**: حرف خود را پس گرفتن، اعتراف به اشتباه کردن",
    "back": "eat your words (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "I was wrong and in the end I had to eat my words."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "857c7b3d-4de9-42b5-8889-9ac80d599d66",
    "front": "**Def**: an appliance used to steam fish, rice, vegetables.\n**Farsi**: بخارپز",
    "back": "steamer",
    "examples": [
      "Use a steamer to cook the rice perfectly."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d093fac8-0897-44fc-a737-94ecc6ba1ed3",
    "front": "**Def**: spend more time doing something than is necessary.\n**Farsi**: اغراق کردن، بیش از حد لازم وقت صرف کردن",
    "back": "make a meal of sth (idiom, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "It took two men three days to build that little wall. They really made a meal of it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3e232a9c-14cb-416c-b8c8-fb6c7af6e6d3",
    "front": "**Def**: suspicious, and probably involving dishonesty.\n**Farsi**: مشکوک، بودار",
    "back": "fishy (adj, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "A man knocked on the door and said that if I gave him £100, it sounded fishy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5bf40c5d-7c07-4036-9c72-58fad6459be1",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who supports their family with money they earn.\n**Farsi**: نان‌آور خانواده",
    "back": "breadwinner",
    "examples": [
      "Since Jamie lost his job, Marcia has been the main breadwinner."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "61e5e0b5-1277-4658-b0dc-4d0abe588034",
    "front": "**Def**: don't be too confident that something will be successful, because it may go wrong.\n**Farsi**: جوجه را آخر پاییز می‌شمارند (زود مطمئن نباش)",
    "back": "don't count your chickens (idiom, SAYING)",
    "examples": [
      "You might get the money but don't count your chickens."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "99e8e3a3-ce73-4640-99d0-eb1ededb2068",
    "front": "**Def**:  a crazy person.\n**Farsi**: آدم دیوانه، خل و چل",
    "back": "nutcase (n, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Ali's brother's a complete nutcase."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eda89b1e-fb28-4987-b190-976570b30c86",
    "front": "**Def**: used for saying that two people are very different.\n**Farsi**: مثل آسمان و ریسمان بودن، مثل زمین تا آسمان فرق داشتن",
    "back": "like chalk and cheese (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "Maggie and her sister are like chalk and cheese."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9d8b3e4b-85fd-4215-a755-ad7cc232295a",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely attractive or impressive. SYN beautiful.\n**Farsi**: حیرت‌انگیز، فوق‌العاده زیبا",
    "back": "stunning",
    "examples": [
      "Prague is a stunning city."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fd19a3f9-d755-4daf-896a-086dd18bcb09",
    "front": "**Def**: growing and developing, and very successful. SYN flourishing.\n**Farsi**: پررونق، شکوفا، موفق",
    "back": "thriving",
    "examples": [
      "This thriving capital of the Czech Republic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf5d7562-0aeb-4de5-8925-8a83b462f0b1",
    "front": "**Def**: full of life and energy.\n**Farsi**: سرزنده، پرجنب و جوش",
    "back": "vibrant",
    "examples": [
      "A romantic and vibrant city-break destination."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd4d2074-02af-4e60-a332-170d48fda623",
    "front": "**Def**: streets with a surface of old round stones.\n**Farsi**: خیابان‌های سنگفرش",
    "back": "cobbled streets",
    "examples": [
      "A stroll through Prague's cobbled streets is wonderfully exciting."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a848dfbe-6eb0-4820-98cb-f4dc58d9eef7",
    "front": "**Def**: in an unusual or surprising way. remarkable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: به طرز چشمگیری، قابل ملاحظه",
    "back": "remarkably",
    "examples": [
      "Its architecture is remarkably diverse."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0496afb3-262e-4b8e-9199-81200f5148db",
    "front": "**Def**: of many different kinds.\n**Farsi**: متنوع",
    "back": "diverse",
    "examples": [
      "The architecture is remarkably diverse."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "96feb441-acae-44af-8e3d-6e3ecfba5902",
    "front": "**Def**: experience a process of change.\n**Farsi**: متحمل شدن، از سر گذراندن",
    "back": "undergo sth",
    "examples": [
      "The Clock has recently been undergoing restoration."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "473d42d0-3541-439d-a04c-00f07ad62f67",
    "front": "**Def**: the work of repairing old buildings, paintings, etc.\n**Farsi**: مرمت، بازسازی",
    "back": "restoration",
    "examples": [
      "The buildings need to be repaired (restoration)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c3a17c32-ebf5-4cb1-a98d-0a72b7c93340",
    "front": "**Def**: relax and do very little.\n**Farsi**: اوقات را به بطالت گذراندن، استراحت مطلق کردن",
    "back": "laze around",
    "examples": [
      "Laze around on the golden, sandy beaches."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9b53912f-e6cb-4ab4-9582-9caf06e97006",
    "front": "**Def**: absorb or take something into your senses, body, or mind.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، لذت بردن کامل (از چیزی)",
    "back": "soak sth up",
    "examples": [
      "Soak up the atmosphere of traditional fishing villages."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5abfdd2b-5bc5-4aa7-8403-577a43ff3d35",
    "front": "**Def**: walk slowly without a real purpose or direction.\n**Farsi**: گشت و گذار کردن، پرسه زدن",
    "back": "go for a wander (around/in)",
    "examples": [
      "Just go for a wander around Albufeira's old town."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c6d71fa7-9b20-43fd-9552-31f0b60c867c",
    "front": "**Def**: keep something. retention N.\n**Farsi**: حفظ کردن، نگه داشتن",
    "back": "retain sth (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "The old town still retains its wonderful charm."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "035bdaba-9bdf-452f-b3e0-cdad993b71dd",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant or attractive quality or feature.\n**Farsi**: جذابیت، دلربایی",
    "back": "charm",
    "examples": [
      "Absorb the charms of the old town."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c427ae0-51ee-49fc-920b-09b3b45957d0",
    "front": "**Def**: a long hard walk, often in the mountains.\n**Farsi**: پیاده‌روی طولانی و دشوار",
    "back": "trek",
    "examples": [
      "Our China trek."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8950a87a-c795-41f0-b32b-e71a579c78a3",
    "front": "**Def**: being the only one of its kind.\n**Farsi**: منحصر به فرد، بی‌نظیر",
    "back": "unique",
    "examples": [
      "Our trek offers a unique experience."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9e25a2d1-6b71-4b53-aac3-2f97820aaa11",
    "front": "**Def**: go somewhere different to have a rest or holiday.\n**Farsi**: از همه چیز دور شدن و استراحت کردن",
    "back": "get away from it all",
    "examples": [
      "The adventurous traveller wants to get away from it all."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ba7e9fb4-e532-4a04-84f5-fc9ad35e1d09",
    "front": "**Def**: far from places where other people live. SYN isolated.\n**Farsi**: دور، پرت افتاده",
    "back": "remote",
    "examples": [
      "Camp in a remote part of rural China."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bda905df-9fe7-4e4e-8d9a-11b8410c8106",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a place) beautiful because it has not been changed or built on.\n**Farsi**: دست نخورده، بکر",
    "back": "unspoilt",
    "examples": [
      "Experience local life in its most unspoilt state."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7a816fec-72f5-4b81-933a-6f2d983b4885",
    "front": "**Def**: relax (SYN take it easy, chill out).\n**Farsi**: ریلکس کردن، آرام شدن",
    "back": "unwind",
    "examples": [
      "If you need to unwind, try the Algarve."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0939b676-2c04-4791-9648-7f84344b2337",
    "front": "**Def**: have the advantages of something without the disadvantages (implying selfishness).\n**Farsi**: هم خدا را خواستن هم خرما را، بهره‌مندی از همه مزایا بدون پذیرش معایب",
    "back": "have your cake and eat it (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "The trouble with Tanya is she always wants to have her cake and eat it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0c722a0e-4495-4d28-abe1-79c47ece4c46",
    "front": "**Def**: valued traditions, historical buildings, etc.\n**Farsi**: میراث فرهنگی",
    "back": "heritage",
    "examples": [
      "The city protects its cultural heritage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "211b7dae-8245-4367-81b1-152bcbdbdbce",
    "front": "**Def**: exciting and unusual, often from a distant place.\n**Farsi**: عجیب و غریب، غیربومی",
    "back": "exotic",
    "examples": [
      "They serve exotic food at the resort."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd5d09cc-ff8d-46b2-9646-a1c8bd304bf9",
    "front": "**Def**: famous for something.\n**Farsi**: مشهور، نامدار",
    "back": "renowned",
    "examples": [
      "The island is renowned for its seafood."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42073363-6862-4c87-93fc-846ac0b7b8c6",
    "front": "**Def**: travelling a long distance (flight/destination).\n**Farsi**: مسافت طولانی",
    "back": "long-haul",
    "examples": [
      "This is a very long-haul flight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "266f3acc-c5d5-4986-9262-40d18f781916",
    "front": "**Def**: calm and peaceful.\n**Farsi**: آرام، ساکت و آرامش‌بخش",
    "back": "tranquil",
    "examples": [
      "We looked for a tranquil spot by the river."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ccebc617-e4c8-4815-8a54-487418df943e",
    "front": "**Def**: very frightening or exciting in a way that you enjoy.\n**Farsi**: هیجان‌انگیز، مو بر تن سیخ کن",
    "back": "spine-tingling",
    "examples": [
      "A spine-tingling ghost story."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e28a03b5-ac54-4fb8-a6a4-bf10dc858434",
    "front": "**Def**: a story about the spirit of a dead person that sb hears or sees.\n**Farsi**: داستان ارواح، داستان شبح",
    "back": "ghost story",
    "examples": [
      "I love reading ghost stories before bed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6e5499de-1d7e-4225-a588-8dea3e72a411",
    "front": "**Def**: very excited and interested in something (often a story or performance).\n**Farsi**: لب مرز نشستن (بسیار هیجان‌زده و مشتاق بودن)",
    "back": "on the edge of your seat (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "The play will have you on the edge of your seat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fdf10beb-2eea-4a6a-a468-2a2f6b43059f",
    "front": "**Def**: the scenery and furniture used in a play, film, etc.\n**Farsi**: صحنه آرایی، دکور",
    "back": "set",
    "examples": [
      "The production used a minimal set."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7d6e3bfc-a30e-47c3-994c-ef5b680fd557",
    "front": "**Def**: sounds that are made artificially in a play, film, etc., to make it more realistic.\n**Farsi**: جلوه‌های صوتی",
    "back": "sound effects",
    "examples": [
      "The film used incredible sound effects."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5acebfb1-27be-4824-a1ba-19553b074421",
    "front": "**Def**: frighten someone very much.\n**Farsi**: تا سر حد مرگ ترساندن",
    "back": "scare sb out of their wits (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "This drama will scare you out of your wits!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c258132c-f084-4bff-8f1a-7c68cc5b760c",
    "front": "**Def**: making you very excited or worried. SYN gripping.\n**Farsi**: پرتنش، هیجان‌آور (به حدی که ناخن بجوی)",
    "back": "nail-biting",
    "examples": [
      "The plot was a nail-biting finish."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ec09eddc-9eb3-4a58-ab4d-6c2b6a9d66cc",
    "front": "**Def**: a book or play that has been made into a film, TV programme, etc.\n**Farsi**: اقتباس",
    "back": "adaptation",
    "examples": [
      "A nail-biting adaptation of Susan Hill's novel."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f7205bbf-a1c2-4188-bb0e-b9ae9f183038",
    "front": "**Def**: an unexpected change or development in a story or situation.\n**Farsi**: پیچش داستانی، تحول غیرمنتظره",
    "back": "twist",
    "examples": [
      "The plot twists are brilliant."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a969f4d-2533-4e15-ae29-04e475ba64e7",
    "front": "**Def**: (singular or plural verb) all the people who act in a play or film.\n**Farsi**: بازیگران، تیم بازیگری",
    "back": "cast",
    "examples": [
      "The cast of two are sensational."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ff901ec8-4762-423c-9090-4464af4a7e99",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely good; wonderful. SYNS fabulous, brilliant.\n**Farsi**: فوق‌العاده، محشر، عالی",
    "back": "sensational (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "The cast are sensational!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "26f6106d-1d4a-4b89-8271-528317c9e604",
    "front": "**Def**: the sound of an audience showing approval by hitting their hands together. applaud V.\n**Farsi**: کف زدن، تشویق",
    "back": "applause",
    "examples": [
      "The applause went on and on."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5ec91fd7-3510-4cf1-bff2-eb322dbb0970",
    "front": "**Def**: in a way that is agreed by everyone. unanimous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: به اتفاق آراء، یک‌صدا",
    "back": "unanimously",
    "examples": [
      "Unanimously acclaimed by the critics."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de26eb9c-cd86-4075-8465-04c86cb18a10",
    "front": "**Def**: publicly talked or written about in an admiring way. acclaim N.\n**Farsi**: تحسین شده، مورد ستایش قرار گرفته",
    "back": "acclaimed",
    "examples": [
      "Unanimously acclaimed by the critics."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "67f621f7-9e45-4c91-9409-3a270f6fc852",
    "front": "**Def**: very bad and unpleasant. SYN dire INF.\n**Farsi**: افتضاح، فجیع، خیلی بد",
    "back": "atrocious",
    "examples": [
      "I had to sit through some atrocious, sentimental movie."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a78f9a1-c395-4cbe-bde7-ebf792f967d9",
    "front": "**Def**: boring, long, and slow.\n**Farsi**: خسته کننده، ملال‌آور",
    "back": "tedious",
    "examples": [
      "Yes, it was tedious, wasn't it?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3047e1ca-8214-495b-85c0-20a2fd213417",
    "front": "**Def**: a phrase or idea that has been used so often it no longer has much meaning and is not interesting. clichéd ADJ.\n**Farsi**: کلیشه",
    "back": "cliché",
    "examples": [
      "The film was full of clichés."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bb624dc7-04e4-46fd-ae3e-f36c27a29f07",
    "front": "**Def**: not showing serious thought, feelings, etc. SYN superficial.\n**Farsi**: سطحی، کم عمق",
    "back": "shallow",
    "examples": [
      "The female characters were shallow."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f4c68fca-bb25-49b4-99a0-6e41a7ab5bfc",
    "front": "**Def**: very weak.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، سست",
    "back": "feeble",
    "examples": [
      "It was all terrible - feeble jokes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0efda874-bcbf-4207-9dda-3e13578f4598",
    "front": "**Def**: not showing enough natural expression, emotion, or movement (especially acting/dialogue).\n**Farsi**: بی‌روح، خشک، غیرطبیعی",
    "back": "wooden",
    "examples": [
      "The acting was quite wooden."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0dc632cf-b9e3-48f0-a0da-5a9e680373c2",
    "front": "**Def**: of only average quality.\n**Farsi**: متوسط، نه چندان خوب",
    "back": "mediocre",
    "examples": [
      "The acting was very mediocre."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f7147124-3ca5-44b2-a217-5863bcf6fd20",
    "front": "**Def**: relax.\n**Farsi**: آرامش گرفتن، حال کردن (عامیانه)",
    "back": "chill out (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm going to chill out all weekend."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd0b144e-e7e6-4632-bfe1-70ec4a7998a2",
    "front": "**Def**: complete (used to emphasize something bad).\n**Farsi**: تمام، مطلق (معمولاً برای تأکید بر بدی)",
    "back": "utter",
    "examples": [
      "It was utter rubbish."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1563d953-d0da-4d58-86f1-43f54e76def1",
    "front": "**Def**: poor quality; nonsense.\n**Farsi**: مزخرف، آشغال",
    "back": "rubbish (n, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "The film was utter rubbish."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "423e41f8-7b9e-48c2-8b26-be3089c44dc5",
    "front": "**Def**: very boring.\n**Farsi**: به طرز کشنده‌ای کسل‌کننده",
    "back": "deadly dull (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "The musical was absolutely deadly dull."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ed622cf4-d0b6-4ab3-ac36-f23aeb4c9517",
    "front": "**Def**: clever and funny.\n**Farsi**: بذله‌گو، شوخ طبع",
    "back": "witty",
    "examples": [
      "The script was very witty."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "646be8ec-fafb-4b06-8f22-55143d8685a3",
    "front": "**Def**: talk enthusiastically about something.\n**Farsi**: با اشتیاق ستایش کردن",
    "back": "rave about sth",
    "examples": [
      "The critics raved about the performance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e274f77-8168-4336-b936-d26b40548523",
    "front": "**Def**: containing a mixture of sadness and happiness.\n**Farsi**: تلخ و شیرین",
    "back": "bitter-sweet",
    "examples": [
      "The ending was bitter-sweet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7755248c-9799-4e9a-980f-f92d3e066adf",
    "front": "**Def**: a film or story intended to make the audience cry.\n**Farsi**: فیلم/داستان اشک‌آور",
    "back": "tear jerker",
    "examples": [
      "It was a real tear jerker."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a3a0a53-7081-41f6-be70-86a30286d408",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant and depressing.\n**Farsi**: سخت، گرفته، تیره و تار",
    "back": "grim",
    "examples": [
      "The future looks grim."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "16edd339-02c1-41bc-806d-cecf51813160",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely distressing or painful.\n**Farsi**: دلخراش، اندوه‌آور",
    "back": "harrowing",
    "examples": [
      "It was a harrowing account of the war."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fb6e8af8-02fe-4962-938f-b2d9c456b5e4",
    "front": "**Def**: playing in their own stadium. OPP away.\n**Farsi**: در خانه، در زمین خودی",
    "back": "at home",
    "examples": [
      "Each team plays the others in their group at home and away."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cbe251a3-1c3b-4cae-b941-aeb2b486c4be",
    "front": "**Def**: be good enough to enter a competition or reach a stage.\n**Farsi**: واجد شرایط شدن، صلاحیت پیدا کردن",
    "back": "qualify for sth",
    "examples": [
      "The group winners qualify for the knockout stage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c2e9329-b946-4982-9732-4246a1892266",
    "front": "**Def**: a competition where the winner continues and the loser is eliminated.\n**Farsi**: حذفی (مسابقات)",
    "back": "knockout",
    "examples": [
      "They qualified for the knockout stage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e2eb1b1e-d156-44be-987d-0c95030b5904",
    "front": "**Def**: a person or team that comes second in a competition.\n**Farsi**: نایب قهرمان(ها)، تیم دوم",
    "back": "runner(s)-up",
    "examples": [
      "The two best runners-up also qualify."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8f055974-18be-4cc5-b135-bc9f323320c0",
    "front": "**Def**: the remaining people or things; the others.\n**Farsi**: بقیه، مابقی",
    "back": "the rest (of sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The rest are eliminated."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "871c060e-39dd-4703-b09a-2a10bbed5a03",
    "front": "**Def**: an act of deciding which teams play against each other by pulling names out of a bag. be drawn (against sb) v.\n**Farsi**: قرعه‌کشی",
    "back": "draw (n)",
    "examples": [
      "The draw for the quarter-final round."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a026fb67-a685-4821-a4b8-3d2118562a06",
    "front": "**Def**: a stage in a sports competition.\n**Farsi**: دور (مسابقات)",
    "back": "round",
    "examples": [
      "We managed to win in the first round."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a6002c2-7ea3-4d2a-b760-f0741348111a",
    "front": "**Def**: reach the next stage in a competition.\n**Farsi**: صعود کردن، راه یافتن (به مرحله بعد)",
    "back": "get through (to sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The two teams that get through their semi-final."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "abd1f4f5-dea8-4e22-892d-b7dbff7c0efa",
    "front": "**Def**: not belonging to either of the teams who are playing.\n**Farsi**: بی‌طرف",
    "back": "neutral",
    "examples": [
      "They play the final at a neutral venue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a32e1ffa-ca99-4384-82c1-b6ed8ca6aa4e",
    "front": "**Def**: a place where an organized event happens.\n**Farsi**: محل برگزاری",
    "back": "venue",
    "examples": [
      "They play the final at a neutral venue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1064d9f8-3066-477a-90c0-d6b65de3a265",
    "front": "**Def**: success in a game, war, etc. victorious ADJ.\n**Farsi**: پیروزی، فتح",
    "back": "victory",
    "examples": [
      "Victory for the winners."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5cf00dc9-4cf0-42d1-8da8-615f789c379a",
    "front": "**Def**: the way in which someone is performing (in or on good/great form; off form).\n**Farsi**: فرم، عملکرد، وضعیت آمادگی",
    "back": "form (performance)",
    "examples": [
      "Our form in the league was poor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e19d7dd5-5539-48a4-9fbf-5b5151d45b45",
    "front": "**Def**: a set of teams who play each other over a season to find the best team.\n**Farsi**: لیگ",
    "back": "league",
    "examples": [
      "The league title is still undecided."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "65cbf9f8-9500-4437-a9df-3b4573066a9e",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of performing well or badly.\n**Farsi**: دوره (خوب/بد) عملکرد",
    "back": "a (good/bad) run",
    "examples": [
      "We've had a good run lately."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d916cafc-a6fd-47ff-960c-5d1611cece21",
    "front": "**Def**: not having lost.\n**Farsi**: شکست‌ناپذیر، بدون باخت",
    "back": "unbeaten",
    "examples": [
      "We're unbeaten now in six matches."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ed159454-2989-41cb-9d1b-e9b3993c547c",
    "front": "**Def**: the action of moving a team up to a higher league. OPP relegation N.\n**Farsi**: صعود (به لیگ بالاتر)",
    "back": "promotion",
    "examples": [
      "We had an outside chance of promotion."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "35f4651f-c5d3-45f2-b1a5-8b8d8d956d56",
    "front": "**Def**: fail to give someone the help and support they need.\n**Farsi**: ناامید کردن، تنها گذاشتن",
    "back": "let sb down",
    "examples": [
      "Recently he's let us down."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d99adf7f-16c4-40f0-be5a-47f9dbb5267d",
    "front": "**Def**: in a stressful situation.\n**Farsi**: تحت فشار",
    "back": "under pressure",
    "examples": [
      "When the opposition put us under pressure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3f196f5b-e527-4aae-9b0b-cbc3009bc30e",
    "front": "**Def**: sit down and relax.\n**Farsi**: لم دادن و استراحت کردن",
    "back": "put your feet up (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "Put your feet up and enjoy the garden."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "212b1888-0b72-4e1b-85e3-deb62a35c9fd",
    "front": "**Def**: not seeming true or real. OPP convincing.\n**Farsi**: غیرقابل باور، نامطمئن",
    "back": "unconvincing",
    "examples": [
      "Maggie Lovett was pretty unconvincing too."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3d04ffc2-89eb-4337-b274-b1147e8fad5a",
    "front": "**Def**: near to the moment of doing or achieving something.\n**Farsi**: در آستانه چیزی بودن",
    "back": "on the verge of sth",
    "examples": [
      "We were on the verge of winning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e78212d2-3dbd-411b-83b9-f4fc9cf2770b",
    "front": "**Def**: a small chance (of success).\n**Farsi**: شانس ضعیف",
    "back": "outside chance",
    "examples": [
      "We had an outside chance of promotion."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d91d4e26-8ab5-49d1-87cd-886a9ec99816",
    "front": "**Def**: a high possibility; good opportunity.\n**Farsi**: شانس بزرگ",
    "back": "great chance",
    "examples": [
      "This season could be my great chance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2e51506d-f837-4fa6-a609-9069496e1352",
    "front": "**Def**: hire a player to play for a team.\n**Farsi**: بازیکن جدید جذب کردن",
    "back": "sign a player",
    "examples": [
      "The club signed a new striker."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "764ae42c-566d-4263-8422-8ce5fec06f06",
    "front": "**Def**: defeat someone heavily.\n**Farsi**: شکست سخت دادن، درهم کوبیدن",
    "back": "thrash sb",
    "examples": [
      "We thrashed them 5-0."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "310a9b48-b060-4159-9a4c-b3d9e32a4860",
    "front": "**Def**: move a player from one team to another.\n**Farsi**: انتقال دادن (بازیکن)",
    "back": "transfer sb",
    "examples": [
      "He was transferred to a Spanish club."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "78212960-cc0b-4c86-8f03-6dafd2168553",
    "front": "**Def**: a ranked player or team in a competition.\n**Farsi**: سید (بازیکن/تیم رده‌بندی شده)",
    "back": "seed (n)",
    "examples": [
      "He was the top seed in the tournament."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3547ab99-fb7d-43ec-a46f-5f6517ef14e2",
    "front": "**Def**: play your first game for a team.\n**Farsi**: اولین بازی خود را انجام دادن",
    "back": "make your debut",
    "examples": [
      "The young player made his debut yesterday."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "69eb1cdc-122e-4ce1-ab18-6eb398d9b691",
    "front": "**Def**: SYN copy sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: تقلید کردن",
    "back": "imitate sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "A garden which imitates the best of nature."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ce96fc10-2155-48e3-81c8-40c6ac52e025",
    "front": "**Def**: obtain something by buying it or being given it.\n**Farsi**: به دست آوردن، کسب کردن",
    "back": "acquire sth",
    "examples": [
      "Having acquired a cottage in the country."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d4ab5521-53ae-4550-9857-457be8c22cb0",
    "front": "**Def**: a small house, especially in the country.\n**Farsi**: کلبه، خانه ییلاقی",
    "back": "cottage",
    "examples": [
      "We stayed in a charming cottage by the sea."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c50015f7-f7b6-439b-8848-ded702326e7a",
    "front": "**Def**: animals, birds, and insects that live in a natural state.\n**Farsi**: حیات وحش",
    "back": "wildlife",
    "examples": [
      "Plants to attract wildlife such as bees and butterflies."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "14515db8-04d7-4ce1-84c8-2ef8a96936eb",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of land that is used for something (camping site/building site).\n**Farsi**: محل، سایت، قطعه زمین",
    "back": "site",
    "examples": [
      "The site is ideal for a garden."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1f2f8137-2f5c-4943-9bfe-9d6bca284231",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of land that is higher at one end than the other.\n**Farsi**: شیب، سراشیبی",
    "back": "slope",
    "examples": [
      "A gentle slope going down to a pond."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "472360af-a1b7-4c50-b4b8-34dec43bc5a4",
    "front": "**Def**: a small simple building, made of wood, and often found in gardens.\n**Farsi**: آلونک، انبار کوچک",
    "back": "shed",
    "examples": [
      "There's a shed in the garden for tools."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1a6120-83ac-4f10-9ed0-b00b5d1eb41e",
    "front": "**Def**: make something/someone come towards you.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، جلب کردن",
    "back": "attract sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "Plants to attract wildlife."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1830476b-03cf-4138-b943-e2160a97f720",
    "front": "**Def**: throw or drop things in different directions over a wide area.\n**Farsi**: پراکنده کردن، افشاندن",
    "back": "scatter sth",
    "examples": [
      "I've scattered seeds to create a meadow."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "38040817-92c4-49a2-8341-acc80abb14c0",
    "front": "**Def**: the small hard part of a plant from which new plants grow.\n**Farsi**: دانه، تخم",
    "back": "seed",
    "examples": [
      "I've bought lots of packets of seed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c69eaa5f-30dc-42c4-b59f-bfc88ec2a2bb",
    "front": "**Def**: a field covered in grass, and often wild flowers.\n**Farsi**: چمنزار، مرغزار",
    "back": "meadow",
    "examples": [
      "A wild-flower meadow."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbae61bb-b9ff-410a-bc66-d23bf6784d75",
    "front": "**Def**: a place where birds lay their eggs and live with their young. nest v.\n**Farsi**: لانه، آشیانه",
    "back": "nest",
    "examples": [
      "I hope birds will soon build nests."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef88763f-3538-498b-af58-7a43048487cb",
    "front": "**Def**: the physical world and everything that lives in it.\n**Farsi**: طبیعت",
    "back": "nature (concept)",
    "examples": [
      "We can say someone is interested in nature."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1d413888-45ce-4828-8424-6dea021e36a1",
    "front": "**Def**: a small job that you have to do regularly, often around the home.\n**Farsi**: کار روزمره، وظیفه",
    "back": "chore",
    "examples": [
      "I've got lots of chores to do today."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5befb451-6cf7-4c00-9c1f-4b3f56c8ec82",
    "front": "**Def**: a mixture of decaying plants and food that is added to soil to help things grow.\n**Farsi**: کود گیاهی، کمپوست",
    "back": "compost",
    "examples": [
      "Add compost to enrich the soil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "085c210c-846f-4f57-9089-ab9a9802bbbc",
    "front": "**Def**: improve the quality of something by adding something to it.\n**Farsi**: غنی‌سازی کردن",
    "back": "enrich sth",
    "examples": [
      "We need to enrich the soil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "29390fa0-3eab-47e5-9bdc-a469172d0180",
    "front": "**Def**: the top part of the earth in which trees and plants grow.\n**Farsi**: خاک",
    "back": "soil",
    "examples": [
      "Compost makes the soil more fertile."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7bf5dbdd-305d-4bef-aac2-fe05235cac6f",
    "front": "**Def**: remove some of a plant's stems or branches to improve future growth. SYN cut sth back.\n**Farsi**: هرس کردن، شاخه‌زنی کردن",
    "back": "prune sth",
    "examples": [
      "Prune certain bushes and plants."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9cc0c0aa-756c-4cb6-a1b7-b55f57a0f5cf",
    "front": "**Def**: (of the earth) wet from too much rain. mud N.\n**Farsi**: گِل‌آلود",
    "back": "muddy",
    "examples": [
      "The ground is muddy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d52ed9cc-51b1-4cb5-a938-889fc3c0bfa4",
    "front": "**Def**: remove the weeds (= wild plants growing where they are not wanted).\n**Farsi**: علف هرز کندن",
    "back": "do the weeding",
    "examples": [
      "Do regular weeding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a9f46758-c1d9-4ba4-82d6-6831005fcdd6",
    "front": "**Def**: (in sport) play better than and be in control of the game. SYN be on top.\n**Farsi**: مسلط بودن، برتری داشتن",
    "back": "dominate",
    "examples": [
      "We dominated the game."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "58006880-1a44-4649-97b8-fdaf94461ffe",
    "front": "**Def**: cut the grass on the lawn.\n**Farsi**: چمن‌زنی کردن",
    "back": "mow the lawn",
    "examples": [
      "Mow the lawn once a week."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "82aa8c84-6114-4fad-b8ca-87796c56f36c",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used for digging (a shovel).\n**Farsi**: بیلچه، بیل",
    "back": "spade",
    "examples": [
      "Have you got something I can use for digging? Have you got a spade?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ca18c145-3a2a-4440-bc76-71c71fcb4874",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine for cutting grass.\n**Farsi**: ماشین چمن‌زنی",
    "back": "lawnmower",
    "examples": [
      "The grass needs cutting - you'll find the lawnmower in the garden."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cc7c5a00-8de1-4ede-90dc-cb3ca2824deb",
    "front": "**Def**: a garden tool with a long handle and prongs, used for gathering leaves.\n**Farsi**: چنگک، شن‌کش",
    "back": "rake",
    "examples": [
      "I used a rake to clear the leaves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "56334eff-41b5-4d05-883b-7fc2315838e0",
    "front": "**Def**: plant seeds in the ground.\n**Farsi**: بذر کاشتن، تخم پاشیدن",
    "back": "sow (v)",
    "examples": [
      "I need to sow the vegetable seeds."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40323cc3-5b9d-41af-89cd-109334af8df9",
    "front": "**Def**: small animals or insects that damage plants or food.\n**Farsi**: آفت‌ها",
    "back": "pests",
    "examples": [
      "The plant is covered in garden pests."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "870e74dc-399a-454a-a0e5-91c386389f7e",
    "front": "**Def**: looking for something.\n**Farsi**: در جستجوی چیزی",
    "back": "in search of sth",
    "examples": [
      "I went into town in search of some shoes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "699b06eb-50ed-45ee-9432-a6bdd347eccf",
    "front": "**Def**: a label on something which shows how much you must pay.\n**Farsi**: برچسب قیمت",
    "back": "price tag",
    "examples": [
      "The price tag was still on the clothes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42809f65-bd82-4b2e-be90-0f8d4645fe93",
    "front": "**Def**: spend a long time shopping because you don't want to stop (till = until).\n**Farsi**: آنقدر خرید کردن که از حال بروی",
    "back": "shop till you drop (idiom, MODERN INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm not the kind of person who shops till they drop."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "33f87c51-6f3f-4089-ab0a-fab776d5029b",
    "front": "**Def**: casually look at things in a shop, or look through the pages of a book.\n**Farsi**: سرسری نگاه کردن، گشت زدن (در مغازه)",
    "back": "browse (v)",
    "examples": [
      "I stopped to browse through this magazine."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c9453e77-9f51-481a-877a-9fe4da91e7a4",
    "front": "**Def**: looking for and trying to obtain something.\n**Farsi**: در پی چیزی بودن",
    "back": "after sth",
    "examples": [
      "You're after a particular buy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "077ec0da-ef13-41cd-8aad-91152d2148d8",
    "front": "**Def**: as soon as. SYN the moment.\n**Farsi**: همین که، به محض اینکه",
    "back": "the minute (phrase)",
    "examples": [
      "The minute you've got it, you're off."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "01cfff50-7a8d-4e0d-a898-9e23dd6f10fd",
    "front": "**Def**: go; leave.\n**Farsi**: رفتن، ترک کردن (مکان)",
    "back": "be off (phrasal verb)",
    "examples": [
      "I told Patsy that I had to be off."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c1dffe4-eb4a-40b8-913f-f7947c9eced3",
    "front": "**Def**: have a natural ability to see or find something (often used for bargains or detail).\n**Farsi**: ذوق و سلیقه داشتن، چشم تیزبین داشتن (برای چیزی)",
    "back": "have an eye for sth (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "You have an eye for a bargain."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ba0d9494-4a14-44ee-ad89-d33677bad40e",
    "front": "**Def**: go to different shops until you find what you want.\n**Farsi**: مغازه به مغازه گشتن (برای یافتن بهترین قیمت/محصول)",
    "back": "shop around (v)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm happy to shop around."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef1e6651-18d7-4511-ba59-58134ea02fd0",
    "front": "**Def**: having a very clear aim; knowing what you want to do.\n**Farsi**: متمرکز",
    "back": "focused",
    "examples": [
      "You're incredibly focused."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "46eaf00c-f1f0-4955-a119-20a447fa9418",
    "front": "**Def**: hobby, pastime (leisure/outdoor pursuits).\n**Farsi**: سرگرمی، مشغله",
    "back": "pursuit (leisure)",
    "examples": [
      "Shopping is the UK's fourth favourite leisure pursuit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7eb58bc7-5bbd-4c41-ba12-7c89d7ca63a1",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period of time doing one activity in an uncontrolled way (spending/shopping spree).\n**Farsi**: ولخرجی، افراط (در یک دوره کوتاه)",
    "back": "spree",
    "examples": [
      "How often do you go on a spending spree?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4759747e-4efc-402a-b7a3-00dbfae34078",
    "front": "**Def**: looking for something at a good price and cheaper than usual.\n**Farsi**: شکار تخفیف، جستجوی ارزان‌قیمت",
    "back": "bargain hunting",
    "examples": [
      "She tends to indulge in a bit of bargain hunting."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9c0e1a27-e1d7-4fe4-a67f-d8934b2ffa40",
    "front": "**Def**: go in the direction of.\n**Farsi**: به سمت جایی رفتن، رهسپار شدن",
    "back": "head for/towards",
    "examples": [
      "Millions of us head for the shops every weekend."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "405a0b5d-302b-4f46-8fb4-bbe9f15c0bc4",
    "front": "**Def**: do something you like, especially something that is bad for you.\n**Farsi**: افراط کردن، زیاده‌روی کردن",
    "back": "indulge in sth",
    "examples": [
      "They indulge in this popular pastime."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d710ab2c-6e1b-4a4c-80de-16a62ea2694a",
    "front": "**Def**: a small tool or piece of equipment that does something useful.\n**Farsi**: ابزارک، وسیله کاربردی کوچک",
    "back": "gadget",
    "examples": [
      "Men over 50 now outspend women because of their love of gadgets."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "100cf526-bd2e-43ce-82cc-e6f62ab4a7e0",
    "front": "**Def**: someone who enjoys shopping and spends a lot of time doing it.\n**Farsi**: خرید بیمارگونه، معتاد به خرید",
    "back": "shopaholic (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "A small number may become compulsive shoppers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "15529dba-d8f3-4788-afb4-77591de22d05",
    "front": "**Def**: finding it difficult to control their actions (a compulsive shopper/gambler/liar).\n**Farsi**: اجباری، غیرقابل کنترل",
    "back": "compulsive",
    "examples": [
      "Compulsive shoppers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5fe18d7-61e6-4586-b2d5-73b607cb6a89",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to stop doing something which is usually harmful. addict N.\n**Farsi**: معتاد به چیزی",
    "back": "addicted to sth",
    "examples": [
      "It's easy to get addicted to things such as drugs or alcohol."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "791e5c24-127b-4f29-8f9b-4c9f13a8a1b9",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat a sick person successfully.\n**Farsi**: درمان کردن",
    "back": "cure V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from cure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9b190a44-6029-4939-b1ac-581cd88980c2",
    "front": "**Def**: put flowers and other plants into the soil.\n**Farsi**: کاشتن",
    "back": "plant sth (v)",
    "examples": [
      "Plant bulbs for the following spring."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "68c5f288-6429-4923-8f4d-9567775b5cf5",
    "front": "**Def**: be greater or more important than something else.\n**Farsi**: سنگین‌تر بودن، ارجح بودن",
    "back": "outweigh (prefix out-)",
    "examples": [
      "The advantages outweigh the disadvantages."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "62fde74c-b462-44b0-af46-2b8aea961598",
    "front": "**Def**: shopping to cheer yourself up.\n**Farsi**: تسکین روحی با خرید",
    "back": "retail therapy",
    "examples": [
      "She needed some retail therapy after a difficult week."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "49164178-55a6-488b-8e5a-0f613e1cbd51",
    "front": "**Def**: a shop that sells donated goods for charity.\n**Farsi**: مغازه خیریه",
    "back": "charity shop",
    "examples": [
      "I bought this jacket from a charity shop."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c001fc7-090b-4630-9c2a-328303d19428",
    "front": "**Def**: argue about the price until a lower price is agreed.\n**Farsi**: چانه زدن",
    "back": "haggle",
    "examples": [
      "She tried to haggle for a better price."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "892d01f0-262b-4ae5-ab18-902341bfa1e5",
    "front": "**Def**: feel excitement from an activity.\n**Farsi**: لذت/هیجان شدید بردن از چیزی",
    "back": "get a buzz/rush from sth (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "He gets a rush from extreme sports."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bb732948-cd26-4ff5-9d8e-5ebc7dae0c3a",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is giving a meal or a party. hostess N.\n**Farsi**: میزبان",
    "back": "host (n)",
    "examples": [
      "Paula and Simon are the hosts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5a849839-0f54-49ab-b190-6c6a33481393",
    "front": "**Def**: provide something for someone, especially food, drink, or transport.\n**Farsi**: تدارک دیدن، فراهم کردن",
    "back": "lay sth on (phrasal verb, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "The host is expected to lay on food and drink."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "120e3df7-20be-46f3-8bfd-d8f23f422e4d",
    "front": "**Def**: needing a lot of time (a time-consuming process).\n**Farsi**: زمان‌بر",
    "back": "time-consuming",
    "examples": [
      "Organizing a party can be expensive and time-consuming."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2fe42cc6-14a4-497a-ac00-85bbad4eb199",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that you give or do to help something be successful. contribute v.\n**Farsi**: مشارکت، سهم، کمک",
    "back": "contribution",
    "examples": [
      "Everyone made a contribution."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de2f4486-0308-485e-bda2-8e722e87ceda",
    "front": "**Def**: leave everything clean and tidy (after a party/mess).\n**Farsi**: مرتب کردن، جمع و جور کردن",
    "back": "clear (sth) up",
    "examples": [
      "A lot of food means a lot of clearing up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "403f7e6a-58be-4cac-a0fb-cc2a80baeccb",
    "front": "**Def**: intended to be used once or twice then thrown away.\n**Farsi**: یکبار مصرف",
    "back": "disposable",
    "examples": [
      "Think about disposable plates and cutlery."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "83162a6d-9603-4ab9-8216-9d7722e0ee63",
    "front": "**Def**: before something else happens or is done.\n**Farsi**: از قبل، پیشاپیش",
    "back": "beforehand (adv)",
    "examples": [
      "Don't advertise it on the internet beforehand."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3a5ff1dc-98a6-409f-a66d-a37baa36cc0b",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a party or event) start to become interesting and enjoyable.\n**Farsi**: گرم شدن (مهمانی)، هیجان‌انگیز شدن",
    "back": "warm up (phrasal verb)",
    "examples": [
      "Parties take a while to warm up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "560ad764-f341-4fc2-942a-e66a2007d215",
    "front": "**Def**: very loud.\n**Farsi**: کر کننده، بسیار بلند",
    "back": "deafening",
    "examples": [
      "Music that is not so deafening."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "14a8cfb7-4499-45fc-9e2d-ca8a9f06c815",
    "front": "**Def**: be louder than other sounds, so they can't be heard.\n**Farsi**: صدای چیزی را تحت الشعاع قرار دادن (به دلیل بلند بودن)",
    "back": "drown sth out (phrasal verb)",
    "examples": [
      "Don't have the music so loud that it drowns out the conversation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b880ea8d-767f-4619-9343-b2556bff96ce",
    "front": "**Def**: make something more exciting.\n**Farsi**: هیجان دادن، پرشور کردن",
    "back": "liven sth up (phrasal verb)",
    "examples": [
      "Party games can liven things up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a5cdff0-4b37-4ba9-9bd4-87d73aea7bea",
    "front": "**Def**: become very excited or lose control of your feelings.\n**Farsi**: از خود بیخود شدن، هیجان‌زده شدن بیش از حد",
    "back": "get/be carried away (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "Don't get carried away!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "424ed6eb-975f-44b4-878f-ec4870b21bca",
    "front": "**Def**: go somewhere quickly or for a fairly short time.\n**Farsi**: سر زدن، سریع رفتن (برای دیدار کوتاه)",
    "back": "pop round/over/in (phrasal verb, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Shall we pop round and see Glynnis?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "025cee28-b476-4c32-824f-9f79ea30d10e",
    "front": "**Def**: want something or want to do something.\n**Farsi**: هوس چیزی کردن، چیزی را خواستن",
    "back": "fancy sth (v, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "She may fancy a bit of company."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aa9e91b4-709a-40c0-8aa1-083bddfc84ea",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you expect something will happen.\n**Farsi**: بدون شک، قطعاً",
    "back": "no doubt (phrase)",
    "examples": [
      "They'll have fun tonight, no doubt."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "337a52a7-e950-4852-b90f-9e0264a30c0d",
    "front": "**Def**: having drunk too much alcohol. get/be drunk.\n**Farsi**: مست، سکران",
    "back": "drunk (adj)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm sure they won't get drunk."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "77bccc12-b194-4ae3-a35b-7cc539df3f13",
    "front": "**Def**: not relaxed or comfortable with other people.\n**Farsi**: معذب، دست و پا چلفتی، ناجور",
    "back": "awkward",
    "examples": [
      "Jim's quite awkward when he's in company."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0aaf3498-9947-42d5-bdae-18a19d7e67ba",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is often alone and usually prefers to be alone.\n**Farsi**: منزوی، گوشه‌گیر",
    "back": "loner",
    "examples": [
      "He's a bit of a loner."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8069c1e2-0bf8-4b75-bbc8-d9d31e1ca542",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly informal meeting or party.\n**Farsi**: دورهمی، جلسه دوستانه",
    "back": "get-together (n)",
    "examples": [
      "We're having a get-together tonight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bdcace51-81d6-45ef-9871-083c64b3e745",
    "front": "**Def**: take part in an activity with other people.\n**Farsi**: ملحق شدن، شرکت کردن",
    "back": "join in (phrasal verb)",
    "examples": [
      "Can I join in?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "83b7c09b-cc12-4097-9e7d-e9d60c5fb597",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly reception that makes you feel relaxed.\n**Farsi**: استقبال گرم",
    "back": "warm welcome",
    "examples": [
      "You never get a warm welcome at Laura's."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7ccea89f-7421-4a39-a7bf-08c2aada6c34",
    "front": "**Def**: go with someone.\n**Farsi**: همراهی کردن",
    "back": "accompany (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "I'll accompany you."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "33c6362c-99c2-4d00-944d-90c87ae3100d",
    "front": "**Def**: do something to make people feel more relaxed when meeting for the first time.\n**Farsi**: سر صحبت را باز کردن",
    "back": "break the ice (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "We played a game to break the ice."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3e72f9-fa5c-4a57-91f2-eb6e97b9cc58",
    "front": "**Def**: organize a party.\n**Farsi**: مهمانی برگزار کردن",
    "back": "throw a party",
    "examples": [
      "They decided to throw a party for her birthday."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "df2786f6-cbee-4653-b662-6759d66a98ba",
    "front": "**Def**: a party to celebrate moving into a new home.\n**Farsi**: مهمانی خانه‌تکانی",
    "back": "housewarming party",
    "examples": [
      "We were invited to their housewarming party."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "32407204-a5d0-4393-88eb-c76451d2d320",
    "front": "**Def**: provide food and drink for a social event.\n**Farsi**: غذا و پذیرایی فراهم کردن/ خدمات پذیرایی",
    "back": "cater/catering",
    "examples": [
      "They hired a company to cater the event."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c069071b-5b25-447b-8579-e56ac39351a7",
    "front": "**Def**: completely change the appearance or character of sth, often to make it better.\n**Farsi**: متحول کردن، دگرگون کردن",
    "back": "transform sth",
    "examples": [
      "Computers have transformed our lives."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf67a146-c028-4cd2-97b8-16afb95e715f",
    "front": "**Def**: The state or process of being transformed.\n**Farsi**: تحول، دگرگونی",
    "back": "transformation N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from transform"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5ea6c065-5ff0-400f-99f5-72c1c762c8a2",
    "front": "**Def**: make changes to correct a mistake or improve a law, statement, document, etc.\n**Farsi**: اصلاح کردن، متمم زدن",
    "back": "amend sth",
    "examples": [
      "Civil servants are now amending the document."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "484d7d33-b009-4ecc-a54d-7e89be4cb00d",
    "front": "**Def**: A change or addition designed to correct or improve a text or law.\n**Farsi**: اصلاحیه، متمم",
    "back": "amendment N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from amend"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e6c61ecf-66cf-48e4-b682-e2ce924c0bb0",
    "front": "**Def**: change your behaviour in order to be more successful in a new situation. SYN adjust (to sth).\n**Farsi**: وفق دادن، سازگار شدن (با)",
    "back": "adapt to sth",
    "examples": [
      "We must adapt to a changing world."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d9f05a1c-7d1a-4d4e-b0dd-cbdb60a7238e",
    "front": "**Def**: learn and get used to sth which is new and different.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، خو گرفتن",
    "back": "assimilate sth",
    "examples": [
      "It takes time to assimilate new ideas."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e45b35b2-7db1-4c11-ba5e-cf6062c236ee",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of becoming assimilated.\n**Farsi**: جذب، همانندسازی",
    "back": "assimilation N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from assimilate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "042240cb-559b-458f-ba14-ca4db378e034",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of evolving.\n**Farsi**: تکامل، فرگشت",
    "back": "evolution N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from evolve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f016f7c7-d7b5-4f8b-87a4-2b17764e2a34",
    "front": "**Def**: a process or period of change from one state to another (a society in transition is changing).\n**Farsi**: گذار، دوره انتقال",
    "back": "transition FML",
    "examples": [
      "We hope for a smooth transition."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e95a6d53-fbe0-4ceb-8ad2-fa98e660e508",
    "front": "**Def**: change back to a state or situation that existed in the past. SYN go back.\n**Farsi**: بازگشتن (به حالت قبلی)",
    "back": "revert (back) to sth",
    "examples": [
      "After weeks of unrest, life has reverted to normal."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "14440597-f453-4d54-a5c3-f374ca880764",
    "front": "**Def**: return sth to its former state or condition.\n**Farsi**: احیا کردن، بازگرداندن",
    "back": "restore sth",
    "examples": [
      "Some people want to restore the monarchy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b5b64fcf-4f7e-45ee-9d6b-c8147ca85682",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of restoring.\n**Farsi**: بازسازی، احیا",
    "back": "restoration N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from restore"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "87d949b8-18bd-4206-b761-96d8ecd99a3b",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of reversing.\n**Farsi**: وارونگی، برعکس شدن",
    "back": "reversal N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from reverse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c64e73b1-572b-4e0f-8026-0ff3a2fdf96f",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to be reversed. OPP irreversible.\n**Farsi**: برگشت پذیر",
    "back": "reversible ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from reverse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "af460691-df5e-446a-9ab0-73305bd5da88",
    "front": "**Def**: improve a system, an organization, a law, etc. by making changes to it.\n**Farsi**: اصلاح کردن، بهبود بخشیدن",
    "back": "reform sth",
    "examples": [
      "There are new proposals to reform the prison system."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4c43af66-3582-4af3-a852-f821b9cf4687",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of reforming.\n**Farsi**: اصلاح، دگرسازی",
    "back": "reform N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from reform"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ddcf90f9-c1a2-4294-afd5-a81f97d328e9",
    "front": "**Def**: refuse to accept sth and try to stop it happening.\n**Farsi**: مقاومت کردن در برابر",
    "back": "resist sth",
    "examples": [
      "Most employees resist change..."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "faa5204a-8eba-4ca7-ab2c-009a72f7e289",
    "front": "**Def**: The refusal to accept or comply with something.\n**Farsi**: مقاومت",
    "back": "resistance N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from resist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3199b52c-50e3-40d4-93c8-d88d0f125993",
    "front": "**Def**: make people obey sth (enforce the law).\n**Farsi**: به اجرا درآوردن، تحمیل کردن (قانون)",
    "back": "enforce sth",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from glossary definition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1b203d69-5327-4d5c-a54f-75429afa08dc",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of enforcing.\n**Farsi**: اجرا، اعمال",
    "back": "enforcement N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from enforce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aee33e6b-5643-47f4-bb99-b787e3566aba",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb accept sth against their wishes.\n**Farsi**: تحمیل کردن (چیزی بر کسی)",
    "back": "impose sth on/upon sb",
    "examples": [
      "change that is enforced and imposed upon them."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b07b9ae-6c13-49eb-8ebf-80e2de5011c5",
    "front": "**Def**: follow or try to achieve sth over a period of time (pursue a policy/goal).\n**Farsi**: دنبال کردن، پیگیری کردن",
    "back": "pursue sth",
    "examples": [
      "wants to pursue a policy..."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d3e9e0a3-40ed-4586-aa94-aaa8698fb7f8",
    "front": "**Def**: being with other people, or an enjoyable person (good company).\n**Farsi**: معاشرت، هم‌صحبتی",
    "back": "company (being with people)",
    "examples": [
      "I like company (being with other people)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1ded85e8-dcfe-48be-9d7c-9d5e45a7bcd5",
    "front": "**Def**: not easy to notice or understand (subtle difference). OPP obvious.\n**Farsi**: ظریف، نامحسوس",
    "back": "subtle",
    "examples": [
      "or even subtle, changes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ad6c866b-9961-4904-a84d-cb47920483ea",
    "front": "**Def**: make an act or process easier to achieve.\n**Farsi**: تسهیل کردن، آسان کردن",
    "back": "facilitate sth",
    "examples": [
      "their role is to facilitate change"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d09f710e-3dd1-4cb0-9008-b9a69007756f",
    "front": "**Def**: continuing to develop (an ongoing process/investigation).\n**Farsi**: مستمر، در حال انجام",
    "back": "ongoing",
    "examples": [
      "This requires an ongoing consultation process"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a19e2234-175f-4e0a-b707-35fd569886c4",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of discussing sth with sb before making a decision.\n**Farsi**: مشاوره، رایزنی",
    "back": "consultation",
    "examples": [
      "an ongoing consultation process with the staff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ad7b3a6b-ae4a-4030-b070-a99d13d5013e",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to consultation.\n**Farsi**: مشورتی",
    "back": "consultative ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from consultation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "81fd732e-5bf9-4d23-b507-39726bdbf514",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of implementing.\n**Farsi**: اجرا، پیاده سازی",
    "back": "implementation N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from implement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9b718d1c-3086-4508-8124-cedc1e45df75",
    "front": "**Def**: A big or fundamental change.\n**Farsi**: تغییر بنیادین/اساسی",
    "back": "radical change",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8477ffc-d21d-433e-a2fb-eadd9c2dd3fd",
    "front": "**Def**: A big and important change.\n**Farsi**: تغییر عمده/بزرگ",
    "back": "major change",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0e7dfe2f-3284-4669-a72c-baff64828e65",
    "front": "**Def**: A change involving many people or things.\n**Farsi**: تغییر کلی/عمده",
    "back": "wholesale change",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d3192589-92b8-42f5-927a-26c4cf357986",
    "front": "**Def**: a change that is pleasantly new or different.\n**Farsi**: تغییر دلپذیر/تازه",
    "back": "refreshing change",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd786493-e4d9-4f56-958f-66f5fe85aee0",
    "front": "**Def**: a change that is pleasantly new or different.\n**Farsi**: تغییر خوشایند",
    "back": "welcome change",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d85ed285-462b-42e7-b619-87c45b3f6ccb",
    "front": "**Def**: avoid wasting sth.\n**Farsi**: حفظ کردن، صرفه‌جویی کردن",
    "back": "conserve sth",
    "examples": [
      "Three easy ways to conserve energy in the home"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "98bddc51-47eb-4ed3-9b5e-71d7e9b2f8f2",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of conserving.\n**Farsi**: حفاظت، صرفه‌جویی",
    "back": "conservation N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from conserve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9e377a94-1459-448a-9344-28464a0216eb",
    "front": "**Def**: change from using one thing to using another.\n**Farsi**: سوییچ کردن به، عوض کردن با",
    "back": "switch to sth",
    "examples": [
      "Switch to energy-saving eco light bulbs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "296cfc89-5f6c-4ed0-a5b1-107c56136df0",
    "front": "**Def**: not wasting much energy (water-saving, labour-saving).\n**Farsi**: کم‌مصرف، صرفه‌جویی در انرژی",
    "back": "energy-saving",
    "examples": [
      "Switch to energy-saving eco light bulbs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e9995e47-1f20-4c70-a25b-aea7ab080b82",
    "front": "**Def**: (short for ecology) relating to the environment (eco-home, eco-disaster).\n**Farsi**: زیست‌محیطی، دوستدار محیط زیست",
    "back": "eco(-)",
    "examples": [
      "eco light bulbs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "febc5ec9-9062-4bdf-8403-f0793a36e31f",
    "front": "**Def**: send out sth such as light, heat, sounds, gas, etc.\n**Farsi**: منتشر کردن، ساطع کردن",
    "back": "emit sth",
    "examples": [
      "They emit less heat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "22f84cfe-2ee3-423f-9d97-30694829d8d7",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of emitting.\n**Farsi**: انتشار، ساطع شدن",
    "back": "emission N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from emit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e0412a42-f9b3-46df-949a-3beddcc6468f",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of using energy, food, or materials.\n**Farsi**: مصرف",
    "back": "consumption",
    "examples": [
      "reduce your energy consumption."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b842987c-423d-4abf-bc6b-24d490505766",
    "front": "**Def**: To use up (energy, food, or materials).\n**Farsi**: مصرف کردن",
    "back": "consume V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from consumption"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a136eca-0a53-41d1-9eea-aec6e28c7cd5",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine you use at home e.g. fridge, washing machine.\n**Farsi**: لوازم خانگی، دستگاه",
    "back": "appliance",
    "examples": [
      "Never leave electrical appliances"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a7d9d5e-4576-49ba-b079-20a5a311a86f",
    "front": "**Def**: If a TV is on standby, it is connected to the power supply but is not in use.\n**Farsi**: در حالت آماده‌باش (استندبای)",
    "back": "on standby",
    "examples": [
      "appliances such as TVs on standby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "01503a62-d3df-40a3-8f09-48e61bd9a6e7",
    "front": "**Def**: pass electricity through sth to store it there, using a charger (N).\n**Farsi**: شارژ کردن",
    "back": "charge sth (up)",
    "examples": [
      "mobile phone charging unnecessarily."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "93678730-75b3-4ce7-9585-d8d0d13baee2",
    "front": "**Def**: A device used to charge batteries.\n**Farsi**: شارژر",
    "back": "charger N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from charge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f367385-7b02-4d9b-9453-6b10aa180ca5",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine that uses hot air to dry clothes.\n**Farsi**: خشک‌کن چرخشی (لباسشویی)",
    "back": "tumble dryer",
    "examples": [
      "Get rid of your tumble dryer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "edce8f51-2897-4987-a5b9-b2ed584db1cc",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of land where large amounts of rubbish are buried.\n**Farsi**: محل دفن زباله",
    "back": "landfill (site)",
    "examples": [
      "making landfill sites even more toxic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9db97212-7166-4878-a940-a335e46f692f",
    "front": "**Def**: poisonous (toxic chemicals/gases/substances).\n**Farsi**: سمی، زهرآلود",
    "back": "toxic",
    "examples": [
      "making landfill sites even more toxic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6dff17df-ce6c-4bc7-afcf-0d5ad2211fa9",
    "front": "**Def**: even better (still is used to make a comparison stronger).\n**Farsi**: بهتر از آن، حتی بهتر",
    "back": "better still",
    "examples": [
      "or better still, solar chargers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aa0a5c8f-8d36-48ea-8728-df67e8acf43c",
    "front": "**Def**: batteries that can be recharged.\n**Farsi**: باتری‌های قابل شارژ",
    "back": "rechargeable batteries",
    "examples": [
      "Use rechargeable batteries"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "00288040-9e0e-45be-8183-373f8c6b2132",
    "front": "**Def**: a big change that will have an important effect.\n**Farsi**: تغییر گسترده، دگرگونی وسیع",
    "back": "sweeping change",
    "examples": [
      "aims to bring about sweeping... changes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9cf6dc5c-79e7-48ca-9e99-74b5fda49535",
    "front": "**Def**: (of fruit and vegetables) ready for eating now and available in large numbers. OPP out of season.\n**Farsi**: فصلی، در فصل",
    "back": "in season",
    "examples": [
      "use local produce which is in season"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0faada61-94a0-4317-a948-9e85201cb946",
    "front": "**Def**: Not ready for eating or available in large numbers.\n**Farsi**: خارج از فصل",
    "back": "out of season",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from in season"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e887abb8-300a-4bf8-9072-b8783b2efc8d",
    "front": "**Def**: the distance food travels from where it is grown or produced to where it is consumed.\n**Farsi**: مایل غذایی (فاصله حمل غذا)",
    "back": "food miles",
    "examples": [
      "reduce food miles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a9848142-f87e-47dd-b61f-5954b75f6638",
    "front": "**Def**: To throw away.\n**Farsi**: دور انداختن",
    "back": "dispose of sth V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from disposable"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "632750b0-e008-4e11-a68a-8bece2830b14",
    "front": "**Def**: treat sth so that it can be used again.\n**Farsi**: بازیافت کردن",
    "back": "recycle sth",
    "examples": [
      "and recycle at least 80 per cent of all waste."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "715c3414-aa97-48ce-a272-033858b2ead4",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of treating things so they can be used again.\n**Farsi**: بازیافت",
    "back": "recycling N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from recycle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8b053125-21a5-46ce-892f-e4a9f5bff4eb",
    "front": "**Def**: reduce sth as much as possible.\n**Farsi**: به حداقل رساندن",
    "back": "minimize sth",
    "examples": [
      "and to minimize energy use."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "13765209-d218-4f6b-8f67-dded63c3bd60",
    "front": "**Def**: using methods which do not harm the environment (sustainable agriculture/energy).\n**Farsi**: پایدار، سازگار با محیط زیست",
    "back": "sustainable",
    "examples": [
      "In the most sustainable restaurant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "84bb791a-2554-4c61-b7cc-26da270de2c8",
    "front": "**Def**: The ability to be sustained.\n**Farsi**: پایداری",
    "back": "sustainability N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from sustainable"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8d54d291-817e-4ce9-9540-d11869c81af1",
    "front": "**Def**: how much CO2 is emitted from your personal energy use (reduce your carbon footprint).\n**Farsi**: رد پای کربن",
    "back": "carbon footprint",
    "examples": [
      "reduce each customer's carbon footprint."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5a460a00-8935-49db-8343-690e1b179fca",
    "front": "**Def**: Helping the environment.\n**Farsi**: دوستدار محیط زیست",
    "back": "eco-friendly",
    "examples": [
      "an eco-friendly light bulb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "faa40040-d3b7-4408-a5b2-02416b91932a",
    "front": "**Def**: Helping the environment.\n**Farsi**: سازگار با محیط زیست",
    "back": "environmentally-friendly",
    "examples": [
      "environmentally-friendly cleaning products"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3c5df56f-1b76-419e-8d6d-bf70c3930a5a",
    "front": "**Def**: easy to use or understand.\n**Farsi**: کاربرپسند، استفاده آسان",
    "back": "user-friendly",
    "examples": [
      "user-friendly instructions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bdb60b57-b7b2-42d8-9ea0-626e1d957716",
    "front": "**Def**: A large new project or enterprise.\n**Farsi**: سرمایه‌گذاری پرخطر، پروژه",
    "back": "venture",
    "examples": [
      "SYN enterprise"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "92271ebd-6946-4de1-8393-031edeedb2d1",
    "front": "**Def**: the place where a plant or animal is usually found (natural habitat).\n**Farsi**: زیستگاه، محل سکونت",
    "back": "habitat",
    "examples": [
      "Some birds are in danger of losing their habitat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e886bfb2-0bc4-473f-9c38-28f723008a93",
    "front": "**Def**: The natural home of an animal or plant.\n**Farsi**: زیستگاه طبیعی",
    "back": "natural habitat",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from habitat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2a63d0a0-3aef-44f9-ba67-6b0f0ebae8d9",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of clearing forests (= removing trees).\n**Farsi**: جنگل‌زدایی، از بین بردن جنگل",
    "back": "deforestation",
    "examples": [
      "Deforestation is a real threat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f273a827-4e72-4ffe-aba2-8a013c7d6a88",
    "front": "**Def**: species in danger because numbers are falling.\n**Farsi**: گونه‌های در معرض خطر",
    "back": "endangered species",
    "examples": [
      "The African elephant is an endangered species."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c6d91eca-9e74-4d16-bfc2-f93841fdd9ff",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of animals, plants, etc. whose members are similar and can breed with each other.\n**Farsi**: گونه",
    "back": "species",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from definition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "098d4b07-3d0a-4467-9bb8-ad4e0f4a3fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to be harmed or damaged; also threatened with sth.\n**Farsi**: در معرض خطر، تهدید شده",
    "back": "under threat (of sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Many wild animals are under threat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d1545e2d-b2bc-4b46-ad3c-c8a94b5d50c2",
    "front": "**Def**: a protected area for plants, animals, etc. (a wildlife/nature reserve).\n**Farsi**: منطقه حفاظت شده، ذخیره‌گاه",
    "back": "reserve",
    "examples": [
      "We can protect certain species by creating reserves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "400c3e17-770c-42bb-a6fd-a8357f78d9a3",
    "front": "**Def**: A protected area for animals.\n**Farsi**: ذخیره‌گاه حیات وحش",
    "back": "wildlife reserve",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from reserve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "af73930d-7c26-4fd6-9098-b20edddee5f1",
    "front": "**Def**: A protected area for nature.\n**Farsi**: ذخیره‌گاه طبیعی",
    "back": "nature reserve",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from reserve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8cc13b5f-9971-406c-830b-f677c1f69e06",
    "front": "**Def**: in a natural environment not controlled by people.\n**Farsi**: در طبیعت، در حیات وحش",
    "back": "in the wild",
    "examples": [
      "In the wild, giant pandas eat bamboo exclusively."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b57e88f0-438a-420d-838d-87c4e16c2fbb",
    "front": "**Def**: kept in a zoo or park, etc.\n**Farsi**: در اسارت",
    "back": "in captivity",
    "examples": [
      "The bear was born in captivity."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "86ab7f08-6e57-43e7-82b2-a51ed001f41b",
    "front": "**Def**: continuously decreasing in number, quantity, etc. (gradual/steady decline).\n**Farsi**: در حال کاهش، رو به زوال",
    "back": "in decline",
    "examples": [
      "Snow leopard populations are in decline."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9708545b-619d-46ae-9ea7-ec467ae847b7",
    "front": "**Def**: A slow decrease.\n**Farsi**: کاهش تدریجی",
    "back": "gradual decline",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from in decline"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "12ef8e8f-4816-4d36-b3a6-a1a3a00b0683",
    "front": "**Def**: A consistent decrease.\n**Farsi**: کاهش مداوم",
    "back": "steady decline",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from in decline"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4ce01a7d-fd6a-4e23-baf9-b878afd7c4b0",
    "front": "**Def**: a large, new project. SYN venture.\n**Farsi**: طرح بزرگ، ابتکار",
    "back": "enterprise",
    "examples": [
      "a groundbreaking enterprise."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa850540-1372-43a6-96ea-c8fd4b0ec116",
    "front": "**Def**: become less common and eventually disappear.\n**Farsi**: منقرض شدن",
    "back": "die out",
    "examples": [
      "This species of cat is dying out."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2a2c0ed2-8a96-4ecf-b98c-9d58c9f33c99",
    "front": "**Def**: If a plant or animal is extinct, it no longer exists.\n**Farsi**: منقرض",
    "back": "extinct ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "baf8d11b-565d-407c-b519-2336ddb66fda",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being extinct.\n**Farsi**: انقراض",
    "back": "extinction N.",
    "examples": [
      "The species is in danger of extinction."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bbfe038d-c4b5-4a57-8b42-3fc9056d5e5d",
    "front": "**Def**: very close to extinction.\n**Farsi**: در آستانه انقراض",
    "back": "on the verge of extinction",
    "examples": [
      "It is on the verge of extinction."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5aa31669-7d2d-48d2-bd74-43e1d18620b3",
    "front": "**Def**: the illegal hunting of animals, birds, etc.\n**Farsi**: شکار غیرقانونی",
    "back": "poaching",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from glossary definition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd685516-2ee0-4f67-80eb-61ab7ce82d57",
    "front": "**Def**: The person who hunts illegally.\n**Farsi**: شکارچی غیرقانونی",
    "back": "poacher N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from poaching"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd631563-f198-4484-a47d-16626d9bed2a",
    "front": "**Def**: create a threat (also pose a risk/danger to sb/sth).\n**Farsi**: تهدیدی ایجاد کردن برای",
    "back": "pose a threat to sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "This poses the greatest threat to this species"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e0933ccd-95af-4738-881c-bc0085ae8fed",
    "front": "**Def**: wanted by many people but not easy to get.\n**Farsi**: پرطرفدار، کمیاب",
    "back": "sought after",
    "examples": [
      "which is particularly sought after"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8ce710c1-491b-428a-8b45-4f4f084238d4",
    "front": "**Def**: use sth for a purpose that is different from its original purpose.\n**Farsi**: منحرف کردن، تغییر مسیر دادن",
    "back": "divert sth (from sth)",
    "examples": [
      "War diverts funds from conservation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "868e4554-6318-458a-a95d-ef683731f61a",
    "front": "**Def**: money available to be spent (raise funds = collect money).\n**Farsi**: بودجه، وجوه",
    "back": "funds PL",
    "examples": [
      "War diverts funds from conservation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0c1a12d7-260b-4d9e-90ee-3391122f8a4d",
    "front": "**Def**: To collect money.\n**Farsi**: جمع آوری پول/کمک مالی",
    "back": "raise funds",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from funds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a342bde-80a7-465f-9794-a1344f5aa744",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being poor.\n**Farsi**: فقر، نداری",
    "back": "poverty",
    "examples": [
      "high levels of poverty in affected areas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f19b171e-1e93-4529-a17d-c7e8f3dc53f7",
    "front": "**Def**: SYN probability.\n**Farsi**: احتمال",
    "back": "likelihood",
    "examples": [
      "increase the likelihood that people will turn to poaching."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c4e881d-85d4-4968-846f-1aab6bfae6e1",
    "front": "**Def**: The extent to which something is likely to happen.\n**Farsi**: احتمال",
    "back": "probability SYN",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from likelihood"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d2fceec4-76e0-4441-aada-3c8dcf091338",
    "front": "**Def**: have a bad effect on sth.\n**Farsi**: خسارت سنگینی وارد کردن، صدمه زدن",
    "back": "take a heavy toll on sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "Civil disturbance has taken a heavy toll on rhino populations."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd99d920-4695-4c6a-80d1-9f93ec0d1c6d",
    "front": "**Def**: gradually cover more and more of an area.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز کردن به، دست‌اندازی کردن",
    "back": "encroach on/upon sth FML",
    "examples": [
      "people encroach on the rhinos' territory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5b15e0c3-4361-4585-a4e7-0328ef6ff19a",
    "front": "**Def**: an area an animal regards as its own and defends against others.\n**Farsi**: قلمرو، محدوده",
    "back": "territory",
    "examples": [
      "encroach on the rhinos' territory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "52b22723-af06-4f5e-9529-801d5bf426d9",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to territory.\n**Farsi**: قلمرویی",
    "back": "territorial ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from territory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "090efbe0-8965-4d75-9047-2dfe64795434",
    "front": "**Def**: a unit of information inside a cell which controls what the living thing will be like.\n**Farsi**: ژن",
    "back": "gene",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from definition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bd198fdb-5fbb-4715-a45d-ac4ba332eb53",
    "front": "**Def**: the total of all the genes in a species.\n**Farsi**: خزانه ژنی",
    "back": "gene pool",
    "examples": [
      "a limited gene pool for breeding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f47a4530-d487-47c7-8329-543765fd1711",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time that has a particular quality or character.\n**Farsi**: عصر، دوره",
    "back": "era",
    "examples": [
      "A revolutionary era in medical advances"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8826ed84-a352-42fb-9e55-7af355fcb55f",
    "front": "**Def**: progress made in science, medicine, technology, etc.\n**Farsi**: پیشرفت، ترقی",
    "back": "advance(s) (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from title"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "89650f6f-2a05-44a2-bc77-1dc1378ef9f8",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of ten years.\n**Farsi**: دهه",
    "back": "decade",
    "examples": [
      "In recent decades"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "939bb6ec-58be-4471-9160-704cb5e72621",
    "front": "**Def**: usual or traditional; not new or different.\n**Farsi**: مرسوم، سنتی",
    "back": "conventional",
    "examples": [
      "conventional medicine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6b7ac60a-780a-4fa9-a2fb-e4dc9660ca0c",
    "front": "**Def**: A way in which something is usually done.\n**Farsi**: عرف، سنت",
    "back": "convention N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from conventional"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "df5a58f1-91f3-4004-8886-b7632d32c5b4",
    "front": "**Def**: used for finding out what physical or mental problem sb has.\n**Farsi**: تشخیصی",
    "back": "diagnostic",
    "examples": [
      "Diagnostic tools were restricted"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b5e1c952-1366-4968-b331-c3e7482b2bd3",
    "front": "**Def**: To identify the nature of an illness.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص دادن",
    "back": "diagnose V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from diagnostic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0bc41b81-f59b-484a-8047-e7d966ca78f6",
    "front": "**Def**: The identification of the nature of an illness.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص (بیماری)",
    "back": "diagnosis N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from diagnostic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eafc7ff0-4e1b-477a-9832-f726b9786f10",
    "front": "**Def**: A limiting condition or measure.\n**Farsi**: محدودیت",
    "back": "restriction N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from restrict"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "935e2742-cd13-48f0-92d0-8b863cd19dcc",
    "front": "**Def**: a medical treatment that makes a sick person well again.\n**Farsi**: درمان، معالجه",
    "back": "cure",
    "examples": [
      "for which there was no effective cure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d033f28d-3fd6-4345-aba7-43040a60bce9",
    "front": "**Def**: destroy or get rid of sth completely.\n**Farsi**: از بین بردن، نابود کردن",
    "back": "wipe sb/sth out",
    "examples": [
      "Deforestation is wiping out certain species."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "827b86ee-c05d-4caa-8b14-0cdbe8fd2f36",
    "front": "**Def**: To administer a vaccine.\n**Farsi**: واکسن زدن",
    "back": "vaccinate V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from vaccine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6ae8b247-344d-4937-82ce-47e4e813fc9b",
    "front": "**Def**: a long-term illness or medical problem.\n**Farsi**: بیماری، عارضه",
    "back": "condition",
    "examples": [
      "eradicated some of these conditions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a26d142-39ab-4e67-92da-574b5dae3c71",
    "front": "**Def**: have to stay in bed / a wheelchair.\n**Farsi**: محدود به بستر/صندلی چرخدار شدن",
    "back": "be confined to bed / a wheelchair",
    "examples": [
      "you would be confined to bed for weeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "650bb03a-b554-492b-8a16-434d86e9eec1",
    "front": "**Def**: (of medical treatment) involving cutting of the body.\n**Farsi**: تهاجمی",
    "back": "invasive",
    "examples": [
      "less invasive procedures"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3d8be4f4-e010-4b02-8533-67c444d0bb38",
    "front": "**Def**: The action of invading.\n**Farsi**: تهاجم",
    "back": "invasion N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from invasive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e3b9e9e4-6638-460c-9f73-6e7f3533ea21",
    "front": "**Def**: To enter in order to seize or subjugate.\n**Farsi**: حمله کردن",
    "back": "invade V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from invasive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "243475d2-c6f0-4a77-962b-da128f050152",
    "front": "**Def**: a medical operation or investigation (carry out / perform a procedure).\n**Farsi**: عمل جراحی، روش درمانی",
    "back": "procedure",
    "examples": [
      "less invasive procedures"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2b3a8a36-0067-432f-baaf-cf4a5573fdc8",
    "front": "**Def**: a part of the body that has a particular purpose, such as the heart or brain.\n**Farsi**: عضو",
    "back": "organ",
    "examples": [
      "patients with organ failure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ccfd0fdf-342f-4f35-bbab-8e5800cd1de5",
    "front": "**Def**: an operation in which a damaged organ is replaced with one from a donor.\n**Farsi**: پیوند (عضو)",
    "back": "transplant",
    "examples": [
      "transplants can allow patients to resume a normal life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b88d06fb-2659-4c59-abe4-e4d68d2ac152",
    "front": "**Def**: To perform a transplant.\n**Farsi**: پیوند زدن",
    "back": "transplant V.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from transplant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d70fceb7-ca2b-4d03-ad95-7074015f3a00",
    "front": "**Def**: someone who gives part of their body, blood, etc.\n**Farsi**: اهدا کننده",
    "back": "donor",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from transplant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd7a1d2d-0921-4102-81e9-91bc3fbc4ad1",
    "front": "**Def**: begin sth again after an interruption.\n**Farsi**: از سر گرفتن، ادامه دادن",
    "back": "resume sth FML",
    "examples": [
      "transplants can allow patients to resume a normal life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7745f0a1-93c1-44ef-961c-df087f394e8b",
    "front": "**Def**: The action of resuming.\n**Farsi**: از سرگیری",
    "back": "resumption N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from resume"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6b0ff157-e12a-40b8-b443-367e28883b31",
    "front": "**Def**: the treatment of diseases, especially cancer, by drugs.\n**Farsi**: شیمی درمانی",
    "back": "chemotherapy",
    "examples": [
      "development of chemotherapy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c9aff44c-75cf-47bd-b625-6233135fa135",
    "front": "**Def**: A measurement of the number of times something happens within a period.\n**Farsi**: نرخ، میزان",
    "back": "rate",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a7651aed-f790-4911-b0b4-8b855e4abe9b",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of people dying.\n**Farsi**: نرخ مرگ و میر",
    "back": "mortality rate / death rate",
    "examples": [
      "the mortality rate for patients with organ failure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "38698859-1fff-486a-a8e6-59ab7351fb69",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of people continuing to live despite a serious illness.\n**Farsi**: نرخ بقا",
    "back": "survival rate",
    "examples": [
      "The survival rate for many cancers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9ef198cb-3884-40ce-8a4f-8d7327a7fc23",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of babies born.\n**Farsi**: نرخ زاد و ولد",
    "back": "birth rate",
    "examples": [
      "The birth rate rocketed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a5ce514-bd4f-470f-8dbe-d68a761d82ca",
    "front": "**Def**: to rise sharply.\n**Farsi**: به سرعت بالا رفتن",
    "back": "rocket V",
    "examples": [
      "The birth rate rocketed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "39cfd7f5-5626-477e-b6c9-049f5f0af8be",
    "front": "**Def**: to fall sharply.\n**Farsi**: به سرعت سقوط کردن",
    "back": "plummet V",
    "examples": [
      "The accident rate plummeted."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5c93f4d4-43eb-464f-b7a5-462366aee929",
    "front": "**Def**: the secret numbers or letters you have to put into a computer in order to use it.\n**Farsi**: رمز عبور",
    "back": "password",
    "examples": [
      "Never tell anyone your password."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eab0463c-c988-4880-8769-1abb2df3df64",
    "front": "**Def**: the name you use to operate a computer or program.\n**Farsi**: نام کاربری",
    "back": "username",
    "examples": [
      "My username is LuluG."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aa18a2ba-25c0-4e30-acbe-6729344e9063",
    "front": "**Def**: perform the actions that let you start to use a computer system.\n**Farsi**: وارد شدن به سیستم (لاگین کردن)",
    "back": "log on/in",
    "examples": [
      "When you log on, enter a username or password."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "db508664-69c2-491c-9164-14ea48e9d17a",
    "front": "**Def**: Perform the actions that let you stop using a computer system.\n**Farsi**: خارج شدن از سیستم (لاگ اوت کردن)",
    "back": "log off/out OPP",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from log on/in"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7d49218a-a585-4c64-ba1e-306eb147eaf0",
    "front": "**Def**: move text on a screen up or down so that you can read different parts.\n**Farsi**: بالا و پایین کردن (صفحه)، پیمایش کردن",
    "back": "scroll (up/down)",
    "examples": [
      "Scroll up and down the page using the scroll bar."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe0180d4-0b45-4b3c-b54f-ab848c204199",
    "front": "**Def**: type words into a search engine to find information about sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جستجو کردن در گوگل",
    "back": "google sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "I found him by googling him"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "51d977ed-e98f-4971-a274-dae13cc7ab70",
    "front": "**Def**: type words into a search engine to find information about sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جستجو در وب انجام دادن",
    "back": "do a search (on sth/sb) SYN",
    "examples": [
      "doing a web search on him."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf9cb527-ddf6-428e-8251-6f1f2c74e180",
    "front": "**Def**: a connection between one file or document and another on the web.\n**Farsi**: پیوند، لینک",
    "back": "link",
    "examples": [
      "Click on the link at the bottom of this page."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aa5879c4-4ac6-4a66-b16e-9217df541e43",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of giving a vaccine.\n**Farsi**: واکسیناسیون",
    "back": "vaccination N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from vaccine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "44903c5f-7267-4851-a792-c09409cef0cd",
    "front": "**Def**: a program that enters your computer and destroys or damages your data.\n**Farsi**: ویروس",
    "back": "virus N.",
    "examples": [
      "Have you got anti-virus protection?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0b897704-1d04-456f-b2b4-8d28315ede59",
    "front": "**Def**: a web-based company.\n**Farsi**: کسب و کار الکترونیک",
    "back": "e-business",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d7cef224-5ad9-482a-9df1-a1cef4225dff",
    "front": "**Def**: learning that takes place on computers or the internet.\n**Farsi**: یادگیری الکترونیک",
    "back": "e-learning",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "af20dc94-1dcc-48da-a790-4f1de0efa6f6",
    "front": "**Def**: a café where people pay to use the internet.\n**Farsi**: کافه سایبری، کافی‌نت",
    "back": "cyber-café SYN internet café",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3b6ed0c1-5900-4dfc-9fc7-119daf770a22",
    "front": "**Def**: the imaginary place where emails exist when being sent between computers.\n**Farsi**: فضای مجازی، سایبرفضا",
    "back": "cyberspace",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6ec4f221-d267-4242-b7ec-3df33afc12cc",
    "front": "**Def**: Extremely great or successful.\n**Farsi**: خارق‌العاده، پدیده‌ای",
    "back": "phenomenal ADJ.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from phenomenally"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "505f375f-129b-4932-b61f-6f57fe9dfa5d",
    "front": "**Def**: have an idea, especially an unusual one. SYN think sth up.\n**Farsi**: فکری به سرش زدن، طرحی ریختن",
    "back": "dream sth up INF",
    "examples": [
      "was dreamt up over dinner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e4f1096e-9b0a-4774-b029-42bb228f24df",
    "front": "**Def**: (in computing) the way data is organized in a computer file or program.\n**Farsi**: قالب، فرمت",
    "back": "format",
    "examples": [
      "videos in any format"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "71a234dc-775f-4397-8a03-043ea39652f5",
    "front": "**Def**: a program that lets you look at files on the internet.\n**Farsi**: مرورگر (وب)",
    "back": "(web) browser",
    "examples": [
      "play in any web browser"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ee31a7c7-ba04-400b-8859-5a42ee4cd48e",
    "front": "**Def**: (in computing) created by computers or appearing on computers or the internet (a virtual community, a virtual office, virtual reality).\n**Farsi**: مجازی",
    "back": "virtual",
    "examples": [
      "a virtual video village"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a1682f57-9851-4e77-bebd-cdfbea999ea9",
    "front": "**Def**: a person whose username and password are recorded on a website, so they can enter it.\n**Farsi**: کاربر ثبت‌نام شده",
    "back": "registered user",
    "examples": [
      "where registered users could upload"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe108836-e3ee-4a6c-b8da-6004688698e2",
    "front": "**Def**: send a file, video, etc. from your computer to a larger system using the internet. OPP download sth.\n**Farsi**: بارگذاری کردن، آپلود کردن",
    "back": "upload sth",
    "examples": [
      "registered users could upload their own videoblogs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "82ae5ce0-79be-42d6-9a6e-ebb5ebaeb32a",
    "front": "**Def**: To transfer a file from the internet to your computer.\n**Farsi**: دانلود کردن، بارگیری کردن",
    "back": "download sth OPP",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from upload sth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6760446b-885d-401b-bcc8-a80396e74446",
    "front": "**Def**: a personal video made by sb on sth they are interested in.\n**Farsi**: ویدئوبلاگ",
    "back": "videoblog",
    "examples": [
      "upload their own videoblogs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e70b7e12-5f6e-470e-ba63-d7a4f7636781",
    "front": "**Def**: a short part of a video or film.\n**Farsi**: کلیپ (ویدئویی)، قطعه فیلم",
    "back": "(video) clip",
    "examples": [
      "and clips"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d2827d29-adbd-4695-a7a0-b82bc5f5b72b",
    "front": "**Def**: say how good you think sth is, e.g. good, acceptable, or bad.\n**Farsi**: امتیاز دادن، رتبه‌بندی کردن",
    "back": "rate sth",
    "examples": [
      "and watch and rate other people's."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40ab88a5-4bd8-4ead-a2af-805bf3fe4df0",
    "front": "**Def**: happen at the same time as sth else.\n**Farsi**: همزمان شدن با، منطبق بودن با",
    "back": "coincide with sth",
    "examples": [
      "The rise of such websites coincided with the availability of cheap camcorders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "abc2daf2-94b6-4467-9902-1eec38d83429",
    "front": "**Def**: The occurrence of events at the same time by chance.\n**Farsi**: تصادف، همزمانی",
    "back": "coincidence N.",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from coincide"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9fedcea2-f487-4f78-a299-c710bb9b3850",
    "front": "**Def**: a video camera that can be carried around.\n**Farsi**: دوربین فیلمبرداری دستی",
    "back": "camcorder",
    "examples": [
      "availability of cheap camcorders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0598a1b7-a767-47e8-8522-a4e4716816d0",
    "front": "**Def**: together or at the same time as sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: در کنار، همراه با",
    "back": "alongside sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "and alongside that, the development of easy-to-use software."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "34a9fd63-074b-4c1b-a838-74c03bd8d79a",
    "front": "**Def**: the programs used to operate a computer (install/run a piece of software).\n**Farsi**: نرم‌افزار",
    "back": "software",
    "examples": [
      "easy-to-use software."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d00f77f2-6ec9-49d5-bb54-dcad2ba09ece",
    "front": "**Def**: escape from a dangerous situation, place, or person very quickly.\n**Farsi**: فرار کردن، گریختن",
    "back": "flee (from) sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "We saw long queues of people fleeing the war."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1553310d-f556-42f6-aaf2-b38fdfb3a14b",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is forced to leave their country for political/religious reasons.\n**Farsi**: پناهنده",
    "back": "refugee",
    "examples": [
      "Many refugees have crossed the border to escape the war."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0b04d0bf-291d-405c-9c1b-f9c1f6d49fd2",
    "front": "**Def**: the protection a country gives to a refugee (seek asylum, apply for asylum).\n**Farsi**: پناهندگی (سیاسی)",
    "back": "(political) asylum",
    "examples": [
      "The numbers seeking asylum have increased recently."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c43686bc-5b44-4b87-9dd6-113f374f1743",
    "front": "**Def**: To apply for protection as a refugee.\n**Farsi**: درخواست پناهندگی دادن",
    "back": "seek asylum",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from asylum"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e26edc20-d76f-4f7e-a60b-bbd74c3e0829",
    "front": "**Def**: A group sharing a common culture or race.\n**Farsi**: گروه قومی",
    "back": "ethnic group",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from ethnic minority"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eb8e5a2b-5340-48ae-8eaf-16e2321ee77e",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of sending spam.\n**Farsi**: ارسال هرزنامه",
    "back": "spamming",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spam"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5d30e8d-8f9e-4f3b-960b-0421ee22f192",
    "front": "**Def**: Pertaining to nostalgia.\n**Farsi**: نوستالژیک، حسرت‌بار",
    "back": "nostalgic ADJ",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from nostalgia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "62be002c-9291-48c2-a74f-f14f306db363",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong wish (have no desire to do sth).\n**Farsi**: میل، اشتیاق",
    "back": "desire",
    "examples": [
      "I have no desire to go back."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e8d6ec19-a218-4691-a2b0-a2e57c69c3e0",
    "front": "**Def**: you become familiar with it and accept it as normal. SYN get used to.\n**Farsi**: عادت کردن به، خو گرفتن با",
    "back": "get accustomed to (doing) sth",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f466b652-1b4f-44ca-972c-8dac853732de",
    "front": "**Def**: you become familiar with it and accept it as normal. SYN get accustomed to.\n**Farsi**: عادت کردن به",
    "back": "get used to (doing) sth",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9432286e-d18a-47ad-9e6d-fcb5380654b9",
    "front": "**Def**: you become familiar with a new climate or situation.\n**Farsi**: سازگار شدن با (آب و هوا)",
    "back": "get acclimatized (to sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cc0940c0-ac9a-4d54-9850-d61fda622b55",
    "front": "**Def**: you learn how to do, use, or understand something.\n**Farsi**: قلق چیزی دست کسی آمدن",
    "back": "get the hang of sth INF",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de576b34-76cb-49c6-bcf2-6f75be07d6ef",
    "front": "**Def**: the practice of treating a person or group in society less fairly than others.\n**Farsi**: تبعیض",
    "back": "discrimination",
    "examples": [
      "He had become a victim of racial discrimination."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5f10344-e55c-4ccc-af9b-1e80b0151da2",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat a person or group unfairly.\n**Farsi**: تبعیض قائل شدن",
    "back": "discriminate V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from discrimination"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e1c690a7-9127-40ff-9499-9bd474d12bd0",
    "front": "**Def**: force sb to leave a country, often because they have no right to be there.\n**Farsi**: اخراج کردن (از کشور)",
    "back": "deport sb",
    "examples": [
      "Foreigners may be deported if they enter the country illegally."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d7f823a4-c6dc-445d-a42d-0d2ea08a2f41",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of deporting.\n**Farsi**: اخراج (از کشور)",
    "back": "deportation N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from deport sb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5ff85cca-7a0e-4415-9553-c427a81e032c",
    "front": "**Def**: Having or showing prejudice.\n**Farsi**: متعصب",
    "back": "prejudiced ADJ",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from prejudice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8462ccf9-8373-425d-a780-fda2f63d66d6",
    "front": "**Def**: The movement of people or animals from one place to another.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت",
    "back": "migration N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2cb3f3c3-f142-4e53-b7fd-eb11dc01ff95",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of coming to live in a country that is not your own.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت (به داخل کشور)",
    "back": "immigration N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7755eb74-fba4-4b88-9594-8f1f03b49165",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who comes to live permanently in a foreign country.\n**Farsi**: مهاجر (وارد شونده)",
    "back": "immigrant N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "30ddce73-471d-4079-ba1b-0ca4da11bcc4",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of going to live in another country.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت (به خارج کشور)",
    "back": "emigration N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "27e88126-98b9-4473-a8ab-1602adfdb6dd",
    "front": "**Def**: To leave one's own country in order to settle permanently in another.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت کردن (به خارج)",
    "back": "emigrate V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b39b098d-6170-4d3b-8cad-a54a9266c689",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who leaves their own country in order to settle in another.\n**Farsi**: مهاجر (خارج شونده)",
    "back": "emigrant N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "73ebefa2-f011-4844-9beb-552b47ae61b2",
    "front": "**Def**: People who move abroad to find a better job.\n**Farsi**: مهاجران اقتصادی",
    "back": "economic migrants",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "01604f91-00fa-4a57-af60-a83b16bddf6e",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with the place where you were born and lived for the first years of your life (native country/land/city).\n**Farsi**: بومی، وطنی، اهل",
    "back": "native ADJ/N",
    "examples": [
      "Moving from my native country"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "84c86c50-d6d0-4178-b5ef-df4bfb6ebc9a",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of confusion and anxiety often felt by people staying in another country.\n**Farsi**: شوک فرهنگی",
    "back": "culture shock",
    "examples": [
      "was a huge culture shock."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6ce01ad1-14e1-4e06-9be0-f064c1bbb99b",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of anger or hatred. SYN hostility.\n**Farsi**: دشمنی، کینه",
    "back": "animosity (towards sb)",
    "examples": [
      "didn't suffer the prejudice or animosity that some migrants complain of."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "397a60a0-b17c-4ceb-a74e-8cc9ca2abe92",
    "front": "**Def**: Hostility or antagonism.\n**Farsi**: خصومت",
    "back": "hostility N SYN",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from animosity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "45584433-d2cc-4490-a420-6cbe734f8945",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong belief in sth (this is often a religious faith).\n**Farsi**: اعتقاد، ایمان، مذهب",
    "back": "faith",
    "examples": [
      "including my religious faith"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7a223825-60f0-4dc2-a5c7-ab86c8114315",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to a stereotype.\n**Farsi**: کلیشه‌ای",
    "back": "stereotypical ADJ",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from stereotype"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "098c51e2-6164-4899-a69e-daabad3715d6",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of becoming a full member of a group or society.\n**Farsi**: ادغام، یکپارچگی",
    "back": "integration",
    "examples": [
      "recognize the need for integration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1376ed64-c82f-4e6a-81dc-dd3880539a47",
    "front": "**Def**: To become a full member of a group.\n**Farsi**: ادغام شدن",
    "back": "integrate (into sth) V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from integration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e8fd2657-7ab6-408d-b0b3-3a126a123151",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of sadness mixed with pleasure when you think of happy times in the past.\n**Farsi**: دلتنگی، غم غربت",
    "back": "nostalgia",
    "examples": [
      "I still have feelings of nostalgia for the place where I grew up"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7d68bce4-667a-4f35-aeab-a8b63284bca8",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of sending sb to get professional help (be referred to sb).\n**Farsi**: ارجاع (به متخصص)",
    "back": "referral",
    "examples": [
      "How do I get a referral to a specialist?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "07452a58-4d49-44a0-a4d5-882cabe6e3f7",
    "front": "**Def**: meant to be kept secret (strictly confidential).\n**Farsi**: محرمانه",
    "back": "confidential",
    "examples": [
      "Are medical records strictly confidential?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2cbed870-f9e0-4dbc-9814-86a9e8a681c3",
    "front": "**Def**: Highly secret.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً محرمانه",
    "back": "strictly confidential",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from confidential"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1720beac-c5b0-44e6-9a1b-f527e956d5d5",
    "front": "**Def**: failure to give proper care or attention.\n**Farsi**: غفلت، سهل‌انگاری (پزشکی)",
    "back": "negligence FML",
    "examples": [
      "What if I suspect medical negligence?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e01ac15d-fa2c-4338-9108-8332a001694a",
    "front": "**Def**: Failing to take proper care.\n**Farsi**: سهل‌انگار",
    "back": "negligent ADJ",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from negligence"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5f26b01b-1c7a-4e5f-aeb9-5e66a81e50fa",
    "front": "**Def**: reach, enter, or use sth (gain/have access to sth).\n**Farsi**: دسترسی پیدا کردن به",
    "back": "access sth FML",
    "examples": [
      "How do I access out of hours care in my area?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "06458ea6-d63a-4b03-9968-38a7a3baf930",
    "front": "**Def**: when a surgery, office, etc. is closed.\n**Farsi**: خارج از ساعات کاری (اورژانسی)",
    "back": "out of hours",
    "examples": [
      "How do I access out of hours care"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5fe3620c-7f4b-4169-b624-f7e50fb5826c",
    "front": "**Def**: medical treatment intended to improve sb's appearance (surgical repair after accidents, burns, etc. is called plastic surgery).\n**Farsi**: جراحی زیبایی",
    "back": "cosmetic surgery",
    "examples": [
      "Can I get cosmetic surgery free of charge?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "076c402c-0d3c-432a-bc5a-49a8d6858603",
    "front": "**Def**: Surgical repair after accidents, burns, etc.\n**Farsi**: جراحی پلاستیک",
    "back": "plastic surgery",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from cosmetic surgery"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40cfa044-837c-4452-a4d6-b0c6dd9479cf",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is free of charge it costs you nothing.\n**Farsi**: رایگان، بدون هزینه",
    "back": "free of charge",
    "examples": [
      "Can I get cosmetic surgery free of charge?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "86b9d79a-0b1e-4850-8c7b-eae3f627cadf",
    "front": "**Def**: find or obtain sth (get hold of sb = find or contact sb).\n**Farsi**: به دست آوردن، پیدا کردن",
    "back": "get hold of sth",
    "examples": [
      "How can I get hold of data about clinical trials?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3a490dcb-ffcd-4621-8f40-f13eaeaa8d29",
    "front": "**Def**: a piece or period of research on the effectiveness or safety of drugs or treatment.\n**Farsi**: کارآزمایی بالینی، آزمایش بالینی",
    "back": "clinical trial",
    "examples": [
      "data about clinical trials"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c0f3d63d-1d25-4103-ac10-bd185d4b66ea",
    "front": "**Def**: treatments that are not part of traditional Western medicine, e.g. acupuncture.\n**Farsi**: طب مکمل",
    "back": "complementary medicine",
    "examples": [
      "Is complementary medicine freely available?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a809adc5-0601-408b-b689-d53d96cbba61",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb feel relaxed and not nervous.\n**Farsi**: راحت کردن (کسی را)",
    "back": "put sb at (their) ease",
    "examples": [
      "The nursing staff immediately put me at my ease"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "11b3af38-0210-4627-b013-66b5c3009031",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to give sb information about sth.\n**Farsi**: مطلع نگه داشتن (کسی را)",
    "back": "keep sb informed",
    "examples": [
      "I was kept informed at all times."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "47eaa1cd-ea63-4916-9424-9fdafc537e98",
    "front": "**Def**: perfectly clean (also spotlessly clean). SYN immaculate.\n**Farsi**: بی‌نقص تمیز، لکه‌دار",
    "back": "spotless",
    "examples": [
      "Sister Ann's ward was spotless"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a2732722-9f1f-45ef-8f8d-97b3eb64647d",
    "front": "**Def**: Perfectly clean.\n**Farsi**: بی‌عیب و نقص، پاکیزه",
    "back": "immaculate SYN",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotless"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "927f8116-f297-4dca-be24-5712980561f3",
    "front": "**Def**: paying careful attention to every detail. SYN fastidious.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، با وسواس",
    "back": "meticulous",
    "examples": [
      "done with meticulous care."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "55331aaf-18dc-4921-a43b-0c7d5682e25f",
    "front": "**Def**: Paying careful attention.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، مشکل‌پسند",
    "back": "fastidious SYN",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from meticulous"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "64a571eb-b422-4a27-af7a-60114171d729",
    "front": "**Def**: = sb is always ready to help.\n**Farsi**: هیچ کاری برای کسی دشوار نیست (همیشه آماده کمک)",
    "back": "nothing is too much trouble",
    "examples": [
      "Nothing was too much trouble."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2fadcf6b-8e36-4453-970e-decfe5fb0215",
    "front": "**Def**: a medical operation in which only a very small cut is made in the body.\n**Farsi**: جراحی با سوراخ کلید (لاپاروسکوپی)",
    "back": "keyhole surgery",
    "examples": [
      "I had keyhole surgery on my knee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b7547542-100a-476e-a041-ba440d5bca24",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation full of confusion due to a mistake. SYN muddle.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه، سوء تفاهم، درهم برهمی",
    "back": "mix-up INF",
    "examples": [
      "apart from a mix-up over my notes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b9524604-91fd-4ae0-a65d-ca62c1071da7",
    "front": "**Def**: Confusion or mistake.\n**Farsi**: درهم برهمی",
    "back": "muddle SYN INF",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from mix-up"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "02f98489-0bb3-4f89-8852-8287cdbd5b5f",
    "front": "**Def**: If a treatment is second to none, it is the best.\n**Farsi**: بی‌نظیر، بی‌همتا",
    "back": "second to none",
    "examples": [
      "the treatment was second to none."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "59158448-a459-44d9-b733-fbb7a6e24c40",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely busy, with too many things to do.\n**Farsi**: سرشان شلوغ بودن (از فرط کار)",
    "back": "rushed off your feet",
    "examples": [
      "staff were rushed off their feet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf4f1aad-f081-40aa-9d82-3bdf32080197",
    "front": "**Def**: pay (no) attention to sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: توجه (نکردن) به کسی/چیزی",
    "back": "take (no) notice of sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "no one took any notice of my calls for help."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "51ed85fc-a4a4-4f1e-9a15-1660d3f379e8",
    "front": "**Def**: having a low rank in an organization or profession. OPP senior.\n**Farsi**: رده پایین، تازه کار",
    "back": "junior ADJ/N",
    "examples": [
      "seen by a junior doctor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e17399da-ffe7-4640-9135-da746ef6b21f",
    "front": "**Def**: An elected member of the council.\n**Farsi**: عضو شورا",
    "back": "councillor N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from council"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "89abdd21-c513-4a9f-a63f-7d52758038e0",
    "front": "**Def**: support or defend sth/sb. SYN stick up for sb INF.\n**Farsi**: حمایت کردن از، دفاع کردن از",
    "back": "stand up for sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "We will stand up for the community"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ff81d875-e95a-4330-ba83-4dfdd8a10eaa",
    "front": "**Def**: as the representative of sb.\n**Farsi**: از طرف کسی، به نمایندگی از",
    "back": "on behalf of sb / on sb's behalf",
    "examples": [
      "speak on behalf of residents"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "74062666-d007-4554-a7d3-f9e3564a0c95",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who lives in a particular place. (Also a meaning of citizen).\n**Farsi**: ساکن، مقیم",
    "back": "resident",
    "examples": [
      "speak on behalf of residents"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "debb8863-cee6-4e39-bd34-8646a9dcddbc",
    "front": "**Def**: a person with legal rights in a country (can also mean resident).\n**Farsi**: شهروند",
    "back": "citizen",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from resident"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6994560f-5492-41eb-b334-92c52b56b990",
    "front": "**Def**: think that sth/sb is important and deserves respect.\n**Farsi**: جدی گرفتن",
    "back": "take sth/sb seriously",
    "examples": [
      "take complaints seriously"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8b509fd-982c-4dd6-84bb-46ccb56614db",
    "front": "**Def**: make sure that sth happens or is definite.\n**Farsi**: تضمین کردن، مطمئن ساختن",
    "back": "ensure sth",
    "examples": [
      "ensure they are properly managed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0114b30b-6019-4187-b0db-2f5164dd0fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: a sum of money given, often by the government, for a purpose.\n**Farsi**: کمک مالی، یارانه",
    "back": "grant",
    "examples": [
      "Provide grants for voluntary organizations"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f53fb7c0-834d-4f8a-a532-67ad03686f6b",
    "front": "**Def**: (of work) done by people (volunteers) who choose to do it without being paid.\n**Farsi**: داوطلبانه، اختیاری",
    "back": "voluntary ADJ",
    "examples": [
      "voluntary organizations"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef9b4629-01d9-4bab-aa4a-9e211d53c18e",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who does work without being paid.\n**Farsi**: داوطلب",
    "back": "volunteer N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from voluntary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "222ec939-d5cb-4816-ba8c-ef1c0d653d1a",
    "front": "**Def**: The sector including charities and voluntary organizations.\n**Farsi**: بخش داوطلبانه/غیرانتفاعی",
    "back": "voluntary sector",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from voluntary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "31d6a542-20dd-4baa-aea4-db77f5e4e076",
    "front": "**Def**: An organization set up to provide help and raise money for those in need.\n**Farsi**: خیریه",
    "back": "charity organization",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from voluntary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2dad9131-8839-45af-93b6-098386d2bad4",
    "front": "**Def**: the most important chosen or elected official in a town or city.\n**Farsi**: شهردار",
    "back": "mayor",
    "examples": [
      "The Mayor of London is elected"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a9dd09a-152f-4f16-86cf-de0dd1d6a7fa",
    "front": "**Def**: allowed by rules or laws to do or receive sth. OPP ineligible.\n**Farsi**: واجد شرایط، ذی‌صلاح",
    "back": "eligible",
    "examples": [
      "Londoners eligible to vote"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5e451ce2-cd12-459c-8d82-7e344f8cf9cc",
    "front": "**Def**: Not allowed by rules or laws.\n**Farsi**: فاقد شرایط",
    "back": "ineligible OPP",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from eligible"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "530d6da7-e89a-4750-83a4-8d103392aaaa",
    "front": "**Def**: A person or thing with a high profile gets attention and is easily noticed (a high-profile job).\n**Farsi**: سرشناس، برجسته، در کانون توجه",
    "back": "high profile",
    "examples": [
      "has quite a high profile."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "47b66e8d-7d40-48eb-9a4b-ffaa571923cd",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who speaks on behalf of a group or an organization.\n**Farsi**: سخنگو",
    "back": "spokesperson",
    "examples": [
      "The mayor is the capital's spokesperson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "61a8f43b-6abe-4b34-8b6f-53d0d246221c",
    "front": "**Def**: help sth to happen or develop.\n**Farsi**: ترویج دادن، ارتقا دادن",
    "back": "promote sth",
    "examples": [
      "promoting economic development."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c5b63085-00f7-4752-9846-e7c769993b4b",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of promoting.\n**Farsi**: ترفیع، ارتقا",
    "back": "promotion N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from promote"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "595c26c6-7874-4443-90e4-0faf9cbd341b",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of money a person or organization has to spend on sth (set a budget = decide a budget).\n**Farsi**: بودجه",
    "back": "budget",
    "examples": [
      "He sets the annual budget"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "76242fe2-8a10-49be-b5d2-d99417f87dc1",
    "front": "**Def**: carefully planned in order to achieve a particular goal.\n**Farsi**: راهبردی، استراتژیک",
    "back": "strategic",
    "examples": [
      "the strategic city-wide government"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dfca40ed-d2e8-433d-a795-81c37142a0f8",
    "front": "**Def**: A plan of action.\n**Farsi**: راهبرد، استراتژی",
    "back": "strategy N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from strategic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "657b0659-d851-4abc-882d-bd15041134ad",
    "front": "**Def**: happening or existing across the whole of a city (also nationwide, worldwide).\n**Farsi**: در سطح شهر، سراسری شهری",
    "back": "city-wide",
    "examples": [
      "the strategic city-wide government"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3c377e2a-52c9-46c9-ad90-00da6d506513",
    "front": "**Def**: Across the whole country.\n**Farsi**: در سطح کشور، سراسری",
    "back": "nationwide",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from city-wide"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "06fddeef-c940-4328-b80d-3a58f61751ff",
    "front": "**Def**: Across the whole world.\n**Farsi**: جهانی",
    "back": "worldwide",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from city-wide"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4a784cc7-bd53-4c43-adf4-0c6c47c35840",
    "front": "**Def**: the activity of keeping order in a place, using the police.\n**Farsi**: نظارت پلیس، اعمال قانون",
    "back": "policing",
    "examples": [
      "provides policing in the capital"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "be5588e3-3507-44e1-b1d4-5b3b7ee95f6c",
    "front": "**Def**: a business or government department that provides a particular service (employment/advertising/travel agency).\n**Farsi**: آژانس، سازمان، نهاد",
    "back": "agency",
    "examples": [
      "He runs an employment agency"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "50cae2a6-77c9-4ed4-9f5b-722c0e9a18a2",
    "front": "**Def**: a system of roads, lines, wires, etc. that are connected to each other (rail/road/underground/network).\n**Farsi**: شبکه",
    "back": "network",
    "examples": [
      "controls the transport network"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f9fc4cfe-dc54-4d04-9137-ace41929e0d3",
    "front": "**Def**: an official who acts as a judge in trials involving minor offences.\n**Farsi**: قاضی صلح، دادیار",
    "back": "magistrate",
    "examples": [
      "issued by a magistrate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e1269d52-e406-49d8-a6da-101cba7a13af",
    "front": "**Def**: be going to do sth very soon.\n**Farsi**: در آستانه (انجام کاری) بودن",
    "back": "be about to (do sth)",
    "examples": [
      "or are about to commit an offence."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0d4d08af-3821-4241-a0c3-6b4e66b25d29",
    "front": "**Def**: warn sb officially that anything they say may be used against them as evidence in court.\n**Farsi**: هشدار رسمی دادن (اخطار پلیس)",
    "back": "caution sb FML",
    "examples": [
      "You are cautioned"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bc8d36cf-7333-4f15-807f-02373634452c",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being in prison while awaiting trial (in custody).\n**Farsi**: بازداشت، توقیف",
    "back": "custody",
    "examples": [
      "Once you are in custody"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "397ba2ef-4d64-4456-8313-73c982f67ae6",
    "front": "**Def**: Held by the police or in prison.\n**Farsi**: در بازداشت",
    "back": "in custody",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from custody"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2cd27435-4094-4088-a30f-aef58b7f4521",
    "front": "**Def**: A person in charge of a meeting or committee.\n**Farsi**: رئیس، گرداننده جلسه",
    "back": "chairperson N (Neutral)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbfc6d3f-68a6-4bca-ab31-9060d458d185",
    "front": "**Def**: A male chairperson.\n**Farsi**: رئیس (مرد)",
    "back": "chairman N (Men only)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "650b2961-ed0e-47e2-be37-21df803e4d89",
    "front": "**Def**: A female chairperson.\n**Farsi**: رئیس (زن)",
    "back": "chairwoman N (Women only)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6150fb7b-4294-405e-b126-ad15a1ac0fca",
    "front": "**Def**: A male spokesperson.\n**Farsi**: سخنگو (مرد)",
    "back": "spokesman N (Men only)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9a4bbff8-51a3-435b-99e4-35b90c2c1f4f",
    "front": "**Def**: A female spokesperson.\n**Farsi**: سخنگو (زن)",
    "back": "spokeswoman N (Women only)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e423d651-f8f4-4507-aed8-6562ebedb9a9",
    "front": "**Def**: A female mayor or the mayor's wife.\n**Farsi**: شهردار زن / همسر شهردار",
    "back": "mayoress N (Women only)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "af6f8a17-5a4b-416e-a2a3-1e59e2105c54",
    "front": "**Def**: the buying and selling of sth illegally. drug-/human-trafficking.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق، معامله غیرقانونی",
    "back": "trafficking",
    "examples": [
      "drug-trafficking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5cfd46b6-84ef-4cae-8b36-58d7977cadbd",
    "front": "**Def**: Illegal trade in drugs.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق مواد مخدر",
    "back": "drug-trafficking",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from trafficking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "199b1b6d-f45e-4b67-a75e-1c9f6c72d6ba",
    "front": "**Def**: Illegal trade in people.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق انسان",
    "back": "human-trafficking",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from trafficking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "70d72c5b-e593-4b99-bc44-ad15a67d9fc0",
    "front": "**Def**: the money you receive when you sell or organize sth.\n**Farsi**: عواید، سود (حاصل از جرم)",
    "back": "proceeds (of sth)",
    "examples": [
      "the illegal proceeds obtained"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "14df617a-bbf9-4568-8ff6-e31690f28d83",
    "front": "**Def**: the crime of moving goods or people illegally into or out of a country.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق (کالا یا انسان)",
    "back": "smuggling",
    "examples": [
      "people-smuggling and human-trafficking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8ace7938-96ef-4b40-8e46-7b4d2afc5ee5",
    "front": "**Def**: To move goods or people illegally.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق کردن",
    "back": "smuggle sth/sb V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from smuggling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "08f478ca-deb1-4c4f-8fe0-7727190b82bf",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat someone unfairly to make money.\n**Farsi**: استثمار کردن، بهره‌کشی کردن",
    "back": "exploit sb V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from exploitation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4d1a304e-47e2-4b12-aa28-46a971bc17e4",
    "front": "**Def**: hard physical work that sb is forced to do.\n**Farsi**: کار اجباری",
    "back": "forced labour",
    "examples": [
      "such as forced labour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1d4fc234-25e7-4602-bbeb-685c7b03400a",
    "front": "**Def**: the crime of obtaining money from sb by tricking them.\n**Farsi**: کلاهبرداری، تقلب",
    "back": "fraud",
    "examples": [
      "fraud committed against individuals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6f415e53-5e57-4a4c-a2bf-b8e3ce7c5cd0",
    "front": "**Def**: To obtain money from someone by deception.\n**Farsi**: کلاهبرداری کردن از",
    "back": "defraud sb V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from fraud"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "74648761-4dbd-4795-9664-9bd5c8b55793",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of criminals working together.\n**Farsi**: باند، دسته تبهکار",
    "back": "gang",
    "examples": [
      "often by organized gangs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fd228d6e-c2d1-4be7-be0e-ba32f5d274b8",
    "front": "**Def**: persuade sb to do sth, usually by offering them sth.\n**Farsi**: وسوسه کردن، فریب دادن",
    "back": "entice sb to do sth",
    "examples": [
      "people are enticed to pay money"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ceac3b26-c62b-43a7-930c-30174dd9da99",
    "front": "**Def**: the crime of making an exact copy of documents or works of art in order to make money by selling them.\n**Farsi**: جعل، سندسازی",
    "back": "forgery",
    "examples": [
      "Other threats include forgery of official documents"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f6974d60-9653-4552-baaf-ee3ca45d40dc",
    "front": "**Def**: To make a fraudulent copy.\n**Farsi**: جعل کردن",
    "back": "forge sth V",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from forgery"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "37883cc5-fb71-4106-9a33-2aa91c36cd47",
    "front": "**Def**: a gun that can be carried.\n**Farsi**: سلاح گرم",
    "back": "firearm FML",
    "examples": [
      "and the use of firearms."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b4d8ae69-adea-4b5f-8dc4-03968007a477",
    "front": "**Def**: keep sb in an official place, e.g. a police station, and prevent them from leaving (be detained in custody).\n**Farsi**: بازداشت کردن، در توقیف نگه داشتن",
    "back": "detain sb",
    "examples": [
      "a police constable lawfully detains someone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c7276609-0363-4873-8c12-856d5879c924",
    "front": "**Def**: a legal document signed by a judge that allows the police to do sth; a judge issues a warrant.\n**Farsi**: حکم (جلب/بازداشت)",
    "back": "warrant",
    "examples": [
      "have a valid arrest warrant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0974a9f0-9134-46a0-acf0-38a8836216c9",
    "front": "**Def**: To release someone upon payment of bail.\n**Farsi**: آزاد کردن با وثیقه",
    "back": "release sb on bail",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from bail"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7971aab3-4eb9-46d9-bc56-d4fa1b766e4a",
    "front": "**Def**: To allow release on bail.\n**Farsi**: وثیقه قبول کردن",
    "back": "grant bail",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from bail"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1950b645-a19c-4eee-9616-54cc94b8386e",
    "front": "**Def**: To deny release on bail.\n**Farsi**: وثیقه نپذیرفتن",
    "back": "refuse bail",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from bail"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "757a6b43-9815-4b26-97af-5452b14594b8",
    "front": "**Def**: an officer of the lowest rank.\n**Farsi**: پاسبان، گروهبان",
    "back": "police constable (PC)",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a59172f-4b09-40dc-b0b8-9ca298a57bc2",
    "front": "**Def**: A police officer above constable.\n**Farsi**: گروهبان",
    "back": "sergeant",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3e89bce8-aa65-4fcc-a4a6-9d6fb162ebc8",
    "front": "**Def**: A police officer above sergeant.\n**Farsi**: بازرس",
    "back": "inspector",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "68b2087e-1079-4dff-8bc3-2f7225a8e7d1",
    "front": "**Def**: the head of each regional police force.\n**Farsi**: فرمانده پلیس (منطقه)",
    "back": "chief constable",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ca2bf4ff-2789-47fc-8a4f-13303bd8e4fd",
    "front": "**Def**: the official ending of a law, system, or institution.\n**Farsi**: لغو رسمی (قانون، سیستم یا نهاد)",
    "back": "abolition",
    "examples": [
      "The abolition of capital punishment."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b2438a77-69a3-4bda-abfd-89296354d100",
    "front": "**Def**: punishment by death.\n**Farsi**: مجازات اعدام",
    "back": "capital punishment",
    "examples": [
      "He faces capital punishment for the crime."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cfdf1c29-d28b-4f1a-bd22-11e94920e080",
    "front": "**Def**: severe punishment for something serious that somebody has done.\n**Farsi**: قصاص، مجازات شدید",
    "back": "retribution",
    "examples": [
      "They are seeking retribution for the attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1d1d7f51-0ab2-4834-803c-b618b430459e",
    "front": "**Def**: to put somebody in prison (syn put sb in prison).\n**Farsi**: زندانی کردن، به حبس انداختن",
    "back": "lock somebody up",
    "examples": [
      "The criminals were locked up for life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b9c4eb60-4e51-4ee2-9b87-39d87fa7f3a4",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of helping people to live a normal life after they have been ill or in prison.\n**Farsi**: توانبخشی، بازپروری",
    "back": "rehabilitation",
    "examples": [
      "The center focuses on drug rehabilitation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42bbd382-78a1-4019-a5e1-eba7f04b9ef1",
    "front": "**Def**: change your behaviour and become a better person.\n**Farsi**: تغییر رویه دادن، متحول شدن",
    "back": "turn over a new leaf",
    "examples": [
      "He promised to turn over a new leaf after his release."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f95ac55f-0c01-4025-b979-6a4830407bc4",
    "front": "**Def**: in a period of great difficulty and uncertainty.\n**Farsi**: در بحران",
    "back": "in crisis",
    "examples": [
      "The system is currently in crisis."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e0ea6779-7392-4967-8f97-9d564c21db45",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) commit a crime again (a person is a reoffender).\n**Farsi**: مرتکب جرم مجدد شدن",
    "back": "reoffend",
    "examples": [
      "Measures are needed to prevent inmates from reoffending."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "88cf9c7a-5775-492b-b2a1-f723252aa00a",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something/somebody in a particular way.\n**Farsi**: چیزی/کسی را به عنوان چیزی تلقی کردن",
    "back": "regard sth/sb as sth",
    "examples": [
      "Many people regard the death penalty as unjust."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8cd18dc-7180-457d-9bf7-01f6cd3d0c7a",
    "front": "**Def**: a risk or danger (= hazard) that is part of a job.\n**Farsi**: خطر شغلی",
    "back": "occupational hazard",
    "examples": [
      "Back injury is an occupational hazard for nurses."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8acbc745-f9b7-4a46-8d3b-cecddcb6e670",
    "front": "**Def**: take action to punish somebody because they made you suffer.\n**Farsi**: انتقام گرفتن",
    "back": "take revenge",
    "examples": [
      "He swore he would take revenge on his attackers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "182a2fac-0063-415c-bb55-cd281016611d",
    "front": "**Def**: show that something is right or fair.\n**Farsi**: توجیه کردن، حق دادن",
    "back": "justify sth",
    "examples": [
      "Can you justify the prison system?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa7e19d4-d2b4-43bc-82ed-bdc1703a5efb",
    "front": "**Def**: only, and with nothing else (e.g. We rely exclusively on rail.).\n**Farsi**: منحصراً، فقط",
    "back": "exclusively",
    "examples": [
      "The club is exclusively for men."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3ce619be-ca17-413e-95cd-14baac21793b",
    "front": "**Def**: treatment of a physical or mental problem or illness.\n**Farsi**: درمان، معالجه",
    "back": "therapy",
    "examples": [
      "She is receiving group therapy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9eff5106-4420-4b2e-a12d-fe024aa5f142",
    "front": "**Def**: a person living in a prison.\n**Farsi**: زندانی، محبوس",
    "back": "inmate",
    "examples": [
      "The inmates are serving long sentences."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c51e58f3-19c8-4f25-b007-9f6944de45b0",
    "front": "**Def**: a part or share of the whole amount or number.\n**Farsi**: نسبت، سهم",
    "back": "proportion",
    "examples": [
      "A large proportion of the budget is spent on defense."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "11c63e1d-3a0f-44e3-8ef7-e48944f54419",
    "front": "**Def**: be different from what is normal.\n**Farsi**: منحرف شدن از",
    "back": "deviate from sth",
    "examples": [
      "The plane had to deviate from the normal route."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f04156d7-21cb-497b-a687-a375295cae29",
    "front": "**Def**: the policy of separating people of different sex, race, religion, etc.\n**Farsi**: جداسازی، تفکیک",
    "back": "segregation",
    "examples": [
      "Racial segregation was common in the past."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7f64062f-c904-42c9-8323-fb236c460e8c",
    "front": "**Def**: keep somebody/something within an enclosed area.\n**Farsi**: محدود کردن، محصور کردن",
    "back": "confine sb/sth in sth",
    "examples": [
      "The men were both confined in a small cell."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a53db910-e93b-455a-b8aa-d6978dedbccc",
    "front": "**Def**: a lockable room for prisoners in a prison or police station.\n**Farsi**: سلول (زندان)",
    "back": "cell",
    "examples": [
      "He spent two weeks in a tiny cell."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "02dedf3d-c6b1-4d99-ae0c-02c45a3d324e",
    "front": "**Def**: agreement about something.\n**Farsi**: رضایت، توافق",
    "back": "consent",
    "examples": [
      "The club required parental consent."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3338bac3-b2bd-4e7b-a43f-0bbb69a2318e",
    "front": "**Def**: when you judge your own progress and achievements.\n**Farsi**: خودارزیابی",
    "back": "self-assessment",
    "examples": [
      "Self-assessment is crucial for personal development."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "482f5f9e-05d0-424f-aa35-3bdd7aa96a7c",
    "front": "**Def**: a country's army, navy, and air force (syn the armed forces).\n**Farsi**: نیروهای مسلح، نظامیان",
    "back": "the military",
    "examples": [
      "He spent twenty years in the military."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "34350f69-8c77-4c06-86d2-fe616ecee3b0",
    "front": "**Def**: a part of a large organization (e.g. branch of a bank).\n**Farsi**: شاخه، بخش",
    "back": "branch",
    "examples": [
      "The military has several branches, including the navy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bc42ffee-48d3-4fb7-96bc-fe2f3c01b2ce",
    "front": "**Def**: a planned military or police action (military operation).\n**Farsi**: عملیات، مأموریت",
    "back": "operation",
    "examples": [
      "The unit was involved in a complex operation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ef70d736-5ec7-4f8d-8be4-ad1c79fa78bc",
    "front": "**Def**: a person or group of people who protect something/somebody.\n**Farsi**: نگهبان، محافظت کردن",
    "back": "guard",
    "examples": [
      "Soldiers guard the entrance to the base."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2d59c2c9-7eac-4b4a-9469-0993adb5f590",
    "front": "**Def**: not belonging to the armed forces.\n**Farsi**: غیرنظامی",
    "back": "civilian",
    "examples": [
      "He was a civilian working for the army."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8026b69f-f19c-4dba-982b-2b2162add035",
    "front": "**Def**: the power to give orders to other people.\n**Farsi**: اقتدار، صلاحیت",
    "back": "authority",
    "examples": [
      "The general holds great authority."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "af98a8f6-c30b-449f-8380-c7ebadf56d50",
    "front": "**Def**: an extra force that performs part-time duties and is available if needed.\n**Farsi**: نیروی ذخیره",
    "back": "the reserve(s)",
    "examples": [
      "He joined the army reserves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "64a5f9e8-9836-43ac-bc37-5fe2dfc66626",
    "front": "**Def**: recognize a difference between people or things (syn differentiate).\n**Farsi**: تمایز قائل شدن بین",
    "back": "distinguish between",
    "examples": [
      "It's important to distinguish between the two terms."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ab8bf35f-4bf6-4dfa-aa20-986acd22a009",
    "front": "**Def**: central, and forming the necessary basis of something.\n**Farsi**: بنیادی، اساسی",
    "back": "fundamental",
    "examples": [
      "Belief in democracy is fundamental."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "254af1a6-0a07-4115-974e-3c71e322a428",
    "front": "**Def**: fighting between forces (armed/unarmed combat).\n**Farsi**: رزم، مبارزه",
    "back": "combat",
    "examples": [
      "He saw active combat during the war."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "03b83fd2-cc6a-462b-a68f-417356cb105f",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely large (syn huge).\n**Farsi**: بسیار بزرگ، گسترده",
    "back": "vast",
    "examples": [
      "A vast majority of people agreed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "83089ced-ac69-424a-ab9b-b3504aada8b7",
    "front": "**Def**: include something within an area or area of activity.\n**Farsi**: شامل شدن، دربرگرفتن",
    "back": "encompass sth",
    "examples": [
      "The area encompasses diverse ecosystems."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a99a8a8d-0e3e-44b3-8b0b-91b172f194c9",
    "front": "**Def**: (in the forces) be in charge of people (a person is in command).\n**Farsi**: فرماندهی کردن",
    "back": "command sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "She commands a unit of 5,000 soldiers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "83df352d-03ed-42c4-94c3-1c77c3141a6e",
    "front": "**Def**: a structure which produces nuclear energy.\n**Farsi**: راکتور هسته‌ای",
    "back": "nuclear reactor",
    "examples": [
      "The country has several nuclear reactors."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e5b72bb7-fb37-4c7e-8f07-df93c4eb80bb",
    "front": "**Def**: an object such as a knife, gun, or bomb that is used for fighting.\n**Farsi**: سلاح",
    "back": "weapon",
    "examples": [
      "A rifle is a deadly weapon."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "07f26ef5-0f4b-473b-8006-cca7f0c0e98d",
    "front": "**Def**: comprise, compose (used to describe what something is formed of).\n**Farsi**: تشکیل دادن، شامل شدن",
    "back": "make up",
    "examples": [
      "The brigade is made up of 5,500 men."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3e4977f3-1af0-432d-a2be-9ba048caf3ed",
    "front": "**Def**: (formal) help somebody to do something.\n**Farsi**: کمک کردن، یاری رساندن",
    "back": "assist (sb) in/with sth",
    "examples": [
      "He simply wanted to assist them with their problems."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3f4aed11-cc5a-4fff-a757-65b2bf7579f1",
    "front": "**Def**: intending to stop people fighting (a peacekeeping force).\n**Farsi**: صلح‌بانی",
    "back": "peacekeeping",
    "examples": [
      "The troops were sent on a peacekeeping mission."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9e0f0cf2-4d0b-43d3-96e4-22499eb5ba5e",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with the people who live in a country (civil unrest/war/rights).\n**Farsi**: مدنی، غیرنظامی",
    "back": "civil",
    "examples": [
      "The nation avoided a full-scale civil war."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fde58945-1cfc-4d32-a2aa-aef468757b9c",
    "front": "**Def**: much; a great deal.\n**Farsi**: به میزان قابل توجهی",
    "back": "considerably",
    "examples": [
      "The price is considerably lower now."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c84a00cd-b001-4be5-9b47-82289268bb3b",
    "front": "**Def**: money provided for a special purpose (government funding).\n**Farsi**: تأمین مالی، بودجه",
    "back": "funding",
    "examples": [
      "The project requires external funding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e31576ae-37e7-48ff-851a-555f283c3eb5",
    "front": "**Def**: the second of two things that have just been mentioned.\n**Farsi**: دومی، مورد دوم",
    "back": "the latter",
    "examples": [
      "Of the two options, I prefer the latter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "468e1188-5d92-4abd-af03-53176309f7fe",
    "front": "**Def**: prepare an army to fight in a war.\n**Farsi**: بسیج کردن",
    "back": "mobilize (sth)",
    "examples": [
      "They’re mobilizing the army."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a491260b-1825-4a27-bc0a-923de3e7f4c9",
    "front": "**Def**: having the opposite effect to the one intended.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه معکوس",
    "back": "counter-productive",
    "examples": [
      "That policy proved to be counter-productive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "68b0ddc3-08d2-4a4e-8640-f8efeba4b7b1",
    "front": "**Def**: only; simply (used to emphasize what you are saying).\n**Farsi**: صرفاً، فقط",
    "back": "merely",
    "examples": [
      "It was merely an oversight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ccca0c-8541-46e5-87d8-4487f247b54e",
    "front": "**Def**: the activity of fighting a war, often of a particular type (guerrilla warfare).\n**Farsi**: جنگ، رزم",
    "back": "warfare",
    "examples": [
      "They specialize in counter-insurgency warfare."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40d9d785-a485-4c85-95f5-555eee7d32d7",
    "front": "**Def**: a subject under discussion.\n**Farsi**: مسئله، موضوع",
    "back": "issue",
    "examples": [
      "The main issue is funding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0ed37482-2726-46fe-bd01-8acc7a0e2fe9",
    "front": "**Def**: place someone on bail or in custody.\n**Farsi**: بازداشت موقت کردن، تحت نظر قرار دادن",
    "back": "remand someone",
    "examples": [
      "The court decided to remand the suspect."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1b01ba64-07cf-4d3f-b2d1-9dbfe50002f0",
    "front": "**Def**: give a warning.\n**Farsi**: هشدار، اخطار دادن",
    "back": "caution",
    "examples": [
      "The police cautioned the driver."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2ffcd113-08cc-47d1-b909-b76fddf25bcb",
    "front": "**Def**: make full use of and benefit from (a resource).\n**Farsi**: بهره‌برداری کردن",
    "back": "exploit",
    "examples": [
      "He exploited the workers for profit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c90b070e-86ff-41f3-a6b7-dabbf7fc9fc1",
    "front": "**Def**: make a copy of (a document, etc.) illegally.\n**Farsi**: جعل کردن",
    "back": "forge",
    "examples": [
      "She forged someone's passport."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0584d680-4725-4a24-a913-708b21097409",
    "front": "**Def**: keep someone in official custody.\n**Farsi**: بازداشت کردن",
    "back": "detain someone",
    "examples": [
      "Police detained him for questioning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ac8075c4-9302-40ee-9886-8d70f0157b24",
    "front": "**Def**: fake, copied illegally.\n**Farsi**: تقلبی، جعلی",
    "back": "counterfeit",
    "examples": [
      "The market was selling counterfeit goods."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "08bbb16b-3b67-44ec-ad84-4c6388c11d4e",
    "front": "**Def**: theft or misappropriation of funds.\n**Farsi**: اختلاس",
    "back": "embezzlement",
    "examples": [
      "He was arrested for embezzlement."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "087c9d02-d2e8-4c00-b3a0-39d75c637c4f",
    "front": "**Def**: the practice of spying.\n**Farsi**: جاسوسی",
    "back": "espionage",
    "examples": [
      "She was charged with industrial espionage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5886bb0c-a786-4af1-8abc-0967c07c2920",
    "front": "**Def**: escaping or fleeing (from police/justice).\n**Farsi**: در حال فرار",
    "back": "on the run",
    "examples": [
      "The suspect has been on the run for two weeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9a676dbc-ab8a-46e5-82ed-35bc890d4928",
    "front": "**Def**: a secret investigation by agents pretending to be ordinary citizens.\n**Farsi**: عملیات مخفی",
    "back": "undercover operation",
    "examples": [
      "The police launched an undercover operation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d23c548a-4bdc-4783-8444-daed57d803d0",
    "front": "**Def**: to imprison or confine.\n**Farsi**: زندانی کردن",
    "back": "incarcerate",
    "examples": [
      "We believe that incarcerating these offenders will act as a deterrence."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c2907ab8-26d7-4032-8100-eb091fec5dfe",
    "front": "**Def**: release of an offender from detention, subject to a period of good behaviour.\n**Farsi**: آزادی مشروط",
    "back": "probation",
    "examples": [
      "He was released on probation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "23af21d6-95fc-415a-8045-90540be8279d",
    "front": "**Def**: isolation from others in a small room.\n**Farsi**: حبس انفرادی",
    "back": "solitary confinement",
    "examples": [
      "The prisoner was sentenced to solitary confinement."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2ba5e29a-2b0e-4d71-b82a-c14a0e1ed07e",
    "front": "**Def**: a sentence requiring the offender to be held in custody (prison sentence).\n**Farsi**: حکم زندان",
    "back": "custodial sentence",
    "examples": [
      "He received a short custodial sentence."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5925905e-6963-41aa-a01c-0eff79bd08ef",
    "front": "**Def**: a sentence that is not enforced immediately, but only if the offender commits another crime.\n**Farsi**: حکم تعلیقی",
    "back": "suspended sentence",
    "examples": [
      "He was given a suspended sentence of six months."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "08203366-190c-4950-9cff-2a586f9a1ddd",
    "front": "**Def**: a prison guard.\n**Farsi**: زندانبان",
    "back": "warder",
    "examples": [
      "The warder checked the cells."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d710e1b6-a534-48be-b173-205f7f6a56c7",
    "front": "**Def**: an urgent and emotional request.\n**Farsi**: درخواست عاجزانه",
    "back": "plea",
    "examples": [
      "Mother’s plea to kidnappers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "286524f6-a97f-4560-a4e4-d4f8ce3325f0",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of taking someone illegally.\n**Farsi**: آدم‌ربایی",
    "back": "kidnapping",
    "examples": [
      "The kidnapping shocked the city."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "075f697a-2413-4981-9ae1-0bd306b8c78d",
    "front": "**Def**: a difficult or unpleasant experience.\n**Farsi**: سختی، محنت، تجربه ناخوشایند",
    "back": "ordeal",
    "examples": [
      "Ten-hour ordeal for tourists."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "99b3d635-9554-4abc-9d97-7a00840a016f",
    "front": "**Def**: the US legislative body (or similar bodies in other countries).\n**Farsi**: سنا (مجلس علیای قانونگذاری)",
    "back": "Senate",
    "examples": [
      "The Senate urges caution."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d657f752-877f-4a31-ae84-e145e0744aad",
    "front": "**Def**: strongly recommend or encourage.\n**Farsi**: اصرار کردن، ترغیب کردن",
    "back": "urge",
    "examples": [
      "The senator urged caution."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "748371e8-5354-4e41-bfb2-776cea688a2a",
    "front": "**Def**: an attempt to do something.\n**Farsi**: تلاش، کوشش",
    "back": "bid (to do sth)",
    "examples": [
      "A bid to oust rail chief."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf0495da-331e-4bbb-ab99-4c88423f0dde",
    "front": "**Def**: to force somebody out of a job or position.\n**Farsi**: بیرون راندن، برکنار کردن",
    "back": "oust",
    "examples": [
      "They bid to oust the chief executive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "17be0d00-7738-4a04-aea1-1eb00c3541e4",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that helps or encourages something.\n**Farsi**: تقویت، افزایش دادن",
    "back": "boost",
    "examples": [
      "A boost for voters."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d24d253b-2196-4df3-863e-3bd18e5b464c",
    "front": "**Def**: formal permission to do something.\n**Farsi**: مجوز، چراغ سبز",
    "back": "Go-ahead (for scheme)",
    "examples": [
      "They received the go-ahead for the scheme."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42f8293f-b081-4561-9500-0d79cbb6f161",
    "front": "**Def**: stop happening or existing.\n**Farsi**: متوقف کردن",
    "back": "cease",
    "examples": [
      "The company may cease trading."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "26528398-4be7-42ee-842d-6c7e67c31f37",
    "front": "**Def**: to limit or control something.\n**Farsi**: مهار کردن، کنترل کردن",
    "back": "curb",
    "examples": [
      "Measures to curb inflation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "edb3531c-7dcc-42f1-88aa-fa6789294e5a",
    "front": "**Def**: a problem that is difficult to solve.\n**Farsi**: معما",
    "back": "riddle",
    "examples": [
      "The death riddle remains unsolved."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "db84f0c1-e2ba-4f73-bf40-e96255bd03d4",
    "front": "**Def**: reached a point where it is about to happen (often something very bad).\n**Farsi**: در آستانه، در مرز",
    "back": "on brink of",
    "examples": [
      "Talks on the brink of collapse."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ae6451fa-d74c-406f-b21c-32627237d546",
    "front": "**Def**: to reject the possibility of something.\n**Farsi**: رد کردن امکان چیزی",
    "back": "rule out",
    "examples": [
      "The PM rules out a referendum."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f24221e5-1f71-4443-aeff-1d0c315874b3",
    "front": "**Def**: jewellery (or precious stones).\n**Farsi**: جواهرات، سنگ‌های قیمتی",
    "back": "gems",
    "examples": [
      "Valuable gems stolen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "392b178b-2119-4937-a84f-e3b9d609bc51",
    "front": "**Def**: a statement, without proof, that somebody has done something wrong.\n**Farsi**: ادعا، اتهام (بی‌اساس)",
    "back": "allegation",
    "examples": [
      "Amid further allegations of a cover-up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "90f419d4-bc86-45f9-b5d8-4f6b07647783",
    "front": "**Def**: an attempt to stop people discovering the truth about something.\n**Farsi**: لاپوشانی",
    "back": "cover-up",
    "examples": [
      "The scandal involved a major cover-up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "741e6630-9057-46f6-8684-314aba2d91e8",
    "front": "**Def**: one of the people who provides information, especially for journalists.\n**Farsi**: منبع (اطلاعات)",
    "back": "source",
    "examples": [
      "According to reliable sources."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a08cf49a-e8b6-4003-829d-4cc3565553d3",
    "front": "**Def**: a small mistake caused by forgetting something or carelessness.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه، غفلت",
    "back": "lapse",
    "examples": [
      "A serious lapse in security."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4b57ce83-8103-4d93-a3f9-2df6e181cb9a",
    "front": "**Def**: causing a lot of discussion and disagreement.\n**Farsi**: بحث‌برانگیز، جنجالی",
    "back": "controversial",
    "examples": [
      "New measures concerning controversial issues."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f90d54fa-0261-48bc-aed4-420d1bce2e91",
    "front": "**Def**: an official action taken in order to achieve something.\n**Farsi**: اقدام، تدبیر",
    "back": "measure",
    "examples": [
      "The government is taking strong measures."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3becda44-1e91-4302-b93d-bdd49ed6a633",
    "front": "**Def**: used for saying where the facts or information have come from.\n**Farsi**: طبق گفته، بر اساس",
    "back": "according to",
    "examples": [
      "According to official figures, inflation is rising."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0562be5-d797-4c2a-af1d-8927c8376e41",
    "front": "**Def**: a process of asking people for their opinion about something.\n**Farsi**: نظرسنجی",
    "back": "opinion poll",
    "examples": [
      "A recent opinion poll shows strong support."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ffc38d54-ea84-4d5b-8287-02806d84d95e",
    "front": "**Def**: (of facts, information, etc.) become known.\n**Farsi**: آشکار شدن، پدیدار شدن",
    "back": "emerge",
    "examples": [
      "More details will emerge over the coming weeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2f8268ea-4ee4-4f9b-a589-f8d9edd02f5f",
    "front": "**Def**: strongly critical (scathing attack/remark).\n**Farsi**: کوبنده، به شدت انتقادی",
    "back": "scathing",
    "examples": [
      "The report contained scathing remarks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd19267f-501a-4fe7-88fc-38a2cd2a9d27",
    "front": "**Def**: give secret information to journalists or the public.\n**Farsi**: درز دادن اطلاعات",
    "back": "leak sth to sb",
    "examples": [
      "Officials leaked the report to the press."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9abae4bf-4ef3-4d59-95ed-d03785dbb9c6",
    "front": "**Def**: repeat the exact words that somebody said.\n**Farsi**: نقل قول کردن",
    "back": "quote sb",
    "examples": [
      "The newspaper quoted a senior doctor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cc960258-89a8-467e-81f9-b24aa26c3cca",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which a large number of people express strong feelings against something.\n**Farsi**: طوفان اعتراض",
    "back": "storm of protest",
    "examples": [
      "There is a storm of protest over the new legislation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3e96d668-83e4-4919-a575-7acb8980a60a",
    "front": "**Def**: the situation and public opinion are changing.\n**Farsi**: ورق برگشتن، تغییر جهت جریان (افکار عمومی)",
    "back": "the tide is now turning",
    "examples": [
      "The tide is turning against the government."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b887318a-0395-4b02-a654-c2f1ff2244b8",
    "front": "**Def**: cause something to start or develop.\n**Farsi**: جرقه‌زدن، آغاز کردن",
    "back": "spark further trouble",
    "examples": [
      "The police fear the arrest of the two youths could spark further trouble."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f0faf51d-abd7-4029-8a62-0ad39330d20d",
    "front": "**Def**: a very angry argument.\n**Farsi**: نزاع آتشین، مشاجره شدید",
    "back": "a blazing row",
    "examples": [
      "The ministers had a blazing row."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d186a41f-7d68-45a6-8f9a-151904c1f10a",
    "front": "**Def**: been strongly criticized.\n**Farsi**: مورد حمله قرار گرفتن (انتقاد)",
    "back": "come under attack",
    "examples": [
      "The headteacher has come under attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0548ad39-2d58-487b-bde3-fae9978caa8d",
    "front": "**Def**: in a position in which people can criticize and blame you.\n**Farsi**: در خط آتش (در معرض انتقاد و سرزنش)",
    "back": "in the firing line",
    "examples": [
      "The Board of Directors could be next in the firing line."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "88565cc2-40ae-4e88-806b-f8ccb8487dc5",
    "front": "**Def**: a difficult situation.\n**Farsi**: در گوشه سخت گیر افتادن، در مخمصه قرار گرفتن",
    "back": "get himself into a tight corner",
    "examples": [
      "The minister has got himself into a tight corner."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d36075fb-8c2e-4aa7-ad8b-75df7b3c1d1e",
    "front": "**Def**: behaviour that is unfair or dishonest.\n**Farsi**: تقلب، تخلف، بازی کثیف",
    "back": "foul play",
    "examples": [
      "There have been accusations of foul play."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a9765ee1-d387-4da6-ba25-f41c186046d5",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which everyone has the same opportunities.\n**Farsi**: زمین بازی برابر (فرصت‌های برابر)",
    "back": "a level playing field",
    "examples": [
      "We just want a level playing field."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "782daa00-643d-49f3-83a6-3aecd5fccf1e",
    "front": "**Def**: write down details of an arrangement which you may have to change later.\n**Farsi**: به طور موقت یادداشت کردن",
    "back": "pencil sth in",
    "examples": [
      "I'll pencil in a meeting for next week."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "22596f95-3e95-40ce-b50a-235dabec3e3e",
    "front": "**Def**: a warning.\n**Farsi**: هشدار",
    "back": "alert",
    "examples": [
      "A new flood alert was issued."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1b5cba12-ce33-4704-95c7-c3a4de84f66d",
    "front": "**Def**: happening after or as a result of another event.\n**Farsi**: متعاقب، در پی آمده",
    "back": "ensuing",
    "examples": [
      "The ensuing panic was widespread."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c96ef558-4ab3-472f-b66b-0f72ec1e94f6",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially of a disease) lasting a long time and hard to cure.\n**Farsi**: مزمن",
    "back": "chronic",
    "examples": [
      "She has chronic headaches."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9ace002d-153c-4355-8bb7-cf8632f3673f",
    "front": "**Def**: still existing or needing to be dealt with.\n**Farsi**: باقی مانده",
    "back": "remaining",
    "examples": [
      "The remaining tasks are simple."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8ea90afb-ed10-4a42-9dc9-ced76c675940",
    "front": "**Def**: get well again quickly after an illness or accident.\n**Farsi**: بهبود سریع یافتن",
    "back": "make a speedy/rapid recovery",
    "examples": [
      "He seems to be making a speedy recovery."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de80872a-d369-4433-92c6-b8932ba9091c",
    "front": "**Def**: to be brave enough to do something.\n**Farsi**: جرأت داشتن، جسارت کردن",
    "back": "dare (to)",
    "examples": [
      "He didn't dare leave the room."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c59cad6-da45-443d-ad79-55d767f92029",
    "front": "**Def**: stay somewhere that protects you from danger or bad weather.\n**Farsi**: پناه گرفتن، سرپناه",
    "back": "shelter",
    "examples": [
      "They found somewhere to shelter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d8d06dff-b211-422f-9f6a-be329421f258",
    "front": "**Def**: full of very many insects, animals, etc. (rat-infested, shark-infested).\n**Farsi**: مملو (از حشرات یا حیوانات مضر)",
    "back": "infested",
    "examples": [
      "The area was snake-infested swamp."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1c2ec765-0963-477c-b44f-015c80739e9f",
    "front": "**Def**: an area in which the ground is very wet or covered in water.\n**Farsi**: باتلاق",
    "back": "swamp",
    "examples": [
      "They were found sheltering up a tree above a crocodile-infested swamp."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4ca0c1f0-4e59-4592-b9ec-15f1b567e245",
    "front": "**Def**: begin to deal with a situation.\n**Farsi**: اقدام کردن",
    "back": "take action",
    "examples": [
      "The authorities must take action immediately."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd3dddd8-9158-4a7b-95f6-33ade4b3850c",
    "front": "**Def**: extreme in a way that has a sudden, violent, or serious effect.\n**Farsi**: شدید، جدی",
    "back": "drastic",
    "examples": [
      "We took drastic action to prevent losses."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5e462ca7-405f-4a4b-bc39-5665881e493a",
    "front": "**Def**: move away from where you should be, without intending to.\n**Farsi**: سرگردان، گم شدن",
    "back": "stray",
    "examples": [
      "The stray dog wandered into the yard."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2634031e-00b9-4281-a4f8-ae739626b07e",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to think clearly because of shock or a blow to the head.\n**Farsi**: گیج، منگ",
    "back": "dazed",
    "examples": [
      "He was still dazed after the accident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "db248cff-51a6-4af1-8779-48fb484d2872",
    "front": "**Def**: confused about where you are or which way to go.\n**Farsi**: سردرگم، جهت گم کرده",
    "back": "disorientated",
    "examples": [
      "I felt completely disorientated in the dark."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a7403498-8872-4214-a528-875c3abc1fb7",
    "front": "**Def**: think clearly again after a period of confusion.\n**Farsi**: به خود آمدن، هوشیاری خود را بازیافتن",
    "back": "regain your senses",
    "examples": [
      "He struggled to regain his senses."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "df3145d2-1518-4c2f-ade8-34662aa8bbb7",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) stay where you are rather than moving away.\n**Farsi**: ثابت ماندن، تکان نخوردن",
    "back": "stay put",
    "examples": [
      "I was told to stay put until help arrived."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "51ad42ac-ef45-46ec-b47f-a514930660f4",
    "front": "**Def**: decide to do something, even though it involves risk.\n**Farsi**: ریسک کردن، شانس خود را امتحان کردن",
    "back": "take a chance on sth",
    "examples": [
      "We took a chance on the lottery."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0099fd8e-7116-46c7-8b51-8eecefcb7590",
    "front": "**Def**: very difficult and tiring; needing great effort (syn punishing).\n**Farsi**: طاقت‌فرسا، بسیار سخت",
    "back": "gruelling",
    "examples": [
      "It was a gruelling experience."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c8b0f2f5-d54a-413c-a13e-ed3bba1617d7",
    "front": "**Def**: a famous person (syns personality, celeb INF).\n**Farsi**: سلبریتی، فرد مشهور",
    "back": "celebrity",
    "examples": [
      "She is a major television celebrity."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4fd4a2db-5f31-4907-bce3-8a1096104f6e",
    "front": "**Def**: it is right that you should have something.\n**Farsi**: شایسته بودن، سزاوار بودن",
    "back": "deserve sth",
    "examples": [
      "Do you agree that celebrities deserve privacy?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "79d1de22-b4dd-4c93-84ea-3947925161e4",
    "front": "**Def**: an investigation into the opinions or behaviour of a large group of people.\n**Farsi**: نظرسنجی، بررسی",
    "back": "survey",
    "examples": [
      "They conducted a survey about political views."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "85dd02cc-457b-4471-ab5a-851afe8725ed",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being alone and not watched or disturbed by others.\n**Farsi**: حریم خصوصی",
    "back": "privacy",
    "examples": [
      "Everyone has a right to privacy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0e289179-995d-44d8-b355-6a13a56e9ce9",
    "front": "**Def**: the reporting of news in the press.\n**Farsi**: پوشش خبری",
    "back": "coverage",
    "examples": [
      "The media coverage was extensive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3f10c759-29c4-4394-ba1d-0a2c6bdb0066",
    "front": "**Def**: well known to many people through TV or the press.\n**Farsi**: در معرض دید عموم، مشهور",
    "back": "in the public eye",
    "examples": [
      "She has been in the public eye for years."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a103a6a-a18c-454b-9c00-0f08a7337739",
    "front": "**Def**: information learned as the result of research.\n**Farsi**: یافته‌ها، نتایج",
    "back": "findings",
    "examples": [
      "The survey findings were surprising."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b314a65c-b805-437f-b511-90cfe13e7b9a",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that comes into somebody's life in a negative way.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز، مزاحمت",
    "back": "intrusion (into sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Prying into private lives is an intrusion."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7989e465-3412-4120-93c4-82d64fef394f",
    "front": "**Def**: a newspaper that gives emphasis to stories about famous people (less serious).\n**Farsi**: روزنامه زرد",
    "back": "tabloid",
    "examples": [
      "Tabloids often feature celebrity gossip."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "69705f88-50c8-4698-8feb-d1e1c3236a5e",
    "front": "**Def**: choose somebody/something from a group for special attention.\n**Farsi**: جدا کردن، متمایز کردن",
    "back": "single sb/sth out",
    "examples": [
      "She was singled out for special praise."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "78d1d223-f59d-4235-8de9-e380540460b0",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely painful (excruciating pain/headaches).\n**Farsi**: طاقت‌فرسا، درد شدید",
    "back": "excruciating",
    "examples": [
      "She was suffering from excruciating pain."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f2b55ef4-4b5f-4383-83d2-249763198372",
    "front": "**Def**: a man and woman who have not been married long.\n**Farsi**: تازه عروس و داماد",
    "back": "newlyweds",
    "examples": [
      "The newlyweds are going on honeymoon."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4aa1cec4-d4be-4e40-b03d-f47b795d6b64",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) in difficulties and likely to fail (usually about a relationship).\n**Farsi**: در آستانه شکست، در خطر",
    "back": "on the rocks",
    "examples": [
      "Their marriage is on the rocks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "672d24e0-ac4f-4eec-8085-d7baf4b9922a",
    "front": "**Def**: a story or piece of information that may or may not be true.\n**Farsi**: شایعه",
    "back": "rumour",
    "examples": [
      "I heard a rumour that the minister is about to resign."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7b4da023-9392-4455-be88-bc1df3ed7bbe",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) end a romantic relationship with somebody.\n**Farsi**: ترک کردن (رابطه)",
    "back": "dump sb",
    "examples": [
      "She dumped him after the fight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "477ea3eb-9a4f-4af4-a6a4-d57d40e47924",
    "front": "**Def**: produce a baby or young animal.\n**Farsi**: زایمان کردن، به دنیا آوردن",
    "back": "give birth",
    "examples": [
      "Amelia had a baby boy last week; she gave birth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8c9b0083-62b0-44e5-a548-17a4dc0c38e7",
    "front": "**Def**: used to describe somebody who is in the same situation as you (fellow students/workers).\n**Farsi**: همکار، همتا، همراه‌",
    "back": "fellow",
    "examples": [
      "He is a student in my class, a fellow student."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dc207e43-40b8-42f1-9e94-dd54f9d63c9c",
    "front": "**Def**: come together to help or support somebody/something.\n**Farsi**: بسیج شدن، گرد هم آمدن (برای کمک)",
    "back": "rally (round/to sb/sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The public rallied to the politician's defense."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9602a176-8b74-4052-905e-772d14de0974",
    "front": "**Def**: support and agree with something/somebody (also be in favour of sth/sb).\n**Farsi**: طرفدار بودن، موافق بودن",
    "back": "favour with sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "She is in favour of it, but her parents oppose it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b97438e9-2b80-40df-83d8-62770b8b1f7a",
    "front": "**Def**: the existing situation (maintain the status quo).\n**Farsi**: وضعیت موجود",
    "back": "status quo",
    "examples": [
      "The Conservative party tends to favour the status quo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "73775869-e7bd-47b1-98df-3c8b1257d583",
    "front": "**Def**: disagreeing strongly with something/somebody.\n**Farsi**: مخالف با",
    "back": "opposed to sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "They are opposed to the proposed changes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "00f860af-f115-47fd-89f4-85f98dd9296b",
    "front": "**Def**: complete and fundamental (often implying major change).\n**Farsi**: رادیکال، بنیادی",
    "back": "radical",
    "examples": [
      "He has extreme views, but his are radical."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eb1185a5-7172-464c-9c94-7cfeb081846b",
    "front": "**Def**: share something among a number of people.\n**Farsi**: توزیع کردن",
    "back": "distribute sth",
    "examples": [
      "Wealth should be distributed equally."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c75374e9-6b86-4bb9-ac6d-dc727c230d38",
    "front": "**Def**: in a way that is fair and the same for everyone.\n**Farsi**: به طور مساوی، عادلانه",
    "back": "equally",
    "examples": [
      "Wealth should be distributed equally."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "10ddb96c-505c-4cf6-a87d-83eb7b3be71e",
    "front": "**Def**: a political party that is not left-wing or right-wing (in the centre).\n**Farsi**: حزب میانه",
    "back": "centre party",
    "examples": [
      "I don't think the director is closely associated with any political party, they are a centre party."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eeba3dca-398e-40a7-b616-f3fac2d57cce",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of doing or achieving something (means of transport/communication).\n**Farsi**: ابزار، وسیله",
    "back": "means",
    "examples": [
      "We lack the means of escape."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "07d4abab-88bc-4bb3-a50c-7f81d9946158",
    "front": "**Def**: the materials and equipment needed to produce things.\n**Farsi**: ابزارهای تولید",
    "back": "means of production",
    "examples": [
      "Socialists believe that everyone should own the means of production."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a4380f29-6020-467a-adff-73f9b2a22938",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of showing who you are.\n**Farsi**: شناسایی، مدرک هویت",
    "back": "identification",
    "examples": [
      "He showed his identification to the guard."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1738a118-f7a1-4a21-90c7-159ef1d61bbe",
    "front": "**Def**: a weakness in an idea, a system, or an organization.\n**Farsi**: ترک برداشتن (نشانه ضعف)",
    "back": "crack a line on the surface of sth",
    "examples": [
      "The first cracks are appearing in the government."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1c168a63-cc30-472c-90a8-1072daf84c71",
    "front": "**Def**: be in control of a situation (syn pull the strings).\n**Farsi**: در جایگاه هدایت، کنترل را در دست داشتن",
    "back": "driving seat",
    "examples": [
      "She is in the driving seat now."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d661f156-5702-4b65-83dd-663880bca15b",
    "front": "**Def**: cause problems by making changes to a situation that is satisfactory as it is.\n**Farsi**: جنجال به پا کردن، وضعیت آرام را به هم زدن",
    "back": "rock the boat",
    "examples": [
      "The PM doesn't want MPs to rock the boat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aa3e4efc-f704-4716-9353-824763485edf",
    "front": "**Def**: create the basic ideas or principles from which something can then develop.\n**Farsi**: زیربنا نهادن، اصول اساسی را ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "foundations (lay the foundations)",
    "examples": [
      "They laid the foundations of the party's success."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8286d8dd-1f16-4a87-8605-a1778e02faeb",
    "front": "**Def**: be in a situation that is too difficult for you to control.\n**Farsi**: از عهده برنیامدن، خارج از عمق توانایی",
    "back": "depth (of sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The minister is out of her depth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "29d8cc93-2a04-477f-b1e6-9dc6b32c1e98",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) upset somebody/something.\n**Farsi**: تکان دادن، ناراحت کردن",
    "back": "rock sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "The scandal rocked the government."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "80a1ceeb-a510-43f3-a783-d7119d55c7f1",
    "front": "**Def**: an angry discussion (also heated discussion).\n**Farsi**: داغ کردن بحث، بحث عصبانی",
    "back": "heat sth (make sth hot)",
    "examples": [
      "He debated the proposals in a heated discussion."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d870ae86-2ceb-4078-aa7f-4ecfea5c56e6",
    "front": "**Def**: a person you can rely on.\n**Farsi**: فرد قابل اعتماد",
    "back": "safe pair of hands",
    "examples": [
      "He got the job because he's a safe pair of hands."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "235df91a-c25a-476e-84ca-1d1ccf985d80",
    "front": "**Def**: making good progress.\n**Farsi**: در مسیر درست حرکت کردن",
    "back": "head (in a direction)",
    "examples": [
      "The movement is heading in the right direction."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8a692c58-8e4e-4e97-b294-8bc4bda131eb",
    "front": "**Def**: give information to make it appear better, or less bad.\n**Farsi**: چرخش خبری، مدیریت رسانه‌ای",
    "back": "spin",
    "examples": [
      "The politicians gave a positive spin."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b6e28942-9ca6-431a-99cc-3139f1bf88db",
    "front": "**Def**: an area or region with a particular feature (a war/danger zone).\n**Farsi**: منطقه",
    "back": "zone",
    "examples": [
      "The streets were full of rubble in the war zone."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "19d98a23-341c-4dc0-8ffd-66ad23f38e31",
    "front": "**Def**: broken stones or bricks from a building that has been destroyed.\n**Farsi**: آوار، نخاله",
    "back": "rubble",
    "examples": [
      "The streets were filled with rubble."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f50f8d8c-b162-44f1-965f-c7673500f599",
    "front": "**Def**: not readily available; in short supply.\n**Farsi**: کمیاب",
    "back": "scarce",
    "examples": [
      "Food was scarce after the siege."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1cb5da59-db2a-4f56-a8a4-42000324e6d6",
    "front": "**Def**: defeat somebody/something completely.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً شکست دادن، تحت تأثیر قرار دادن",
    "back": "overwhelm sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "They were overwhelmed by superior forces."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5db4ed5b-301b-4e24-bb3d-5141293ce0dd",
    "front": "**Def**: fire a metal case full of explosives, to be fired from a large gun.\n**Farsi**: گلوله توپ، خمپاره",
    "back": "shell",
    "examples": [
      "The soldiers were firing shells."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e3e28c23-6c7d-45f9-a895-22ab7d85a28c",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who shoots at somebody from a hidden position.\n**Farsi**: تک‌تیرانداز",
    "back": "sniper",
    "examples": [
      "He was shot by a sniper."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cfc40fe9-04a9-49e0-9900-e60cc166b884",
    "front": "**Def**: happening without any intended or regular pattern.\n**Farsi**: تصادفی، بی‌هدف",
    "back": "random",
    "examples": [
      "The situation was at random."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "89b4d4bc-4556-4384-8af0-e9dd3d89f606",
    "front": "**Def**: go away from a place and leave it empty (syn abandon sth).\n**Farsi**: رها کردن، ترک کردن",
    "back": "desert sth",
    "examples": [
      "The inhabitants were forced to desert their city."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f3398238-54a3-472f-b687-bf7e5c35c5fa",
    "front": "**Def**: a substance secreted in the body when you are excited or afraid, giving you more energy.\n**Farsi**: آدرنالین",
    "back": "adrenaline",
    "examples": [
      "The excitement gave me an adrenaline rush."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f4267f34-bf6c-4fd2-b044-4a34ddc4ec98",
    "front": "**Def**: a military operation in which an armed force surrounds a place and stops the supply of food, etc.\n**Farsi**: محاصره",
    "back": "siege",
    "examples": [
      "The city was under siege for three months."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d45f2f6d-ea7e-4877-82a8-4e8253f95ce3",
    "front": "**Def**: selling very quickly or in large numbers.\n**Farsi**: مثل برق فروخته شدن/پرطرفدار بودن",
    "back": "selling like hot cakes",
    "examples": [
      "The new model is selling like hot cakes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c4540f93-9b0c-4871-a096-9ba1800e1fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb suffer because it will be good for them later.\n**Farsi**: سخت‌گیری به نفع شخص (نوعی ضرب‌المثل)",
    "back": "be cruel to be kind (SAYING)",
    "examples": [
      "sometimes you have to be cruel to be kind."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "714b22f0-c1c6-4c26-81e6-08b5d2f6a269",
    "front": "**Def**: feel anger about sth, often when it seems unfair. resentment N.\n**Farsi**: رنجیدن/ناراحت بودن (به دلیل ناعادلانه بودن)",
    "back": "resent sth (v)",
    "examples": [
      "They resented me being in their home."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7770cff2-fd96-45c9-a9f4-eb5a6a578531",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to exist (used especially about sth unpleasant). persistent ADJ.\n**Farsi**: ادامه یافتن/باقی ماندن",
    "back": "persist (v)",
    "examples": [
      "If symptoms persist, consult your doctor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "979c48d4-7b11-4caa-9d17-b3aadd1464d5",
    "front": "**Def**: doing things that are necessary to achieve something.\n**Farsi**: در حال انجام کاری بودن، در فرآیند",
    "back": "in the process of doing sth",
    "examples": [
      "I'm now in the process of creating my own wildlife garden."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b5f9da67-91f3-400b-b4ba-27852891f0da",
    "front": "**Def**: take a break or holiday to get your energy back.\n**Farsi**: شارژ شدن (انرژی گرفتن)",
    "back": "recharge your batteries (idiom)",
    "examples": [
      "You recharge your batteries."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "094680de-9f03-4d98-a7b8-8e7311376d44",
    "front": "**Def**: very serious (crippling debts/disease).\n**Farsi**: فلج‌کننده، بسیار سنگین",
    "back": "crippling",
    "examples": [
      "They end up with crippling financial debts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "854e1695-5150-4536-ad7e-c961508c88df",
    "front": "**Def**: using new methods or making new discoveries.\n**Farsi**: پیشگام، بدیع، نوآورانه",
    "back": "groundbreaking",
    "examples": [
      "a groundbreaking enterprise."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "91cef3ea-8a28-47ff-a4e7-7197091051ad",
    "front": "**Def**: used with nouns, adjectives, and adverbs to mean 'helping a person or thing; not harming them'. (e.g., eco-friendly, user-friendly)\n**Farsi**: دوستدار، سازگار (مانند کاربرپسند)",
    "back": "-friendly",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from spotlight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f5ba931c-df73-40b0-a757-eb638d65df9d",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of behaving that results from responses you were born with rather than responses you have learned. instinctive ADJ.\n**Farsi**: غریزه/فطرت",
    "back": "instinct",
    "examples": [
      "My own instinct is to be quite guarded."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "18847fff-f2f6-4978-acc8-ab252da9bce1",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. (of animals) have sex and produce young. 2. keep animals in order for them to produce young.\n**Farsi**: تولید مثل کردن، پرورش دادن",
    "back": "breed V",
    "examples": [
      "Eagles breed in spring. We breed eagles in captivity."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cabb1c51-ea0b-4e09-8a22-9fc0ba6233c6",
    "front": "**Def**: means 'it doesn't matter what (when, etc.)' or 'it isn't important what (when, etc.)'.\n**Farsi**: مهم نیست چه چیزی، هر آنچه که",
    "back": "no matter what/whatever",
    "examples": [
      "No matter what happens, don't panic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "390b8640-71ef-40f8-b473-df1e75e656b2",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth harmful to sb because they harmed you first. retaliation N.\n**Farsi**: تلافی کردن، مقابله به مثل کردن",
    "back": "retaliate",
    "examples": [
      "He retaliated and kicked mine."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0bad23cf-e5f8-49f1-957b-e8e35ff532be",
    "front": "**Def**: accept and deal with a difficult situation without letting it worry you.\n**Farsi**: با آرامش با چیزی کنار آمدن/مواجه شدن",
    "back": "take sth in your stride",
    "examples": [
      "Some teenagers take failure in their stride."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a43f0ec3-67e4-45f7-b8ba-afeb006bb4ef",
    "front": "**Def**: qualities that exist and can be developed (fulfil/realize your potential = use your natural abilities to achieve what you hoped to achieve).\n**Farsi**: پتانسیل/استعداد",
    "back": "potential",
    "examples": [
      "A talented young chef who was really keen to fulfil his potential."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "67d8cc04-5c2d-4cbe-9ed9-ddb410fe9f4f",
    "front": "**Def**: the offering of money or another incentive to sb to persuade them to take part in an activity, usually something dishonest.\n**Farsi**: رشوه و فساد",
    "back": "bribery and corruption",
    "examples": [
      "There are still allegations of bribery and corruption in the police force."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "52a332f5-f681-4455-b883-94633c8822a5",
    "front": "**Def**: the skin covering the part of the head where your hair is. If it itches (or is itchy), you want to scratch it.\n**Farsi**: پوست سر خارش‌دار",
    "back": "itchy scalp",
    "examples": [
      "I had an itchy scalp until I started using this special shampoo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fe91c19d-353f-4b28-bdd9-c57224f2ff35",
    "front": "**Def**: get rid of sth you no longer want or need.\n**Farsi**: دور انداختن",
    "back": "discard sth",
    "examples": [
      "Discard any remaining solution."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e47f47fc-4c24-42c0-8af8-461e5205f4ab",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. do more of sth than is stated in an order or a law. 2. be greater than a number, amount, or quality.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز کردن از حد/بیشتر بودن",
    "back": "exceed",
    "examples": [
      "Do not exceed the stated dose. / The film exceeded my expectations."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "47997217-2540-415b-aa80-935f8dfae882",
    "front": "**Def**: behaving confidently so that people take notice of what you say.\n**Farsi**: قاطع/با اعتماد به نفس",
    "back": "assertive",
    "examples": [
      "whether she's assertive enough for this role."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c91331ea-4a4e-4847-a6fa-d85ce70450a4",
    "front": "**Def**: A degree of sth is a certain level or amount of sth, and it is commonly used in certain expressions or patterns.\n**Farsi**: میزان، درجه",
    "back": "degree",
    "examples": [
      "It requires a degree of skill."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b22b6645-63ca-43df-ada8-f8dcca95cd22",
    "front": "**Def**: you believe people do things for themselves rather than for unselfish reasons. cynicism N.\n**Farsi**: بدبین (به انگیزه‌های انسان)",
    "back": "cynical",
    "examples": [
      "My brother is very cynical about politicians."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "03176010-e9ce-4a2b-8d03-2bc786c8faaa",
    "front": "**Def**: a family in which the parents are divorced or separated.\n**Farsi**: خانه از هم پاشیده (طلاق والدین)",
    "back": "broken home",
    "examples": [
      "A broken home needn't have a detrimental effect."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eef16d25-afb3-427a-ad3a-a0ba7bfc049b",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to happen soon.\n**Farsi**: قریب‌الوقوع، حتمی",
    "back": "imminent",
    "examples": [
      "Warburg takeover imminent."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0aa30ca7-f4a5-487a-bf89-0b13422716b8",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in achieving or winning sth (clinch a deal/victory).\n**Farsi**: قطعی کردن، به دست آوردن",
    "back": "clinch sth",
    "examples": [
      "Cavendish could clinch the deal."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0edf1bca-766d-4b0e-920a-5630980c84a2",
    "front": "**Def**: INF go out of business. SYN go bankrupt.\n**Farsi**: ورشکست شدن، از بین رفتن",
    "back": "go under",
    "examples": [
      "The company may go under."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0051250-8176-491d-a191-b02ae05d9ccb",
    "front": "**Def**: stop running a business and close it completely.\n**Farsi**: منحل کردن (شرکت)",
    "back": "wind sth up",
    "examples": [
      "The board may have to wind up the company."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d9161139-60bb-48b0-8df0-c96101afbda8",
    "front": "**Def**: leave an important job.\n**Farsi**: کنار رفتن، استعفا دادن",
    "back": "step down/aside",
    "examples": [
      "The chairman had to step down."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6b2772d1-496b-438d-9dee-482c523e3676",
    "front": "**Def**: take a particular course of action.\n**Farsi**: آن مسیر خاص را دنبال کردن",
    "back": "go down that road",
    "examples": [
      "The company doesn't want to go down that particular road."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2bf4cdda-eed8-4ae8-8846-2f39ad0b6a2b",
    "front": "**Def**: INF, DISAPPROVING avoid doing sth that you should do.\n**Farsi**: شانه خالی کردن از زیر چیزی",
    "back": "wriggle out of sth / doing sth",
    "examples": [
      "They are trying to wriggle out of their obligation to customers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "17eada44-e112-4062-8bed-72bfaaa20113",
    "front": "**Def**: not accept a bad situation without a fight or protest.\n**Farsi**: بی‌تفاوت نماندن، اعتراض کردن",
    "back": "not take sth lying down",
    "examples": [
      "You can be sure that BA won't take this situation lying down."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e9f8efae-6fcf-4210-99e2-52662c3fcd42",
    "front": "**Def**: affect the result of sth in one way rather than another.\n**Farsi**: تعادل را بر هم زدن، نتیجه را تغییر دادن",
    "back": "tip the balance",
    "examples": [
      "The city's transport links could tip the balance in their favour."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "626d514e-d5f7-4723-8c7d-e7f2e5096673",
    "front": "**Def**: increase sth and make it stronger (fuel fears/inflation).\n**Farsi**: دامن زدن به، تشدید کردن",
    "back": "fuel sth",
    "examples": [
      "The situation is fuelling fears that prices could rise again."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "79d6d8ce-faac-488c-abe3-bcf87f9266c9",
    "front": "**Def**: the situation becomes clearer and less disturbed.\n**Farsi**: آرام شدن اوضاع، فرو نشستن گرد و غبار",
    "back": "the dust settles",
    "examples": [
      "Wait until the dust settles."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fc79c951-8c6f-4a8c-b9ce-09f642715240",
    "front": "**Def**: a large and sudden increase in the amount or value of sth. surge v.\n**Farsi**: افزایش ناگهانی، موج",
    "back": "surge (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The market is now expecting a surge in the value of the euro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dffded35-55a4-453c-8d8b-7c43fd8656b7",
    "front": "**Def**: an improvement or increase. OPP loss.\n**Farsi**: افزایش، سود",
    "back": "gain",
    "examples": [
      "The dollar made significant gains."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "64cb13ed-d5ec-4510-b05d-606a34acc49b",
    "front": "**Def**: INF a sudden or significant increase in the level or amount of sth. OPP cut.\n**Farsi**: افزایش شدید و ناگهانی",
    "back": "hike",
    "examples": [
      "Another hike in the rate is possible."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e849d350-e959-483b-ae19-39e93607f6bb",
    "front": "**Def**: become stronger. OPP weaken.\n**Farsi**: تقویت شدن",
    "back": "strengthen",
    "examples": [
      "The yen will strengthen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "51a33fbe-4d68-4e33-8baa-8d6bf0964e88",
    "front": "**Def**: confident, successful, and staying at a high level. SYN healthy.\n**Farsi**: پررونق، با نشاط",
    "back": "buoyant",
    "examples": [
      "The market is still buoyant."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf8f9ec5-01d4-45bb-8bb3-ff8449e1ebf7",
    "front": "**Def**: buy sth quickly, usually while it is cheap or available.\n**Farsi**: سریع خریدن، قاپیدن",
    "back": "snap sth up",
    "examples": [
      "The advice is to snap up the shares while you can."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c1173b31-88c3-46cb-84dd-24b519ecfd72",
    "front": "**Def**: fall suddenly and quickly. SYN plunge.\n**Farsi**: سقوط کردن، به شدت کاهش یافتن",
    "back": "plummet",
    "examples": [
      "The value may plummet even more."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "87fd9c1e-aef5-4951-814e-c856cf117db0",
    "front": "**Def**: reduce sth by a large amount.\n**Farsi**: به شدت کاهش دادن",
    "back": "slash sth",
    "examples": [
      "The Federal Reserve has slashed the discount rate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3e8be685-c11c-432c-bc74-132ad28da420",
    "front": "**Def**: remove sth from sth, quickly and completely.\n**Farsi**: حذف کردن، از بین بردن (مقدار پول)",
    "back": "wipe sth off sth",
    "examples": [
      "The recession has wiped billions off the stock markets round the world."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "26ccc55b-c5c8-4130-b6a4-c88d84838741",
    "front": "**Def**: a state of great confusion.\n**Farsi**: آشفتگی، هرج و مرج",
    "back": "turmoil",
    "examples": [
      "The market is still in turmoil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa29285b-d0c6-46f0-a8dd-c32204a311ec",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to change suddenly. volatility N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌ثبات، نوسان‌پذیر",
    "back": "volatile",
    "examples": [
      "The market remains volatile."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f09d21af-1099-43b1-b7df-dd1e002854ec",
    "front": "**Def**: a lot of sudden change (also a bumpy ride INF). turbulent ADJ.\n**Farsi**: تلاطم، نوسانات شدید",
    "back": "turbulence",
    "examples": [
      "There is likely to be short-term turbulence in the market."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "25822321-9790-4238-8a50-45ffce50ae42",
    "front": "**Def**: saying two different and opposing things. SYN conflicting. contradiction N. contradict sb/sth v.\n**Farsi**: متناقض، ضد و نقیض",
    "back": "contradictory",
    "examples": [
      "Investors may be given contradictory advice."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cc52eb3c-82ab-4474-8f6a-34314dee010d",
    "front": "**Def**: support or form the basis of sth.\n**Farsi**: تقویت کردن، زیربنا قرار دادن",
    "back": "underpin sth",
    "examples": [
      "Good global growth which will underpin corporate profit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ea3d5cd7-d7c9-4582-bea8-ebd3d82bc578",
    "front": "**Def**: the responsibility of having to pay back a lot of money.\n**Farsi**: بار بدهی",
    "back": "debt burden",
    "examples": [
      "Few significant debt burdens."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "827710fe-5a9a-453e-a45f-68f0e696b5bf",
    "front": "**Def**: the total profit or income you get from a business or investment.\n**Farsi**: بازده، سود",
    "back": "yield",
    "examples": [
      "Current yields may be low."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3d5ddce9-801f-4775-8a68-f039929550ec",
    "front": "**Def**: (in finance) An underlying number or situation shows what the true amount or level of sth is.\n**Farsi**: اساسی، زمینه‌ای",
    "back": "underlying",
    "examples": [
      "The underlying outlook is healthy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "67eff5a8-cc18-41f1-aa18-74489220c0d9",
    "front": "**Def**: (in finance) a temporary and fragile situation caused by a rapid increase in sth (the bubble will burst = the situation will end, and people will lose money).\n**Farsi**: حباب (مالی)",
    "back": "bubble",
    "examples": [
      "A huge credit bubble."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "07f13156-c1b7-42c8-8f77-4a945d0eb345",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth dries up, there is gradually less and less of it.\n**Farsi**: خشک شدن، تمام شدن (منابع)",
    "back": "dry up",
    "examples": [
      "Bank lending will dry up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "472069b3-1acd-4ba5-bc12-89598489cfc4",
    "front": "**Def**: cause sth to happen.\n**Farsi**: به راه انداختن، باعث شدن",
    "back": "trigger sth",
    "examples": [
      "Could trigger more selling."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "38480b72-afc7-44de-826d-b47d9358ba31",
    "front": "**Def**: PL the money a person or business has to spend regularly. OPP income.\n**Farsi**: مخارج، هزینه‌ها",
    "back": "outgoings",
    "examples": [
      "Keep a record of your outgoings."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d3f1dc77-6161-4af1-bf30-fe7115950373",
    "front": "**Def**: defeat sb very heavily (often used when talking about sport). (SYN thrash sb).\n**Farsi**: کسی را به سختی شکست دادن",
    "back": "hammer sb (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Our team got absolutely hammered yesterday. We lost 5-1."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f32ec446-1529-4aa4-be3f-d693822346ad",
    "front": "**Def**: increase gradually in size. SYN build up/accumulate.\n**Farsi**: تلنبار شدن، انباشته شدن",
    "back": "mount up",
    "examples": [
      "Allow debts to mount up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7a8a11d4-5a5d-4000-baf2-2f1fd33fb19a",
    "front": "**Def**: a piece of business between people.\n**Farsi**: تراکنش، معامله",
    "back": "transaction",
    "examples": [
      "Check all the transactions in your bank statements."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7ac9f667-4413-4d55-bac2-69af2fa0d8cc",
    "front": "**Def**: waste sth, especially money or time, in a careless way.\n**Farsi**: هدر دادن، تلف کردن",
    "back": "squander sth",
    "examples": [
      "Squander large sums of money."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f1230442-b7ea-4cf0-bc70-4d8cb1da2746",
    "front": "**Def**: use numbers to find a total number, amount, or distance. SYN work sth out. calculation N.\n**Farsi**: محاسبه کردن",
    "back": "calculate sth",
    "examples": [
      "Calculate the total amount of money coming in."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "19defe4f-89b3-4bda-9c30-2cbd59c67bc9",
    "front": "**Def**: A surplus is more of something than is necessary. If it is money, the opposite is a deficit.\n**Farsi**: مازاد، اضافه",
    "back": "surplus",
    "examples": [
      "If there's a surplus, don't spend it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "df261c53-2477-4af5-bea1-5b31647fe671",
    "front": "**Def**: an amount of money available for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: صندوق مالی، وجه",
    "back": "fund",
    "examples": [
      "Emergency fund."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "78058025-c9aa-4be3-ab4d-659858355410",
    "front": "**Def**: sth that may or may not happen (contingency plans/a contingency fund).\n**Farsi**: پیشامد، موارد احتمالی",
    "back": "contingency",
    "examples": [
      "Keep for contingencies."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6908cd0d-bde0-4490-8877-fb120676c539",
    "front": "**Def**: the difference between what you have and what you need.\n**Farsi**: کمبود، کسری (مالی)",
    "back": "shortfall",
    "examples": [
      "If there is a shortfall, then you must take action."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7355ddab-e6d4-42d1-9515-55647712d500",
    "front": "**Def**: reduce the amount of money, time, goods, etc. that you use. SYN make cutbacks.\n**Farsi**: صرفه‌جویی کردن",
    "back": "economize",
    "examples": [
      "Consider where you can economize."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "45a1b01e-b5aa-41fb-9702-c11c93f33c7d",
    "front": "**Def**: give money to sb to help them pay for sth. subsidy N.\n**Farsi**: یارانه دادن به کسی",
    "back": "subsidize sb",
    "examples": [
      "Don't expect anyone else to subsidize you."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "95b3b298-b7f9-40a7-8b6d-be9f1da48093",
    "front": "**Def**: write sth quickly.\n**Farsi**: سریع یادداشت کردن",
    "back": "jot sth down",
    "examples": [
      "Jot down a list of jobs to do."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "57a61c7c-217b-42a9-b685-a44e3a5351e3",
    "front": "**Def**: a particular way in which sth is organized or done (on a day-to-day basis, on a daily/weekly/regular basis).\n**Farsi**: مبنا، اساس",
    "back": "basis",
    "examples": [
      "On a daily basis."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "036e371f-fd77-41d2-a3e6-e706a6e25cfe",
    "front": "**Def**: in a determined and firm way.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحمانه، قاطعانه",
    "back": "ruthlessly",
    "examples": [
      "You need to be ruthless."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "76fdc44c-d0a1-4c30-a34c-ae97f271b652",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in doing or completing sth. SYN achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: به انجام رساندن، موفق شدن در",
    "back": "accomplish sth",
    "examples": [
      "Accomplish your daily list."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c6452c09-8e98-4860-926b-e41b53286c8f",
    "front": "**Def**: continue doing sth despite difficulties.\n**Farsi**: به چیزی پایبند بودن",
    "back": "stick to sth",
    "examples": [
      "Do you stick to your priorities."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "30fb4b6c-3866-4810-b74d-8c6a6e27d99a",
    "front": "**Def**: expect sth will happen and prepare for it. anticipation N.\n**Farsi**: پیش‌بینی کردن",
    "back": "anticipate sth",
    "examples": [
      "Try to anticipate so that you can schedule your tasks better."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0a2152fd-c531-40dc-896e-890a10f2f21b",
    "front": "**Def**: arrange for sth to happen at a particular time. schedule N.\n**Farsi**: برنامه‌ریزی زمانی کردن",
    "back": "schedule sth",
    "examples": [
      "Schedule your tasks better."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "37744ffc-f38c-40d4-adaf-0116466b1aad",
    "front": "**Def**: give part of your work to sb, especially sb in a lower position.\n**Farsi**: واگذار کردن، محول کردن (مسئولیت)",
    "back": "delegate sth (to sb)",
    "examples": [
      "Do you delegate responsibilities."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "14e78441-801b-4d69-ad57-24a6677fecdd",
    "front": "**Def**: strict and severe.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، سختگیرانه",
    "back": "rigorous",
    "examples": [
      "Set yourself rigorous time limits."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "32d58c47-438d-4610-8ce9-905092c1ebf9",
    "front": "**Def**: far away from other people and houses.\n**Farsi**: دورافتاده، خارج از مسیر معمول گردشگری",
    "back": "off the beaten track",
    "examples": [
      "Our China trek offers an experience off the beaten track."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "83695ccf-d304-4b69-9461-33e475e180d9",
    "front": "**Def**: If you are in credit, there is money in your account. OPP overdrawn / in the red INF.\n**Farsi**: بستانکار، دارای موجودی",
    "back": "credit",
    "examples": [
      "Keep your account in credit all the time."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fbce51a7-8dba-4ac8-9827-9cee38c6f08e",
    "front": "**Def**: quickly; without delay. prompt ADJ.\n**Farsi**: سریعاً، بی‌درنگ",
    "back": "promptly",
    "examples": [
      "Respond to them promptly."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "17344c5e-75c2-4d72-b612-434dbbd2f2e9",
    "front": "**Def**: not producing good results. OPP productive.\n**Farsi**: غیرمولد، بی‌نتیجه",
    "back": "unproductive",
    "examples": [
      "Leaving them frustrated and unproductive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "57f49e47-5851-482e-8364-50507d11da7b",
    "front": "**Def**: badly affected by sth (also severely/badly hit).\n**Farsi**: به شدت آسیب دیده",
    "back": "hard-hit",
    "examples": [
      "Females feel particularly hard-hit by the deluge."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5092d191-a0ef-4bfa-b669-7b27cca4a406",
    "front": "**Def**: be/become impossible to control. OPP be under control.\n**Farsi**: از کنترل خارج شدن",
    "back": "be/get out of hand",
    "examples": [
      "Email is got out of hand."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "16239390-3a4a-4a78-82d1-af263742b104",
    "front": "**Def**: stop speaking or doing sth for a time.\n**Farsi**: دست کشیدن از، متوقف کردن (کار)",
    "back": "break off (from sth)",
    "examples": [
      "When you break off from what you are doing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a92626b8-9ff6-4c59-a7fd-0bff44f2cc4e",
    "front": "**Def**: a linked series of thoughts in your head at one time.\n**Farsi**: رشته افکار",
    "back": "train of thought",
    "examples": [
      "You lose your train of thought."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0ee8c435-8783-4fd8-9c9b-8898d64f3218",
    "front": "**Def**: keep sth, especially money or time, for a purpose.\n**Farsi**: اختصاص دادن، کنار گذاشتن",
    "back": "set sth aside",
    "examples": [
      "Set aside two or three specific email-reading times."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c4c443e-7aa6-43a7-8c9a-a4cbf7caed19",
    "front": "**Def**: a fast-spreading disease which often results in death; in the title it is something that causes irritation.\n**Farsi**: بلای فراگیر (استعاری)",
    "back": "plague (metaphorical)",
    "examples": [
      "Email stress: the new office workers' plague."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c1aedaa-5a54-4c53-a440-ab82e7454ccd",
    "front": "**Def**: a small river, but here it means a continuous flow of things.\n**Farsi**: جریان، سیل (ایمیل)",
    "back": "stream (metaphorical)",
    "examples": [
      "A never-ending stream of emails."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1cbcbacd-81ae-404c-84f5-47f5455445dd",
    "front": "**Def**: a flood or heavy rain, but in the text it means a great quantity of something arriving at the same time.\n**Farsi**: سیل عظیم، هجوم (ایمیل)",
    "back": "deluge (metaphorical)",
    "examples": [
      "Hard-hit by the deluge."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bfdeadae-d1dd-4fe5-afa5-145b66851f3d",
    "front": "**Def**: a failure to reach an agreement or settle an argument (be unable to break the deadlock).\n**Farsi**: بن‌بست، گره کور",
    "back": "deadlock",
    "examples": [
      "Talks between Royal Mail bosses and the CWU union have again ended in deadlock."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "569db8c4-6d7c-445f-8fb9-c42cdae59378",
    "front": "**Def**: a system of voting in which votes are made in secret (ballot (v)).\n**Farsi**: رای‌گیری، اخذ رأی مخفی",
    "back": "ballot",
    "examples": [
      "Following the support of its members in the national ballot."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1fc08d-5bb8-4c08-85a6-225d234d910f",
    "front": "**Def**: a disagreement, often official, between people or groups (a pay/industrial dispute, settle a dispute).\n**Farsi**: اختلاف، مناقشه (صنعتی)",
    "back": "dispute",
    "examples": [
      "It is not just a pay dispute."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f356daaa-8568-4d5c-92fb-db7dfe9b9069",
    "front": "**Def**: prevent sth from continuing.\n**Farsi**: متوقف کردن",
    "back": "halt sth",
    "examples": [
      "An attempt to halt the closure of 2,500 post offices."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f053e34-78af-413f-9b2a-467bfcd6836d",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which a school, factory, etc. is permanently shut.\n**Farsi**: تعطیلی، بسته شدن",
    "back": "closure",
    "examples": [
      "The closure of 2,500 post offices."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d7fc499d-96db-4bd5-9ce3-a9813642d502",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of selling an industry so it is no longer owned by the government. OPP nationalization. privatize sth v.\n**Farsi**: خصوصی‌سازی",
    "back": "privatization",
    "examples": [
      "Further privatization of services."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6408830e-3830-4bb7-b601-65b754e595e7",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is at stake, you will lose it if a plan or action is not successful (there's a lot at stake / the stakes are high).\n**Farsi**: در معرض خطر، مطرح",
    "back": "at stake",
    "examples": [
      "There is a great deal at stake."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "27cee6cd-3c2f-4fca-9e03-dc32c99205cf",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to do sth or tending to do sth. inclination N.\n**Farsi**: متمایل بودن به انجام کاری",
    "back": "inclined to do sth",
    "examples": [
      "Who may feel more inclined to step up their own claims."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3e4a218d-d36d-4d5e-b0c7-0cec3fc32434",
    "front": "**Def**: increase the amount of an activity in order to achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: افزایش دادن، بالا بردن",
    "back": "step sth up",
    "examples": [
      "Step up their own claims for higher wage settlements."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "61693b7f-8463-4b72-b858-bc3c3c3c821d",
    "front": "**Def**: get involved in a situation in order to help. intervention N.\n**Farsi**: مداخله کردن، پادرمیانی کردن",
    "back": "intervene in sth",
    "examples": [
      "Intervene at once to resolve the problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ceaaa5c0-515f-4b2d-8c5f-7e94a3c6cabf",
    "front": "**Def**: FML find an acceptable solution to a problem. resolution N.\n**Farsi**: حل و فصل کردن، رفع کردن",
    "back": "resolve sth",
    "examples": [
      "Intervene to resolve the problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c300903-28e7-4101-9942-11b043a80a36",
    "front": "**Def**: slept very well.\n**Farsi**: مثل کنده خوابیدن (خواب عمیق)",
    "back": "slept like a log",
    "examples": [
      "I slept like a log last night."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5d2772f7-a26b-47b8-98f2-58a55b1844d7",
    "front": "**Def**: INF too anxious and tired to be able to relax.\n**Farsi**: تحت فشار عصبی، خسته و مضطرب",
    "back": "stressed out",
    "examples": [
      "Are stressed out by the pressure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "503d23da-ff82-4638-af29-bef3a4b5ba89",
    "front": "**Def**: deal with a problem successfully (if sth sorts itself out, the problem is resolved without the need for action from anyone).\n**Farsi**: حل و فصل کردن (مشکل)",
    "back": "sort sth out",
    "examples": [
      "See if the staff can sort it out themselves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "29152faf-c428-4682-a152-591bb88c3797",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb else deal with sth that you should deal with.\n**Farsi**: مسئولیت را به گردن دیگری انداختن",
    "back": "pass the buck",
    "examples": [
      "This could be interpreted as passing the buck."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0c0bbfd6-c71a-41f2-bf37-e99bdaf7d407",
    "front": "**Def**: get involved in a situation in a way that annoys others. interference N.\n**Farsi**: دخالت آزاردهنده کردن",
    "back": "interfere (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "The staff may not want you to interfere."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1f1fe749-ff55-474c-97e4-b9e252ed04ea",
    "front": "**Def**: sensible; showing good judgement. wisdom N. SYN prudent. prudence N.\n**Farsi**: عاقلانه، محتاطانه",
    "back": "wise (of actions)",
    "examples": [
      "It could be a wise thing to do."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ba2f54de-9eb7-4afb-83bd-0840eb2608a4",
    "front": "**Def**: FML delay doing sth until later, often because you don't want to do it. procrastination N.\n**Farsi**: امروز و فردا کردن، به تعویق انداختن",
    "back": "procrastinate",
    "examples": [
      "Would you just be procrastinating?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e8273e96-97eb-4c1b-ba27-ec21cb7e01d6",
    "front": "**Def**: pretend a difficult situation doesn't exist.\n**Farsi**: نادیده گرفتن مشکل، سر در برف فرو بردن",
    "back": "bury your head in the sand",
    "examples": [
      "Would you bury your head in the sand?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e6427e22-2c2b-4fbe-8836-476bc993e69b",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing you particularly dislike or find annoying.\n**Farsi**: چیزی که به شدت آزاردهنده است، مورد تنفر شخصی",
    "back": "pet hate",
    "examples": [
      "It's one of my pet hates."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d8dd1a88-a897-407c-80bd-f4b53467edf1",
    "front": "**Def**: make a situation better after a mistake has been made.\n**Farsi**: درست کردن، رفع اشکال کردن",
    "back": "put sth right",
    "examples": [
      "Leave others to put it right."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3106238e-19f7-4825-8f31-6ba7b53614e8",
    "front": "**Def**: not in a place, e.g. because of illness. absence N.\n**Farsi**: غایب، حاضر نبودن",
    "back": "absent (from sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Are always absent when the work piles up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "461658a2-6467-4e6d-b916-183c4e7b112b",
    "front": "**Def**: become larger in quantity or amount. SYN accumulate.\n**Farsi**: تلنبار شدن، روی هم جمع شدن",
    "back": "pile up",
    "examples": [
      "When the work piles up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9a944009-26a2-4025-8e50-825a72da6bec",
    "front": "**Def**: very busy.\n**Farsi**: پر مشغله، شلوغ",
    "back": "hectic",
    "examples": [
      "Things are really hectic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "43262ba8-d3ad-44b3-8e5f-a431d4e6b953",
    "front": "**Def**: not do sth, or not give enough attention to sth. neglect N.\n**Farsi**: نادیده گرفتن، بی‌توجهی کردن",
    "back": "neglect sth",
    "examples": [
      "Neglect their own work."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a6ded8f3-faea-4610-a085-d424976849b0",
    "front": "**Def**: INF become involved in sth that does not concern you.\n**Farsi**: فضولی کردن، دخالت کردن",
    "back": "poke/stick your nose in(to) sth",
    "examples": [
      "Poke their noses into other people's business."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b314bbd3-46d2-41e9-aa93-7d3b7bd5ce8f",
    "front": "**Def**: not do sth that people expect you to do. SYN neglect to do sth.\n**Farsi**: کوتاهی کردن در انجام کاری",
    "back": "fail to do sth",
    "examples": [
      "Fail to provide handover instructions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e0470a01-2628-4a29-9933-b64675a6936e",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of making sb else responsible for sth. hand sth over (to sb) v.\n**Farsi**: واگذاری (مسئولیت)",
    "back": "handover",
    "examples": [
      "Provide handover instructions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "824746cf-cc16-42c3-9812-76863256aa77",
    "front": "**Def**: sing a tune with your lips closed.\n**Farsi**: زمزمه کردن، زیر لب آواز خواندن",
    "back": "hum",
    "examples": [
      "Constantly hum."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9392f097-03e1-4817-9ca6-809e804e2e21",
    "front": "**Def**: laugh in a silly way when you're embarrassed, amused, or nervous.\n**Farsi**: ریز خندیدن، خنده احمقانه کردن",
    "back": "giggle",
    "examples": [
      "Giggle uncontrollably."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fcd87333-4305-460a-b3ad-f5097dcfe7e2",
    "front": "**Def**: take a quick, noisy breath in through your nose, e.g. when you have a cold.\n**Farsi**: بو کشیدن، فین فین کردن",
    "back": "sniff",
    "examples": [
      "Constantly sniff."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "94a95ee4-4343-48ac-8c0e-50060a4b9156",
    "front": "**Def**: angry or violent behaviour by one driver towards another driver.\n**Farsi**: خشم جاده‌ای",
    "back": "road rage",
    "examples": [
      "The road rage thing was all sparked by a trivial incident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "daf7b414-f5f7-423a-b2d4-34739381d659",
    "front": "**Def**: cause sth to start or develop suddenly.\n**Farsi**: باعث شروع شدن چیزی شدن، جرقه‌ای زدن",
    "back": "spark sth (off)",
    "examples": [
      "All sparked by a trivial incident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "07ace1be-b2fa-4a1b-8ea3-05bf7c4dfc2b",
    "front": "**Def**: sth that happens, especially sth unusual or unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: حادثه، واقعه",
    "back": "incident",
    "examples": [
      "A trivial incident."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9a0df3fc-d810-4e33-af0c-2c9f996eba2a",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb very angry, crazy, etc.\n**Farsi**: کسی را دیوانه/عصبانی کردن",
    "back": "drive sb mad/crazy/insane",
    "examples": [
      "It was driving me mad."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0bc21b8d-9c41-4b8c-b7eb-1b1477d8db8b",
    "front": "**Def**: INF encourage sb to do sth, especially sth they should not do.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن کسی به کار بد",
    "back": "egg sb on",
    "examples": [
      "My passenger Phil egged me on to have a word with him."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40071c78-9951-44ea-a8f3-ae2757160772",
    "front": "**Def**: in a very great or impressive way. SYN extraordinarily.\n**Farsi**: به طور فوق‌العاده‌ای، به نحو چشمگیری",
    "back": "phenomenally",
    "examples": [
      "Phenomenally successful."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ea3d8fe1-4b95-4545-b40a-90fbbfeff9b5",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth more serious than it is.\n**Farsi**: بزرگنمایی کردن، غلو کردن",
    "back": "blow sth (up) out of (all) proportion",
    "examples": [
      "Is there a risk of blowing it up out of all proportion?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e7798cd6-0da8-4c5a-ab0d-2c30d85e9cf7",
    "front": "**Def**: INF (of a situation) have sth as a main or basic part.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه شدن در، علت اصلی بودن",
    "back": "boil down to sth",
    "examples": [
      "I think it all boils down to the fact that I haven't been well lately."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7284f7c5-b02e-497e-950e-80035c5d17e2",
    "front": "**Def**: a number of connected events that happen one after the other. SYN sequence of events.\n**Farsi**: زنجیره وقایع",
    "back": "chain of events",
    "examples": [
      "All I can say is that it was an unfortunate chain of events."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "68bae5f3-a51c-4b2b-b658-8a4d5d1baa58",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb have a particular feeling or attitude. arouse (sb's) suspicion/curiosity.\n**Farsi**: برانگیختن، تحریک کردن (شک/کنجکاوی)",
    "back": "arouse sth",
    "examples": [
      "What aroused the police's suspicions?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "02f4fd09-c6ab-4282-8d48-84db52af5df6",
    "front": "**Def**: a reason for doing sth.\n**Farsi**: انگیزه، دلیل",
    "back": "motive",
    "examples": [
      "Sims had a clear motive: revenge."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4c851c3b-23a1-4f73-98ce-c72a2df1907e",
    "front": "**Def**: the result of a situation or event (final outcome SYN end result).\n**Farsi**: نتیجه، برآیند",
    "back": "outcome",
    "examples": [
      "What was the outcome of the discussion?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f03fb02d-294f-448f-998c-f8f57f8ce054",
    "front": "**Def**: FML force sb to do sth. coercion N.\n**Farsi**: مجبور کردن کسی به انجام کاری",
    "back": "coerce sb (into doing sth)",
    "examples": [
      "We were eventually coerced into agreeing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8cd0b9b3-6908-49cb-90c6-fab037601000",
    "front": "**Def**: unintended and usually unwelcome results of an action or event. SYN consequences.\n**Farsi**: پیامدهای ناخواسته، عواقب",
    "back": "repercussions",
    "examples": [
      "It was bound to have repercussions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c5b27930-1152-4a70-be6e-881cd49ce260",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb decide to do sth.\n**Farsi**: ترغیب کردن، باعث تصمیم‌گیری شدن",
    "back": "prompt sb to do sth",
    "examples": [
      "What prompted you to ring Nina?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b937ea36-6473-47c5-8740-7c69813b6243",
    "front": "**Def**: often used when you do not want to say why you have done sth.\n**Farsi**: بدون دلیل خاصی، همینطوری",
    "back": "no reason",
    "examples": [
      "No reason - just fancied a chat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7344e779-1457-4ef1-bc78-0bc53228ebd0",
    "front": "**Def**: a new product that is based on another that already exists.\n**Farsi**: محصول فرعی، مشتق",
    "back": "spin-off",
    "examples": [
      "We're considering various spin-offs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2b836f39-370e-4c81-9658-c4e4dec8be33",
    "front": "**Def**: produce or create sth (generate income/profit/jobs).\n**Farsi**: تولید کردن، ایجاد کردن (درآمد)",
    "back": "generate sth",
    "examples": [
      "That should generate more income."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b5dbdfa0-4231-47f4-ae12-1d3f6a4d3a7a",
    "front": "**Def**: have an effect on sth, usually a good effect.\n**Farsi**: تفاوت ایجاد کردن، مؤثر بودن",
    "back": "make a difference",
    "examples": [
      "It's already made a big difference."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf32549d-eb47-41b0-b775-f4de07d0704b",
    "front": "**Def**: If a law or regulation comes into effect, it begins to apply or be used.\n**Farsi**: اجرایی شدن (قانون)",
    "back": "come into effect",
    "examples": [
      "Has the smoking ban come into effect?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "62a49808-22ea-4c67-9405-fb85abc3f1a2",
    "front": "**Def**: cause events to happen one after another in a series.\n**Farsi**: اثرات زنجیره‌ای، پیامدهای ثانویه",
    "back": "knock-on effects",
    "examples": [
      "The flood had a knock-on effect on tourism."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "296d42c5-a7ee-4aed-aeb5-d4b8e3b6d559",
    "front": "**Def**: describe sth in a way that makes it sound better than it is.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تعریف و تمجید کردن/بزرگنمایی کردن",
    "back": "talk sth up",
    "examples": [
      "He often talks things up, especially when our sales were down."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c0dcab1e-6b1a-4dc3-be0d-c4f23cc60215",
    "front": "**Def**: make a statement or story more interesting by adding details that are not always true.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را شاخ و برگ دادن/آراستن",
    "back": "embellish sth",
    "examples": [
      "I embellished my previous salary by a few thousand."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cd335c6a-f98e-470e-90f3-63ee28140f10",
    "front": "**Def**: deliberately avoid talking about sth unpleasant, or say as little as possible about it.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را لاپوشانی کردن/سرسری رد شدن",
    "back": "gloss over sth",
    "examples": [
      "I glossed over one rather unpalatable truth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ac78f13a-a53e-4db1-aacc-0b8c63198cda",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant and hard to accept.\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/غیرقابل پذیرش",
    "back": "unpalatable",
    "examples": [
      "I glossed over one rather unpalatable truth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e2e4992c-8dee-4d11-80e9-dd8a9e68b708",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce more exact information about a subject.\n**Farsi**: یعنی/به عبارت دیگر",
    "back": "namely",
    "examples": [
      "namely that I'd been sacked from my last job."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2000ccd4-c3f8-4e81-9fdf-32a5634d8a8e",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth continue for some time.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را حفظ کردن/ادامه دادن",
    "back": "sustain sth",
    "examples": [
      "Trying to sustain the lies at the interview was a nightmare."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2122c856-a5ce-487d-a73d-5824d6c86591",
    "front": "**Def**: discover or notice sth, especially sth that is hard to see or hear.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را کشف کردن/متوجه شدن",
    "back": "detect sth",
    "examples": [
      "My interviewer soon detected something was wrong."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c0edb7f-2ea5-4491-afee-94b4c94106e5",
    "front": "**Def**: announce the start of war or a ceasefire.\n**Farsi**: اعلان جنگ/آتش‌بس کردن",
    "back": "declare war / a ceasefire",
    "examples": [
      "The rebels have declared a ceasefire."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f02cf1b2-1dd7-436e-84fd-8231cd8e1a0a",
    "front": "**Def**: sth that is destroyed or sb who suffers when sth else happens.\n**Farsi**: تلفات/قربانی",
    "back": "casualty",
    "examples": [
      "When war is declared, truth is the first casualty."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b6865444-bbab-4b90-b814-c46e09988ff0",
    "front": "**Def**: in such a way that the speaker's name is kept secret. (N: anonymity)\n**Farsi**: به طور ناشناس",
    "back": "anonymously",
    "examples": [
      "Tell the complete truth anonymously."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2de9326c-ff1a-4efa-b4f4-a990c324b8c2",
    "front": "**Def**: after sb has died.\n**Farsi**: پس از مرگ",
    "back": "posthumously",
    "examples": [
      "He was awarded the medal posthumously."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0d52bd15-4c23-4d17-883d-244a4626d723",
    "front": "**Def**: an enemy or opponent.\n**Farsi**: دشمن/حریف",
    "back": "adversary (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "Tell the truth so as to puzzle and confound your adversaries."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aab16177-a11d-4201-a20e-5daf4280c292",
    "front": "**Def**: trick sb by behaving dishonestly (also deceive yourself refuse to admit that sth unpleasant is true SYN delude yourself). (N: deceit, deception)\n**Farsi**: کسی را فریب دادن/اغفال کردن",
    "back": "deceive sb",
    "examples": [
      "We deceive ourselves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9af53068-8c73-4a4b-8a54-890224f9c591",
    "front": "**Def**: is a lie.\n**Farsi**: نادرستی/دروغ",
    "back": "A falsehood (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "The most dangerous of all falsehoods is a slightly distorted truth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dae82c28-ad47-4fea-a970-0c8f5672eea2",
    "front": "**Def**: a small lie, especially one you tell to avoid hurting someone.\n**Farsi**: دروغ مصلحتی",
    "back": "A white lie",
    "examples": [
      "A white lie is a small lie, especially one you tell to avoid hurting someone."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e3d2fb78-e516-416d-b602-7637c189e1b1",
    "front": "**Def**: a statement which only gives some of the facts.\n**Farsi**: نیمه حقیقت",
    "back": "A half-truth",
    "examples": [
      "That's a half-truth. They're all on your pizzas!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "322d4242-a508-44b3-8266-2f0770fbb782",
    "front": "**Def**: an unimportant lie.\n**Farsi**: دروغ کوچک/سرهم بندی",
    "back": "A fib (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "A fib is an unimportant lie."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c4cee529-47ed-4117-bd12-7bf922f157ea",
    "front": "**Def**: not important. (Opp: major).\n**Farsi**: جزئی/کوچک",
    "back": "minor",
    "examples": [
      "The design is a minor problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5409bd27-ada3-4e87-aded-57f63f3468b4",
    "front": "**Def**: increasing in size, amount, or degree.\n**Farsi**: رو به رشد/فزاینده",
    "back": "growing",
    "examples": [
      "Obesity is a growing problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7f484596-f18c-42d9-b443-f85a6b5034cb",
    "front": "**Def**: requiring immediate action.\n**Farsi**: فوری/ضروری",
    "back": "urgent",
    "examples": [
      "Lack of funds is an urgent issue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5e13a7b3-d9a9-4b18-8b2d-c7a8125c5870",
    "front": "**Def**: always existing and not seeming to change.\n**Farsi**: همیشگی/دیرپا",
    "back": "perennial",
    "examples": [
      "Noise is a perennial problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8ea8afde-83f8-4bcf-8955-63d15b92c7cc",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to be solved. (SYN insurmountable FML).\n**Farsi**: حل نشدنی/لا ینحل",
    "back": "insoluble",
    "examples": [
      "The problem seems insoluble."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd07cee8-7533-49fe-9b10-53d1a93bf750",
    "front": "**Def**: start to exist. (SYN occur / come up).\n**Farsi**: بوجود آمدن/پیش آمدن",
    "back": "arise",
    "examples": [
      "Various problems have arisen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d8d8e5d5-59fd-4d25-a23b-ea62c26dd4bf",
    "front": "**Def**: mention sth for people to discuss.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را مطرح کردن",
    "back": "raise sth",
    "examples": [
      "I raised the problem of staffing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c2ba58f1-e6e6-4131-ad08-94d4163145d1",
    "front": "**Def**: deal with a problem or difficult situation. (SYN face up to sth).\n**Farsi**: با چیزی مقابله کردن/مواجه شدن",
    "back": "confront sth",
    "examples": [
      "She's had to confront the fact that she can no longer walk."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a2643794-3c37-46dd-bed5-19bf1c2aca01",
    "front": "**Def**: think about a difficult situation and decide how to deal with it.\n**Farsi**: به چیزی پرداختن/رسیدگی کردن",
    "back": "address sth",
    "examples": [
      "We've got to address the lack of experience in the team."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "76ff7613-96af-4e8e-bc91-03fa32db846e",
    "front": "**Def**: begin to understand and deal with sth difficult.\n**Farsi**: با چیزی دست و پنجه نرم کردن/مسلط شدن",
    "back": "get to grips with sth",
    "examples": [
      "I'm just beginning to get to grips with my new job."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "41daa357-a79a-49c0-a0c4-6cddba032452",
    "front": "**Def**: make a big effort to deal with a problem.\n**Farsi**: با چیزی دست و پنجه نرم کردن/اقدام کردن",
    "back": "tackle sth",
    "examples": [
      "They must tackle inflation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ca683e9d-0bc6-438b-8e04-f57b628cc8ba",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in dealing with a problem that has been preventing you from achieving sth.\n**Farsi**: بر چیزی فائق آمدن/غلبه کردن",
    "back": "overcome sth",
    "examples": [
      "The company had to overcome a number of financial difficulties."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7965b469-e20b-41fb-82bf-831386fc1cb1",
    "front": "**Def**: make an existing problem worse. (SYN aggravate sth).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تشدید کردن/وخیم‌تر کردن",
    "back": "exacerbate sth (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "We must be careful not to exacerbate the problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f02adb8-594d-4058-be34-09df1f09f0ef",
    "front": "**Def**: damage sb's confidence, etc.\n**Farsi**: (اعتماد به نفس) کسی را تضعیف کردن",
    "back": "dent (sb's confidence, reputation, etc.)",
    "examples": [
      "This can dent their self-esteem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b65921f3-ba62-4104-a287-7d86681c7e66",
    "front": "**Def**: the way you feel about yourself (high/low self-esteem).\n**Farsi**: عزت نفس",
    "back": "self-esteem",
    "examples": [
      "This can dent their self-esteem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6be9b3bc-3ef9-4f40-9445-6a4b8decb033",
    "front": "**Def**: treat sth as unimportant. (OPP take sth seriously).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را دست کم گرفتن",
    "back": "make light of sth",
    "examples": [
      "Don't make light of these worries."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "631725f3-5d2c-4db0-b312-66adf9c2eac6",
    "front": "**Def**: not important or serious.\n**Farsi**: بی اهمیت/ناچیز",
    "back": "trivial",
    "examples": [
      "Don't make light of these worries even if they seem trivial to you."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "de35736e-e045-4ff7-afee-9625d5aa8718",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is not honest or sincere. (Adj: phoney)\n**Farsi**: ریاکار/قلابی",
    "back": "phoney (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Nobody spots a phoney quicker than a child."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3722a391-4f8b-4340-a404-772085d0aae0",
    "front": "**Def**: not allow a problem to have too much importance.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را در چارچوب درست دیدن/اهمیت واقعی دادن",
    "back": "keep sth in perspective",
    "examples": [
      "Help your teen to keep things in perspective."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8cb1710-be8b-4821-a46f-ca53d0c08972",
    "front": "**Def**: a problem that delays or prevents progress.\n**Farsi**: شکست/عقب‌گرد",
    "back": "setback",
    "examples": [
      "Everyone has setbacks in life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4f1590db-a059-46c4-95a3-699aba9bd5be",
    "front": "**Def**: give your support to sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: از کسی/چیزی حمایت کردن",
    "back": "be behind sb/sth",
    "examples": [
      "I will support him, because she loves him (His mother will support him)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "11f424ce-1575-404d-99af-c861c4e82d02",
    "front": "**Def**: without being affected or influenced by sth.\n**Farsi**: صرف نظر از چیزی",
    "back": "regardless of sth",
    "examples": [
      "Regardless of what happens."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7872b0a3-8517-482f-8011-9c684016cf2d",
    "front": "**Def**: express your thoughts clearly in words. (Adj: articulate).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را به وضوح بیان کردن",
    "back": "articulate sth (FML)",
    "examples": [
      "Find it difficult to identify and articulate how they feel."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6e953a8b-5fef-4d5d-ae06-ee76a4b278a6",
    "front": "**Def**: a system or method for sending or obtaining information.\n**Farsi**: کانال ارتباطی",
    "back": "channel of communication",
    "examples": [
      "Keep channels of communication open."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbe92e56-d35a-4707-aff5-092bcd5bc10d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a building) old and in very bad condition. (SYNS run-down, ramshackle).\n**Farsi**: مخروبه/فرسوده",
    "back": "dilapidated",
    "examples": [
      "We saw this amazing, dilapidated house."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3029c4c7-a216-47ef-9ff9-b57498cfd31e",
    "front": "**Def**: in earlier times. (SYN previously).\n**Farsi**: قبلاً/در گذشته",
    "back": "formerly",
    "examples": [
      "The house was formerly owned by a wealthy family."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9decfe71-6b13-4ad3-ae58-05aa501c31e0",
    "front": "**Def**: leave a place, vehicle, etc. empty without planning to return.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را ترک کردن/رها کردن",
    "back": "abandon sth",
    "examples": [
      "The house was abandoned at the end of the century."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2c930a8f-db06-4c2e-93ef-0756248b6489",
    "front": "**Def**: keep sth in its original state or in good condition. (N: preservation).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را حفظ کردن",
    "back": "preserve sth",
    "examples": [
      "Some features are very well preserved."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "589fc36d-f26b-4ca8-b6cb-4cc7d3b08fbb",
    "front": "**Def**: gradually be destroyed through lack of care.\n**Farsi**: دچار پوسیدگی/خرابی شدن",
    "back": "fall into decay/disrepair",
    "examples": [
      "Most of it is pretty run-down and has fallen into decay."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6c73e606-0525-45cb-9b7e-0a1fc4cfb608",
    "front": "**Def**: repair and decorate an old building, car, etc. (SYN do sth up INF).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را بازسازی کردن/نوسازی کردن",
    "back": "renovate sth",
    "examples": [
      "It could be a lot of fun renovating it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b225bf17-c333-42ef-9420-f3359f96c3df",
    "front": "**Def**: buildings in which horses are kept.\n**Farsi**: اصطبل",
    "back": "stables",
    "examples": [
      "It has old stables."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8719e84f-a8d1-4ccf-9a34-60bd33880859",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely (modern) (also ultra-cautious).\n**Farsi**: فوق‌العاده (مدرن)/بسیار",
    "back": "ultra-(modern)",
    "examples": [
      "Convert it into an ultra-modern kitchen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "77bea739-a79b-402e-99ff-8c8485598ba1",
    "front": "**Def**: parts of a building that remain after it has been destroyed.\n**Farsi**: ویرانه‌ها/آثار باستانی",
    "back": "ruins",
    "examples": [
      "There are also the ruins of a medieval tower."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "941d0725-858b-48d0-b570-c33bc614ac39",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with the Middle Ages (= about 1000 to 1450).\n**Farsi**: قرون وسطایی",
    "back": "medieval",
    "examples": [
      "the ruins of a medieval tower."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a5cd1b09-0302-4b03-8f70-89fd9bf9d129",
    "front": "**Def**: find the origin or cause of sth.\n**Farsi**: منشأ چیزی را پیدا کردن/ردیابی کردن",
    "back": "trace sth (back) (to sth)",
    "examples": [
      "I'd love to trace the history of the place."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d734ae68-8bff-4c8a-9bfd-d79949fa7f9e",
    "front": "**Def**: completely new.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً نو/آکبند",
    "back": "brand new",
    "examples": [
      "Brand new Sasko G5000 mobile phone."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "774eab07-098f-41d8-8539-652e468717de",
    "front": "**Def**: featuring or introducing new ideas, methods, etc.\n**Farsi**: نوآورانه/خلاقانه",
    "back": "innovative",
    "examples": [
      "Innovative anti-snore device."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "80b9dd8c-a231-4822-93ce-0d930dadc9ca",
    "front": "**Def**: an object or piece of equipment designed to do a particular job.\n**Farsi**: دستگاه/ابزار",
    "back": "device",
    "examples": [
      "Innovative anti-snore device."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8e775dc0-ec18-4200-9c0f-5fbc11d1761c",
    "front": "**Def**: modern (out of date = old-fashioned, or without the most recent information and therefore no longer useful).\n**Farsi**: به روز/مدرن",
    "back": "up to date",
    "examples": [
      "Up-to-date guidebook to Korea."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0ebd5bc2-6392-49f7-a72c-38f70ea28e67",
    "front": "**Def**: not new; owned by sb else before.\n**Farsi**: دست دوم",
    "back": "second-hand",
    "examples": [
      "Second-hand but good as new guidebook."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b860df7b-a6b3-4260-98c4-49ac575c6a3d",
    "front": "**Def**: in very good condition (also like new ADV). (SYN in perfect condition)\n**Farsi**: مثل روز اول/بسیار سالم",
    "back": "(as) good as new",
    "examples": [
      "Second-hand but good as new guidebook."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ec8f7bdb-2a08-448f-8107-099b37b10c6c",
    "front": "**Def**: exactly what it appears to be; real. (SYN authentic).\n**Farsi**: اصل/معتبر",
    "back": "genuine",
    "examples": [
      "Genuine antique grandfather clock."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f008376-2e8f-4d6b-bf51-45950f80e75a",
    "front": "**Def**: old, and often very valuable. (N: antique).\n**Farsi**: عتیقه/قدیمی",
    "back": "antique",
    "examples": [
      "Genuine antique grandfather clock."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1ddafce4-ac2f-4d89-b796-dd0ad68aac8b",
    "front": "**Def**: new or as good as new. (SYN in perfect condition).\n**Farsi**: در وضعیت عالی/کاملاً نو",
    "back": "in mint condition",
    "examples": [
      "The 8-day mechanism is in mint condition."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "32dc93a6-e299-4415-9c09-1d87e078f2db",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a machine) repaired so that it is in good condition.\n**Farsi**: تعمیر شده/بازسازی شده",
    "back": "reconditioned",
    "examples": [
      "Fully reconditioned exercise bike."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aace8865-e83a-46b8-8a1a-045e0df10f1e",
    "front": "**Def**: materials used to wrap and protect goods sold in shops.\n**Farsi**: بسته‌بندی",
    "back": "packaging",
    "examples": [
      "Fully reconditioned exercise bike with original packaging."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d1a44826-afa0-4078-a499-414bab090981",
    "front": "**Def**: very great (a resounding success/defeat/win/victory).\n**Farsi**: چشمگیر/بسیار زیاد",
    "back": "resounding",
    "examples": [
      "Your pizza chain's been a resounding success."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "da245d9d-1956-4836-9ce1-d184ebf4b41e",
    "front": "**Def**: happen in a particular way, often unexpectedly.\n**Farsi**: (چیزی) نتیجه دادن/رخ دادن",
    "back": "turn out (well/badly)",
    "examples": [
      "How did things turn out so well for you?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c405057c-4d2a-4f25-ae6f-1066d7df6a0a",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of doing things that has brought success.\n**Farsi**: راز موفقیت (شما)",
    "back": "the secret of (your) success",
    "examples": [
      "What's the secret of your success?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7874ea65-2c0a-4835-acf7-455e32689b30",
    "front": "**Def**: an unexpected but important event (a stroke of luck).\n**Farsi**: یک شانس/موفقیت ناگهانی",
    "back": "a stroke of sth",
    "examples": [
      "I had a stroke of luck early on."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "70e451f9-7461-4319-b1c9-a51eb41979f0",
    "front": "**Def**: not make a single mistake.\n**Farsi**: هرگز اشتباه نکردن/سیر درست را پیمودن",
    "back": "not put a foot wrong",
    "examples": [
      "He never put a foot wrong."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "21af3d0f-a001-4a49-b166-ce55d68bfe56",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation or event that makes it hard for you to achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: مانع/مشکل",
    "back": "obstacle",
    "examples": [
      "There were obstacles in our way."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1eaddd52-b729-45e3-832f-17d18aa555cf",
    "front": "**Def**: stopping sb from doing sth.\n**Farsi**: مزاحم کسی/چیزی بودن",
    "back": "in sb's/the way",
    "examples": [
      "The obstacles were in our way."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c01bceb3-6f6e-431c-86d6-d85902249b12",
    "front": "**Def**: fail completely.\n**Farsi**: شکست خوردن/خراب شدن",
    "back": "come unstuck (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "We nearly came unstuck when the first restaurant was flooded."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "980398b2-2abf-41b3-9817-f60a427507b5",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in achieving a goal; become successful.\n**Farsi**: موفق شدن/به هدف رسیدن",
    "back": "make it",
    "examples": [
      "Eventually we made it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4d21c013-1641-4146-ad78-57f711819c98",
    "front": "**Def**: an important development that may lead to an achievement or agreement (make/achieve a breakthrough).\n**Farsi**: موفقیت بزرگ/دستاورد مهم",
    "back": "breakthrough",
    "examples": [
      "You made a big breakthrough after you were on that TV show."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b21850a2-5c45-479f-a338-ccd6210ebcf9",
    "front": "**Def**: become more and more successful.\n**Farsi**: موفقیت بیشتری کسب کردن/قوی‌تر شدن",
    "back": "go from strength to strength",
    "examples": [
      "We went from strength to strength after that."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "97f507f1-136e-435d-8e78-0b7a90c88224",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth succeed, especially a business or marriage.\n**Farsi**: (در کسب و کار) موفق شدن",
    "back": "make a go of sth (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Did Don make a go of the business?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b23fe3ab-6b96-4739-8998-d3c9b3795bdc",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to do or understand sth because it is too hard.\n**Farsi**: از عهده کاری برنیامدن/درک نکردن",
    "back": "out of your depth",
    "examples": [
      "He was way out of his depth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3fab6df3-ee10-419b-9782-21c72621f155",
    "front": "**Def**: difficult to do or deal with (a tricky situation/question/problem).\n**Farsi**: دشوار/پیچیده",
    "back": "tricky",
    "examples": [
      "It's a tricky situation to deal with."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "42288904-292d-4e34-97f6-a2dc2e8934fc",
    "front": "**Def**: facing difficult problems or opposition.\n**Farsi**: با مشکلات جدی مواجه بودن",
    "back": "up against it (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Sue's really up against it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "26d416b1-cdbc-459f-bc34-0ee3ad0de1f4",
    "front": "**Def**: get worse in quality, health, etc. (SYN deteriorate).\n**Farsi**: رو به زوال رفتن/بدتر شدن",
    "back": "go downhill",
    "examples": [
      "I'm afraid the marriage is going downhill."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8855733f-9a30-4438-9d12-9ebaf7fdad57",
    "front": "**Def**: receive the lowest score in an exam. (OPP come top).\n**Farsi**: کمترین نمره را آوردن",
    "back": "come bottom",
    "examples": [
      "Carla came bottom in the exams."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9687422d-6a53-4093-a40e-416fe2c20723",
    "front": "**Def**: only just succeed in passing an exam.\n**Farsi**: به سختی قبول شدن/با نمره لب مرزی قبول شدن",
    "back": "scrape through (an exam)",
    "examples": [
      "I only just scraped through."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5dbe38a4-d7ce-48df-b7f4-86754ac36950",
    "front": "**Def**: be too old to do what you used to be able to do.\n**Farsi**: (عمر) کسی گذشته بودن/پیرتر از آن بودن",
    "back": "be past it (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "That boxer is past it, surely."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d504e6a7-7ce3-4670-9cf3-14531b63b727",
    "front": "**Def**: a film, play, book, party, etc. that is not successful. (V: flop).\n**Farsi**: شکست/ناموفقیت",
    "back": "flop (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I hear the film was a flop."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "810bb53c-5c08-4271-b612-422f7ad4a359",
    "front": "**Def**: complete (used to describe sth bad). (SYN absolute).\n**Farsi**: مطلق/تمام عیار",
    "back": "unmitigated",
    "examples": [
      "An unmitigated disaster."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e2c5f833-02bc-4542-8c32-4dbbd2b91304",
    "front": "**Def**: by a large amount or 'very far'.\n**Farsi**: بسیار/خیلی زیاد",
    "back": "way (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "It cost way over $1,000."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "971fa54f-c765-4f98-9c20-85e1f94e68f5",
    "front": "**Def**: time seems to pass very quickly.\n**Farsi**: زمان به سرعت می‌گذرد",
    "back": "time flies",
    "examples": [
      "Time flies when you get older."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "919c1d62-66b0-4861-b2a5-151c61fea630",
    "front": "**Def**: belonging to a period of history from thousands of years ago.\n**Farsi**: باستانی/کهن",
    "back": "ancient",
    "examples": [
      "Reproduction ancient Egyptian statue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "60e20ef9-2c13-4a2a-9bf8-aaa46602cacf",
    "front": "**Def**: at the right time and not before.\n**Farsi**: در زمان مناسب/به موقع",
    "back": "in due course",
    "examples": [
      "I will go to university in due course."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9d9b15ca-7f0e-4eb9-98ec-cfcca12dcac5",
    "front": "**Def**: in the past but not now.\n**Farsi**: در یک مقطع زمانی (در گذشته)",
    "back": "at one time",
    "examples": [
      "At one time I wanted to be a journalist."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fa5e7ebe-87ae-47d7-bbdc-0018df5d0444",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth at the latest possible time before sth else happens. (SYN leave sth to/till the last minute).\n**Farsi**: کاری را در آخرین لحظه انجام دادن",
    "back": "do sth at the last minute",
    "examples": [
      "I do everything at the last minute."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "51e1a02f-56a5-41f7-90af-03950a4b49c8",
    "front": "**Def**: thinking now about the past, often with a different view from the one you had then. (SYN looking back).\n**Farsi**: با نگاهی به گذشته",
    "back": "in retrospect",
    "examples": [
      "In retrospect, I wish I'd gone to university."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "96525805-8a04-4831-bdf2-61a40f9339ee",
    "front": "**Def**: for a short period of time but not permanently.\n**Farsi**: فعلاً/در حال حاضر",
    "back": "for the time being",
    "examples": [
      "For the time being I'm happy where I am."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0b8a2ad9-d014-4c03-9e5b-26e6e72e5703",
    "front": "**Def**: old-fashioned in ideas, ways, etc.\n**Farsi**: عقب افتاده/قدیمی",
    "back": "behind the times",
    "examples": [
      "My parents are a bit behind the times."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e8a515c6-de08-4d79-b80f-fbd6f4c3e591",
    "front": "**Def**: gradually.\n**Farsi**: به مرور زمان",
    "back": "over time",
    "examples": [
      "I've become more tolerant over time."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b709e096-7857-4a84-b5d7-c31e7f72c450",
    "front": "**Def**: before you were born or before you can remember.\n**Farsi**: قبل از دوران (زندگی) شما",
    "back": "before your time",
    "examples": [
      "Elvis Presley was a bit before my time."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "51ea000a-5ce6-46f7-8b48-5325c663084d",
    "front": "**Def**: at a point within a period of time.\n**Farsi**: در طول (یک مقطع زمانی)",
    "back": "during",
    "examples": [
      "It rained during the day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cbf9de51-ba3c-496f-b22e-a54f8418fbb2",
    "front": "**Def**: continuously within a period of time.\n**Farsi**: در سرتاسر/در تمام مدت",
    "back": "throughout",
    "examples": [
      "It rained throughout the day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "26e2a04d-e457-4602-a8bf-e00908a9f79f",
    "front": "**Def**: a particular period of history.\n**Farsi**: عصر/دوران",
    "back": "age",
    "examples": [
      "We're living in the nuclear age."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fcdca3b3-7836-4253-836c-256c2858390c",
    "front": "**Def**: increase the length of time of sth. (OPP curtail FML).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تمدید کردن/طولانی‌تر کردن",
    "back": "extend sth",
    "examples": [
      "They're going to extend my visa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0bacc874-19e6-49fb-a372-ed63aebf99e7",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth last longer. (OPP curtail FML).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را طولانی کردن",
    "back": "prolong sth",
    "examples": [
      "The drugs will prolong her life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf905106-3037-499d-bfc4-c3bfefb95e99",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time between two events or two parts of sth, e.g. a play.\n**Farsi**: فاصله/بازه زمانی",
    "back": "interval",
    "examples": [
      "Buses run at regular intervals."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a60f492d-727b-4f11-b95b-35cbc4fbc978",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time when sth stops.\n**Farsi**: وقفه/شکاف زمانی",
    "back": "gap",
    "examples": [
      "We met again after a ten-year gap."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "93883f20-016e-4583-8797-d30f403818a5",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period of time when you stop what you are doing and rest.\n**Farsi**: استراحت/تنفس",
    "back": "break",
    "examples": [
      "I get a coffee break and lunch break at work."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2eaccf46-4bd4-41cc-b947-8a21c84b5a21",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period of time or of a particular activity.\n**Farsi**: دوره کوتاه/مدت",
    "back": "spell",
    "examples": [
      "She had a short spell working for an oil company."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "84e7fffb-fe66-4247-9200-a1a5d3aa28ef",
    "front": "**Def**: a period that forms part of an activity. A difficult period of time that sb/sth passes through (stage is also possible).\n**Farsi**: مرحله",
    "back": "stage",
    "examples": [
      "I stopped for water at one stage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6f16d5ac-02ab-4254-9879-f04cb850ca48",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time that forms part of a process or the development of sth.\n**Farsi**: فاز/مرحله",
    "back": "phase",
    "examples": [
      "It's just a phase that most teenagers go through."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "937daf97-4f82-4a56-9bb6-7a944da6b126",
    "front": "**Def**: quickly (after sth happens). In a short period of time from now. A short period after sb/sth. A short period before sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: به زودی/بیدرنگ",
    "back": "soon or shortly",
    "examples": [
      "I'll be with you soon/shortly."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "da0bd041-c8f7-4ee0-afd5-873a15a3e077",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly informal meeting or party. (Syn: get-together).\n**Farsi**: مهمانی/دورهمی",
    "back": "do (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I thought the do at Coleen's would be a good laugh."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd7c6b27-6225-4c25-852e-dea2736d59d0",
    "front": "**Def**: an enjoyable experience.\n**Farsi**: تجربه سرگرم‌کننده/خنده دار",
    "back": "a (good) laugh (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "It was a good laugh."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d51bd287-142a-4242-ac28-f05287d868b7",
    "front": "**Def**: a boring or annoying occasion or situation.\n**Farsi**: کسالت‌آور/خسته‌کننده",
    "back": "a (bit of a) drag (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "It was a bit of a drag."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3d086f4b-c8ee-4041-b7cc-0ece526f8c28",
    "front": "**Def**: bad, unpleasant, or of poor quality (a lousy film, lousy weather).\n**Farsi**: مزخرف/افتضاح",
    "back": "lousy (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Yeah, lousy I thought."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "44dc2598-5fd0-4887-af96-9bdb9425afd8",
    "front": "**Def**: a pound (£) in money (PL quid NOT quids).\n**Farsi**: پوند (اصطلاح عامیانه)",
    "back": "quid (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Asking people to pay twenty quid was a bit of a rip-off."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5cd26528-1770-4b8c-b3b2-1117c6f72a6d",
    "front": "**Def**: sometimes but not regularly. (SYN now and again).\n**Farsi**: گهگاه/هر از گاهی",
    "back": "from time to time",
    "examples": [
      "I get depressed from time to time."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "516e37c9-7b68-47b6-a4d1-ce84da6cdc22",
    "front": "**Def**: very bad or unpleasant (a vile smell). (SYN disgusting).\n**Farsi**: نفرت‌انگیز/خیلی بد",
    "back": "vile (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Who was that vile bloke?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b3563fb0-eeab-456d-b81a-69f4dffa7710",
    "front": "**Def**: a man. (SYN guy).\n**Farsi**: مرد/آدم (عام)",
    "back": "bloke (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Who was that vile bloke in the black leather jacket?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8d91bf01-c8e7-4f24-8bd5-6b14cb697672",
    "front": "**Def**: complain (about sth) in a way that annoys people.\n**Farsi**: ناله و شکایت کردن",
    "back": "moan (about sth) (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He spent ages moaning about his flatmate."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2e782ced-f814-433a-94e2-94d83f09d754",
    "front": "**Def**: a toilet.\n**Farsi**: دستشویی",
    "back": "loo (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "When I got up and went to the loo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f099880e-d803-44dc-b487-4c218fcfe278",
    "front": "**Def**: steal sth. (SYN nick sth).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را کش رفتن/دزدیدن",
    "back": "pinch sth (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He pinched my drink."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f78881b-9423-4d1e-8bcf-4df04c6ec52f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to address sb you love, and by some people in shops as a friendly way of addressing customers, particularly women.\n**Farsi**: عزیزم/عشق من (خطاب محبت‌آمیز)",
    "back": "darling/love (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "What would you like, love?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "79d4395f-e17c-48a2-b438-77c0462e3d19",
    "front": "**Def**: not having any money.\n**Farsi**: بی‌پول/ورشکسته",
    "back": "broke (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm completely broke."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5ec04455-0d18-4eb7-9d3f-bb29520f6148",
    "front": "**Def**: very hungry. (SYN dying for sth to eat).\n**Farsi**: گرسنه (خیلی)",
    "back": "starving (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "What's for lunch? I'm starving."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "41f62325-fcda-488e-a787-372bcdb1f7e2",
    "front": "**Def**: a short sleep.\n**Farsi**: چرت زدن/خواب کوتاه",
    "back": "kip (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I might have a kip after lunch."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7b7b66d3-a9e1-4abb-889e-f89b501abfa1",
    "front": "**Def**: elegant and expensive.\n**Farsi**: شیک و گران/لاکچری",
    "back": "posh (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "They stayed in a very posh hotel."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6b9321ca-947a-4c2d-99b6-71ee26cf08b6",
    "front": "**Def**: interested in things that don't concern you.\n**Farsi**: فضول/دخالت کننده",
    "back": "nosy (also nosey) (DISAPPROVING, INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm careful what I say to Cath; she's very nosy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "38ca9631-076c-4045-b052-577bf2b93ae7",
    "front": "**Def**: an infectious illness.\n**Farsi**: بیماری عفونی/ویروس",
    "back": "bug (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "She picked up a bug on holiday."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "27b30912-0c24-40ad-9880-79f61367e422",
    "front": "**Def**: deceive and trick sb, especially in order to get money from them.\n**Farsi**: کسی را فریب دادن/کلاهبرداری کردن",
    "back": "con sb (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "I think that builder conned us."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0945c219-1d35-4232-bd60-58995480c0fa",
    "front": "**Def**: criticism. (SYN stick).\n**Farsi**: انتقاد/توبیخ",
    "back": "flak (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He's taken a lot of flak over this issue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1edf3d63-a5f5-48ed-aa45-73f09bb4fdd0",
    "front": "**Def**: silly (sometimes in an amusing way).\n**Farsi**: احمقانه/مسخره",
    "back": "daft (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "It was rather a daft thing to say."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ec3dc08f-26f9-4230-a149-b2539a4e2454",
    "front": "**Def**: thanks. (SYN cheers).\n**Farsi**: ممنون (کوتاه شده)",
    "back": "ta (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Here's your change. ~ Ta."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5065413b-0daa-40a2-90f2-1d09d082d2d2",
    "front": "**Def**: causing suspicion; possibly dishonest.\n**Farsi**: مشکوک/ناصادق",
    "back": "dodgy (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "His idea sounds a bit dodgy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "02f7f03c-685a-4400-9c76-65ada46c89de",
    "front": "**Def**: calm and relaxed. (SYN easy-going).\n**Farsi**: ریلکس/آرام",
    "back": "laid-back (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "He's very laid-back."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8455a811-838b-4015-b8bf-5d3596a3e16c",
    "front": "**Def**: a large amount of noise. (SYN din).\n**Farsi**: سر و صدای زیاد/غوغا",
    "back": "racket (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "What a terrible racket!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "33b5ee6c-3284-4885-beb8-cc319176f097",
    "front": "**Def**: an action you will take if there is no other option (as a last resort SYN if all else fails).\n**Farsi**: آخرین چاره/مأمن",
    "back": "a last/final resort",
    "examples": [
      "We can borrow money if need be, but it's a last resort."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dfaa2d1c-ac3a-4f8d-87a8-785843f4ea7b",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say the disadvantages of sth are greater than the advantages.\n**Farsi**: زحمتش بیشتر از ارزشش است",
    "back": "it's more trouble than it's worth",
    "examples": [
      "Frankly it's more trouble than it's worth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "613a9b76-104c-4dc5-afca-a3e3a2bae091",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which you have the advantages of two things without any disadvantages.\n**Farsi**: بهترین وضعیت ممکن/هر دو جنبه خوب را داشتن",
    "back": "the best of both worlds",
    "examples": [
      "He's got the best of both worlds."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8c958880-0a43-4323-9319-08ee1915c1ab",
    "front": "**Def**: look stupid or be less respected because of sth you have done.\n**Farsi**: آبرو ریزی کردن/اعتبار خود را از دست دادن",
    "back": "lose face",
    "examples": [
      "She didn't want to lose face."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6889ae20-ad42-4404-968e-82fdd9c4da87",
    "front": "**Def**: remain sensible and realistic about life.\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بین بودن/خاکی ماندن",
    "back": "keep your feet on the ground",
    "examples": [
      "He'll do well as long as he keeps his feet on the ground."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c400f785-028e-49ef-963a-1d3d3a583e39",
    "front": "**Def**: relax and enjoy yourself.\n**Farsi**: راحت بودن/خوش گذراندن",
    "back": "let your hair down",
    "examples": [
      "She needs to let her hair down a bit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0d4234ea-d58c-4616-9bf0-d066e36c0b24",
    "front": "**Def**: try to do sth that will almost certainly fail.\n**Farsi**: نبرد شکست خورده را ادامه دادن/تلاش بیهوده کردن",
    "back": "fight a losing battle",
    "examples": [
      "I think she's fighting a losing battle."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "578b072a-5046-4f3e-abe3-c542d8b94796",
    "front": "**Def**: was very successful.\n**Farsi**: عالی کار کردن/مثل رؤیا عمل کردن",
    "back": "worked like a dream",
    "examples": [
      "The plan worked like a dream."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dde86ef2-3f21-4eb1-af0d-798e1c720d86",
    "front": "**Def**: not generous with money. (SYNS tight, stingy).\n**Farsi**: خسیس/پول دوست",
    "back": "tight-fisted (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Coleen is a bit tight-fisted."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3cad2d93-0e8f-45b3-b8f2-183a325a13dc",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth goes in one ear and out of the other, you forget it very quickly.\n**Farsi**: از این گوش شنیدن و از آن گوش در کردن",
    "back": "go in one ear and out (of) the other",
    "examples": [
      "New words seem to go in one ear and out the other."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a6c3f69b-d2a1-4357-ade6-76cf9753c643",
    "front": "**Def**: suddenly I cannot remember sth.\n**Farsi**: ذهن کاملاً خالی شدن/مطلب را فراموش کردن",
    "back": "my mind goes (a complete) blank",
    "examples": [
      "When I want to say something, my mind goes a complete blank."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0c65872e-67a6-4abd-9966-967c405aa504",
    "front": "**Def**: be successful (get somewhere = make progress; get nowhere = make no progress).\n**Farsi**: موفق شدن/به هدف رسیدن",
    "back": "get there",
    "examples": [
      "You'll get there in the end."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a16ebb0f-fedd-4f16-8508-84f7e4a46040",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that it is not useful doing sth. (SYNS there's no point in + -ing, it's no use + -ing).\n**Farsi**: بیهوده است که...",
    "back": "it's no good + -ing",
    "examples": [
      "It's no good moaning about it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "65fbbb1d-1cad-4bf7-bd7d-7033385726cc",
    "front": "**Def**: I (/you/he, etc.) need sth.\n**Farsi**: احتیاج داشتن به چیزی",
    "back": "I (you/he, etc.) could do with sth",
    "examples": [
      "Maybe I could do with some extra lessons."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0d40554a-c423-4e01-b694-4db4ff411838",
    "front": "**Def**: be thinking of sb/sth for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: کسی/چیزی را در نظر داشتن",
    "back": "have sb/sth in mind",
    "examples": [
      "Do you have anyone in mind?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "62eb644d-8728-4c23-9582-569cd7b0870e",
    "front": "**Def**: without thinking about sth carefully.\n**Farsi**: بدون فکر/همینطوری",
    "back": "off the top of my head",
    "examples": [
      "Not off the top of my head, no."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bf06fd2e-77b9-4dc2-81fa-7d4ae404456f",
    "front": "**Def**: used when advising sb what to do. (SYN the best thing (to do is ...)).\n**Farsi**: بهترین کار (برای شما) این است که",
    "back": "your best bet (is to ...)",
    "examples": [
      "Your best bet is to talk to your teacher."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "09489e24-7d1e-49a7-9cda-df88681ac1c8",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you don't expect sth to happen even though sb said it would.\n**Farsi**: زیاد امیدوار نباش",
    "back": "Don't hold your breath",
    "examples": [
      "Bob's coming, isn't he? Don't hold your breath."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "fb4a58f4-6c05-4a94-8382-2c2ab740d7f8",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize you are keen to do sth.\n**Farsi**: حتماً/بله که",
    "back": "You bet",
    "examples": [
      "Are you going to the party? You bet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a9c9315d-db8f-4b11-b56b-74c7c6f3d26e",
    "front": "**Def**: used to agree completely with what sb has just said.\n**Farsi**: حرفت کاملاً درست است",
    "back": "You can say that again",
    "examples": [
      "It's very cold today. You can say that again."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f2d6a16e-b92a-459c-9f29-b6964e7a251c",
    "front": "**Def**: used to express your disappointment that sth is not going to happen.\n**Farsi**: از این شانس‌ها نداریم",
    "back": "No such luck",
    "examples": [
      "Have you got Saturday off? No such luck, I'm afraid."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d9d47ce7-6945-4842-a3e0-b504884749c9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you don't know sth. (SYNS Don't ask me, Your guess is as good as mine).\n**Farsi**: کوچکترین ایده‌ای ندارم",
    "back": "I haven't the faintest idea",
    "examples": [
      "Where's Patsy? I haven't the faintest idea."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "264f7e0c-8345-4297-838c-d716db0d9577",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you have had a hard day.\n**Farsi**: امروز روز سختی بود",
    "back": "it's been one of those days",
    "examples": [
      "You look very stressed. Yes, it's been one of those days."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f4523310-00db-4ba3-9033-fd691ebf545f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say there is no reason for sb not to do sth.\n**Farsi**: چیزی برای از دست دادن نداری",
    "back": "You've got nothing to lose",
    "examples": [
      "Shall I apply for that job? You've got nothing to lose."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b46dc5ad-38e7-491f-8cd3-e20ea006b73d",
    "front": "**Def**: used when several unpleasant or unfortunate things happen on the same day.\n**Farsi**: امروز روز تو نیست",
    "back": "It's not your day",
    "examples": [
      "I hurt my toe, then I burnt my hand. Oh dear. It's not your day, is it?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "99e30606-cd10-4ea5-8198-684290242911",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is not at all possible or not allowed. (SYN no chance).\n**Farsi**: محال است/به هیچ وجه",
    "back": "No way",
    "examples": [
      "Can we go in if we're not members? No way."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "736239a6-7eff-4bb0-a6f1-6881dc1267b0",
    "front": "**Def**: used to add politeness to a question. (Also: Do you happen to know if they're married?).\n**Farsi**: احتمالاً/اگر شانسی باشد",
    "back": "by any chance",
    "examples": [
      "Do you know if they're married, by any chance?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f57a6042-d3de-4cfe-aa3b-536c3b281ae5",
    "front": "**Def**: used before a question which you think may be sensitive.\n**Farsi**: اگر ناراحت نمی‌شوی بپرسم",
    "back": "If you don't mind my/me asking",
    "examples": [
      "If you don't mind my asking, how much did it cost?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "44a83581-02ff-4f70-ac51-9a05aad51427",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce an explanation, and often one that suggests there is a problem.\n**Farsi**: نکته این است که",
    "back": "the thing is",
    "examples": [
      "We'd like to see you, but the thing is, we don't know what time we'll get there."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "880bf376-e720-4020-8db1-050a319555e4",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize the comparative; equally good, bad, interesting, etc.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً به اندازه... خوب است",
    "back": "every bit as good as",
    "examples": [
      "I think the film is every bit as good as his last one."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c69573e3-c05b-40e4-91f0-9273737c82f2",
    "front": "**Def**: very embarrassed.\n**Farsi**: مثل لبو سرخ (خیلی شرمنده)",
    "back": "as red as a beetroot",
    "examples": [
      "Sally went as red as a beetroot."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a4abbd0-5ae4-4158-95d8-1a9ff66c9833",
    "front": "**Def**: spend time with other people in a friendly way. sociable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: اجتماعی شدن، معاشرت کردن",
    "back": "socialize (v)",
    "examples": [
      "Do you want to make new friends and socialize more effectively?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9c6e2736-3518-4fcb-a589-7b95bc196047",
    "front": "**Def**: concerned with or supporting the protection of the environment.\n**Farsi**: سبز (طرفدار محیط زیست)",
    "back": "green",
    "examples": [
      "turn out green chefs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1c87664d-bdef-4a53-9e29-7072c0532a73",
    "front": "**Def**: an action you will take if there is no other option. (SYN as a last resort)\n**Farsi**: اگر هیچ چیز دیگری کار نکند",
    "back": "if all else fails",
    "examples": [
      "So you may have to sell your car. ~ Yes, if all else fails."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "63a877bc-84de-4f02-a2c3-61112954c937",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize the fact that sth is not surprising.\n**Farsi**: جای تعجب نیست که",
    "back": "no wonder",
    "examples": [
      "He's been working since 7 o'clock this morning, so no wonder he's tired."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4a808372-f3c7-45af-a39e-b55263a3b1b9",
    "front": "**Def**: used after wh- questions to indicate surprise, and sometimes annoyance, about sth.\n**Farsi**: در کجای زمین (تاکید بر تعجب)",
    "back": "Where on earth",
    "examples": [
      "Where on earth did you get those boots?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "02fa19d4-c2e2-4272-aa7b-caaba01f53a9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is true if there are no other factors affecting it.\n**Farsi**: اگر همه شرایط مساوی باشد",
    "back": "all things being equal",
    "examples": [
      "I would say, all things being equal, that women are better communicators than men."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4f12199b-794e-49fb-baaf-c6335615ecb5",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say, often with slight annoyance, that you don't know the reason or don't understand it.\n**Farsi**: به دلایلی (که نمی‌دانم)",
    "back": "for some reason",
    "examples": [
      "The room is empty but, for some reason, we're not allowed to use it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ddb88fe9-41da-4269-a825-22b8db3d0624",
    "front": "**Def**: used to agree reluctantly that sth is true.\n**Farsi**: باید اعتراف کنم",
    "back": "I have to admit",
    "examples": [
      "I have to admit, he's very good at his job."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4f867a15-acb2-4f4b-9884-5dcf969a654c",
    "front": "**Def**: from one place to another and then back again, many times.\n**Farsi**: عقب و جلو/مرتب رفت و آمد کردن",
    "back": "back and forth",
    "examples": [
      "We've been going back and forth all day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b031b3f7-e5eb-4ed4-a309-4ff1b516b65f",
    "front": "**Def**: for a long time.\n**Farsi**: طولانی و سخت/با دقت زیاد",
    "back": "long and hard",
    "examples": [
      "I thought long and hard before taking the job."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4cd75c28-b223-4d42-b7f3-f7866a94a48e",
    "front": "**Def**: at some time in the future.\n**Farsi**: دیر یا زود",
    "back": "sooner or later",
    "examples": [
      "They'll be here sooner or later."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a17b4b6e-cb59-4757-b4a0-acb566859d5a",
    "front": "**Def**: with the back where the front should be.\n**Farsi**: پشت و رو/برعکس",
    "back": "back to front",
    "examples": [
      "You're wearing your jumper back to front."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c108c492-38e8-4c2e-8860-f3276098641b",
    "front": "**Def**: busy and noisy activity.\n**Farsi**: شلوغی و هیاهو",
    "back": "hustle and bustle",
    "examples": [
      "I enjoy the hustle and bustle of city life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dd903d48-cb5d-4e4c-b7dd-a315816cd20b",
    "front": "**Def**: a process of trying to solve a problem in different ways until you are successful.\n**Farsi**: آزمون و خطا",
    "back": "trial and error",
    "examples": [
      "I learnt how to use a computer by trial and error."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "855ebbbc-eebc-47f9-b55e-9b6a34697633",
    "front": "**Def**: things you want to achieve.\n**Farsi**: اهداف و مقاصد",
    "back": "aims and objectives",
    "examples": [
      "What are our aims and objectives?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dba88300-d21e-4c7a-a249-af6a4b470e76",
    "front": "**Def**: rules.\n**Farsi**: قواعد و مقررات",
    "back": "rules and regulations",
    "examples": [
      "That's against the rules and regulations."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "37a4cbfb-50dc-4cd5-b59a-bc98b520bc1e",
    "front": "**Def**: safe and peaceful conditions in society when people obey the law.\n**Farsi**: نظم و قانون",
    "back": "law and order",
    "examples": [
      "Who is responsible for law and order?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "20854a0b-8dea-45b7-809e-928425aab8e3",
    "front": "**Def**: happy and lively.\n**Farsi**: شاد و سرزنده",
    "back": "bright and cheerful",
    "examples": [
      "Max was very bright and cheerful today."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8dea23dc-f8ba-4587-9dd4-6a916d4ff42d",
    "front": "**Def**: safely; not harmed, damaged, lost, etc.\n**Farsi**: سالم و سلامت",
    "back": "safe and sound",
    "examples": [
      "The children got home safe and sound."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "49147b13-3741-4fea-931a-da55ebf948be",
    "front": "**Def**: bored with or annoyed about sth, and wanting it to stop.\n**Farsi**: خسته و دلزده از",
    "back": "sick and tired of (SYN fed up with sth)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm sick and tired of this weather."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "28e7c46e-b1e1-4d77-a5f6-aec9cd30d447",
    "front": "**Def**: choose only those things that you like or want.\n**Farsi**: گلچین کردن/انتخاب کردن (بدون محدودیت)",
    "back": "pick and choose",
    "examples": [
      "He can't really afford to pick and choose."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c859c7b5-6464-4848-86ef-eaa38da33a23",
    "front": "**Def**: push in a rough way.\n**Farsi**: هل دادن و تنه زدن",
    "back": "pushing and shoving",
    "examples": [
      "They were pushing and shoving behind us."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "118cb692-f4bd-447a-8b3a-ccbf406c9b2b",
    "front": "**Def**: well behaved.\n**Farsi**: مثل طلا بودن (خیلی خوب رفتار کردن)",
    "back": "as good as gold",
    "examples": [
      "The kids were as good as gold today."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "54806c7e-1744-4dd0-856f-ffa2f5dcdce5",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely light.\n**Farsi**: مثل پر سبک",
    "back": "as light as a feather",
    "examples": [
      "She was as light as a feather."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "874c813a-5020-4c18-b307-038a3fa8b776",
    "front": "**Def**: cannot see well.\n**Farsi**: مثل خفاش کور (خیلی ضعیف دیدن)",
    "back": "blind as a bat (humorously)",
    "examples": [
      "I'm afraid I'm blind as a bat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "46ddda5b-5c10-475a-a14a-e1221edfd978",
    "front": "**Def**: cannot hear well.\n**Farsi**: مثل ستون کر (هیچ چیز نشنیدن)",
    "back": "deaf as a post (humorously)",
    "examples": [
      "My father is deaf as a post."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "45cd4787-e69e-462b-aa7d-4f7be403b0d7",
    "front": "**Def**: very strong.\n**Farsi**: مثل گاو نر قوی",
    "back": "as strong as an ox",
    "examples": [
      "He's as strong as an ox."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0e3cbfc-3b7e-491a-ad14-2ad194cde598",
    "front": "**Def**: very thin.\n**Farsi**: مثل چنگک لاغر",
    "back": "as thin as a rake",
    "examples": [
      "My sister's as thin as a rake."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4ed21b22-e6d5-4fd6-8429-d7e17d4dc772",
    "front": "**Def**: very quiet.\n**Farsi**: مثل موش ساکت",
    "back": "as quiet as a mouse",
    "examples": [
      "The baby's been as quiet as a mouse."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8111807c-1c9a-4373-82e7-7e18b8276cea",
    "front": "**Def**: white with fear or illness.\n**Farsi**: مثل گچ سفید (از ترس یا بیماری)",
    "back": "as white as a sheet",
    "examples": [
      "Ken went as white as a sheet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "55cc7634-0828-41fc-a9bc-9d2da199a13c",
    "front": "**Def**: used before giving sb surprising or exciting news.\n**Farsi**: حدس بزن چی شده!",
    "back": "Guess what!",
    "examples": [
      "Guess what! Ed and Sue are getting married."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ff230c16-1348-4c75-8909-c726474be231",
    "front": "**Def**: communicate with them clearly.\n**Farsi**: منظور خود را واضح رساندن، تفهیم کردن",
    "back": "get your ideas across",
    "examples": [
      "If you get your ideas across to someone, you communicate with them clearly."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "22b759fc-36fb-49d3-a14c-3611cba956e7",
    "front": "**Def**: interrupt a conversation.\n**Farsi**: میان صحبت کسی پریدن، دخالت کردن",
    "back": "butt in (on a conversation)",
    "examples": [
      "If you butt in on a conversation, you interrupt a conversation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b9ede7f3-e5af-4f56-9e6f-98fedbc9922d",
    "front": "**Def**: prolong it (= make it longer than necessary).\n**Farsi**: به درازا کشاندن، طول دادن",
    "back": "drag out (a discussion)",
    "examples": [
      "If someone drags out a discussion, they prolong it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9c3ec86d-981f-4e3e-ae2b-d0e844909c23",
    "front": "**Def**: confess to it (= admit you did sth wrong).\n**Farsi**: اعتراف کردن، گردن گرفتن (خطا)",
    "back": "own up (to something)",
    "examples": [
      "If you own up to something, you confess to it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3fc0a6e3-a9d8-4e17-a533-49b2aa4d19ee",
    "front": "**Def**: criticize you for sth you have done.\n**Farsi**: سرزنش کردن، ایراد گرفتن، غر زدن",
    "back": "go on at you",
    "examples": [
      "If someone goes on at you, they criticize you for sth you have done."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7c48ca16-ff0e-455e-9020-be82862268b6",
    "front": "**Def**: retaliate (against them).\n**Farsi**: تلافی کردن، مقابله به مثل کردن",
    "back": "hit back at someone",
    "examples": [
      "If you hit back at someone who has criticized you, you retaliate (against them)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e3068a20-3907-435a-8ed0-d55e4be7fa64",
    "front": "**Def**: abolish it.\n**Farsi**: لغو کردن، منسوخ کردن",
    "back": "do away with (a tax)",
    "examples": [
      "If the government does away with a tax, it abolishes it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bb7aeafb-f42d-4b9b-a854-73d2bc71b449",
    "front": "**Def**: cancel it.\n**Farsi**: لغو کردن",
    "back": "call off (a meeting)",
    "examples": [
      "If you call off a meeting, you cancel it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "07e222bb-f3bb-4b13-bbb0-347cbeaafefa",
    "front": "**Def**: compensate for it (= do sth good to balance the bad effects of it).\n**Farsi**: جبران کردن",
    "back": "make up for something",
    "examples": [
      "If you make up for something, you compensate for it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1a5dc02e-69b0-45f7-bdfe-3b8b5df46086",
    "front": "**Def**: be deceived by it.\n**Farsi**: فریب خوردن، گول خوردن",
    "back": "be taken in by charm",
    "examples": [
      "If you are taken in by someone's charm, you are deceived by it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c793973e-770f-4707-ab04-582bef3a088f",
    "front": "**Def**: be reconciled with them (= become friends with them after a disagreement).\n**Farsi**: آشتی کردن، دوباره دوست شدن",
    "back": "make it up (with them)",
    "examples": [
      "If you have a row with someone and then make it up with them, you are reconciled with them."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5bc2b517-e54c-41e6-a4a6-65a5b5e23a27",
    "front": "**Def**: dismantle it (also take it to pieces).\n**Farsi**: از هم باز کردن، پیاده کردن (دستگاه)",
    "back": "take a machine apart",
    "examples": [
      "If you take a machine apart, you dismantle it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "04447445-7187-4228-9916-3518330d9759",
    "front": "**Def**: meet sb by chance.\n**Farsi**: تصادفاً کسی را دیدن",
    "back": "bump into sb",
    "examples": [
      "I bumped into Sue in town last week."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "20d4363a-cbae-4d6a-82cd-443145c65250",
    "front": "**Def**: ask sb how sb else is, or what they are doing.\n**Farsi**: احوال کسی را پرسیدن",
    "back": "ask after sb",
    "examples": [
      "She was asking after you."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7b56faba-60e4-4ea2-a10a-251b0bf9a307",
    "front": "**Def**: arrive where you have arranged to meet sb. SYN turn up.\n**Farsi**: حاضر شدن، آمدن",
    "back": "show up",
    "examples": [
      "She didn't show up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b1e53ea9-2d8f-4f8a-a035-de3abae6c517",
    "front": "**Def**: happen unexpectedly. SYN come up.\n**Farsi**: ناگهانی رخ دادن، پیش آمد کردن",
    "back": "crop up",
    "examples": [
      "Something must've cropped up."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2321e376-2086-43f6-b22d-df8b6b525506",
    "front": "**Def**: become sick or ill with sth. SYN catch sth.\n**Farsi**: مریض شدن، مبتلا شدن",
    "back": "go down with sth",
    "examples": [
      "I realized I must be going down with the flu."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c2cb8cbb-ece6-4136-81d1-cf5218953d64",
    "front": "**Def**: get rid of sth, such as an illness or a problem.\n**Farsi**: از شر چیزی خلاص شدن، رفع کردن (بیماری)",
    "back": "shake sth off",
    "examples": [
      "I was hoping to shake it off with painkillers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "666d6bfc-05f5-424e-9667-860ccab2979d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a pain, a feeling, or an effect) gradually disappear or stop.\n**Farsi**: از بین رفتن تدریجی (اثر، درد)",
    "back": "wear off",
    "examples": [
      "Once the effects wore off, I felt dreadful."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cb66f642-0b96-4bf8-99d3-a6d27e138b0d",
    "front": "**Def**: miss an opportunity to do or have sth.\n**Farsi**: فرصتی را از دست دادن",
    "back": "miss out on sth",
    "examples": [
      "I even missed out on my best friend's wedding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "499f4152-25c0-4429-9048-fddaf7d62c99",
    "front": "**Def**: learn a new skill easily and without effort.\n**Farsi**: یاد گرفتن، آموختن (مهارت)",
    "back": "pick sth up (skill)",
    "examples": [
      "My brother's brilliant at picking up languages."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "783300cf-f8d4-4c8c-bb50-b9d7386a564c",
    "front": "**Def**: If you get by in a language, you can speak at a basic level.\n**Farsi**: در حد پایه از پس زبانی برآمدن",
    "back": "get by (language)",
    "examples": [
      "He can get by in German."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c9a3e8d8-36fb-46b1-8a26-69f84246146e",
    "front": "**Def**: become completely understood or able to be remembered.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً درک شدن، جا افتادن (مطلب)",
    "back": "sink in",
    "examples": [
      "It takes ages for things to sink in."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5b6915d9-f0bd-46e0-bcde-13a89d2c50d5",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to work in a determined way to achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: با پشتکار ادامه دادن، به کاری چسبیدن",
    "back": "stick at sth",
    "examples": [
      "I've really stuck at it and I feel I'm getting somewhere now."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d7ed26b3-a06d-4224-a97d-1d0944561eba",
    "front": "**Def**: raise the topic.\n**Farsi**: موضوعی را مطرح کردن",
    "back": "bring a topic up",
    "examples": [
      "If you bring a topic up in a conversation, you raise the topic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b07e9ffe-2e4b-4abd-b9bf-9aef118da39d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to suffer from sth (also accident-prone).\n**Farsi**: مستعد، متمایل (به چیزی)",
    "back": "prone to sth",
    "examples": [
      "children were prone to certain infectious diseases"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c2bde70d-3670-4aad-9493-9f7154099dc5",
    "front": "**Def**: Special words and phrases used by people who do the same kind of work. (OFTEN DISAPPROVING)\n**Farsi**: اصطلاحات تخصصی، ژارگون",
    "back": "jargon",
    "examples": [
      "She used a lot of technical jargon in her explanation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40bc8add-2b7f-4263-9984-0f7b10f313eb",
    "front": "**Def**: live without quarrelling with others.\n**Farsi**: در صلح زندگی کردن با",
    "back": "live at peace with sb",
    "examples": [
      "to be able to live at peace with my neighbours."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bebab085-5684-4714-9f1f-fc8ab4076e1e",
    "front": "**Def**: find shelter or protection from trouble or danger.\n**Farsi**: پناه بردن، پناه گرفتن",
    "back": "seek/take refuge (from sth/sb)",
    "examples": [
      "The men had to take refuge in the French embassy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f8823aff-2084-42ab-9d7f-ae0f66473181",
    "front": "**Def**: an opinion about sb/sth that is not based on reason or experience, especially a dislike based on race, religion, etc.\n**Farsi**: پیش‌داوری، تعصب",
    "back": "prejudice (against sb/sth)",
    "examples": [
      "There is no prejudice against people"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3ad29f87-84c6-4830-aa40-0e782ec16449",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which sb treats sb else unfairly in order to make money from their work.\n**Farsi**: استثمار، بهره‌کشی",
    "back": "exploitation DISAPPROVING",
    "examples": [
      "trafficking people for criminal exploitation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d9ba7260-41f0-46f4-8f13-58648eab0630",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of keeping things secret (protect patient/client confidentiality).\n**Farsi**: محرمانه بودن",
    "back": "confidentiality N",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from confidential"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "0e4da278-c991-4359-8d53-51b45a9ad6dc",
    "front": "**Def**: the right to take part in deciding sth (give sb a say / have a say in sth).\n**Farsi**: حق رأی، حق نظر",
    "back": "say N",
    "examples": [
      "give neighbourhoods a say in local decisions."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1a43b2be-14ea-486a-bead-1b833c007cec",
    "front": "**Def**: bad news, especially when something unfortunate has happened.\n**Farsi**: ضربه، خبر بد",
    "back": "blow (bad news)",
    "examples": [
      "Injury blow for United."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eaf854d0-66a8-47a3-a6a6-ea04967e4815",
    "front": "**Def**: make a small hole in something (puncture skin / a tyre).\n**Farsi**: سوراخ کردن، پنچر کردن",
    "back": "puncture sth",
    "examples": [
      "The nail punctured the tire."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6324378f-8622-4cea-b581-ebb8c294d63b",
    "front": "**Def**: without people's awareness or knowledge (in private, not in public).\n**Farsi**: پشت صحنه، مخفیانه",
    "back": "behind the scenes",
    "examples": [
      "They were working behind the scenes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "315b652f-a53a-4468-85ca-ea24db976d92",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of helping to cure somebody with drug or alcohol addiction (short for rehabilitation).\n**Farsi**: ترک اعتیاد، بازپروری",
    "back": "rehab",
    "examples": [
      "He checked into rehab."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8e4c114d-a7f8-41ad-b52c-e1dc8cef1fdd",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which important people behave in a dishonest or immoral way that shocks people.\n**Farsi**: رسوایی، آبروریزی",
    "back": "scandal",
    "examples": [
      "The scandal over the politician's conduct."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "70f41e5f-b649-405a-8b9a-3483fa055954",
    "front": "**Def**: the time when problems have become so great that somebody can no longer deal with them.\n**Farsi**: نقطه شکست، آستانه تحمل",
    "back": "breaking point",
    "examples": [
      "He was pushed to his breaking point."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f74592a6-5290-421a-ac14-76faa2f0ec5b",
    "front": "**Def**: DISAPPROVING persuade or tempt sb to do sth by offering them a reward. SYN entice sb.\n**Farsi**: اغوا کردن، وسوسه کردن",
    "back": "lure sb",
    "examples": [
      "The company is trying to lure passengers away from its rivals."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1946c82b-e5fa-47a0-8655-f4ef2d95df5a",
    "front": "**Def**: increase in value after a period when it has fallen. SYN recover / bounce back.\n**Farsi**: بازگشت (ارزش)، افزایش دوباره",
    "back": "rally",
    "examples": [
      "The pound rallied later in the day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ad2ed41a-fa37-4497-b1d0-a2efaf1cf749",
    "front": "**Def**: not have information about what is happening or where sth/sb is. OPP keep track of sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: رد چیزی را گم کردن، بی‌اطلاع بودن",
    "back": "lose track of sth/sb",
    "examples": [
      "Lose track of what you spend."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ec0ab9-e2ae-4fa7-b04b-791718572a24",
    "front": "**Def**: take one number from another to calculate the difference. SYN take sth away from sth.\n**Farsi**: کم کردن، تفریق کردن",
    "back": "subtract sth from sth",
    "examples": [
      "Subtract the expenses from the income."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "e58ed5f5-ba3f-4a09-806c-66be34fa89cc",
    "front": "**Def**: given so many things that you cannot deal with them. SYNS overwhelmed, swamped.\n**Farsi**: غرق در چیزی، لبریز از چیزی",
    "back": "inundated (with sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Workers say they are inundated with a never-ending stream of emails."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a9c6e726-c894-4dab-a866-c22153c68f71",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth to solve a problem.\n**Farsi**: رسیدگی کردن به یک مشکل، حل کردن",
    "back": "tackle a problem",
    "examples": [
      "A positive way to tackle the problem."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "caad9d0c-c0c7-41e8-816d-746dcd87e1ab",
    "front": "**Def**: tell the truth and not hide any important facts.\n**Farsi**: با کسی روراست بودن/صادق بودن",
    "back": "level with sb (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "Level with your child by being honest."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "36fc487f-f2f3-4fb7-97e9-175f440e70d7",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that happened in the past which is seen as a rule or example to be followed by others in a similar situation.\n**Farsi**: سابقه، الگو، رویه",
    "back": "precedent",
    "examples": [
      "It could set a precedent for other groups."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "78cce957-0bf1-43c9-871f-afa3131cb22b",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which a machine doesn't work because sth is stuck in one position (a paper jam). jam v (the photocopier keeps jamming).\n**Farsi**: گیر کردن، انسداد (مثلاً کاغذ در دستگاه)",
    "back": "jam",
    "examples": [
      "Create a paper jam in the photocopier."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1d0872ca-84aa-430a-8da3-9417475c0ec1",
    "front": "**Def**: say or do sth that you know will annoy sb so that they react angrily. SYN goad sb. provocation N.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن، برانگیختن خشم",
    "back": "provoke sb (into sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Phil, who is easily provoked, joined in."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dc5ba3d7-3e27-4893-8c49-8f238c9e661e",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb feel confused because they don't understand sth. (Syns: baffle sb, confound sb FML. Adj: puzzled)\n**Farsi**: کسی را گیج کردن/متحیر ساختن",
    "back": "puzzle sb",
    "examples": [
      "Tell the truth so as to puzzle and confound your adversaries."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2242d78d-2a29-4065-b0f1-434dd3759ff0",
    "front": "**Def**: say or do sth that makes sb less worried. (SYN set sb's mind at rest).\n**Farsi**: به کسی اطمینان خاطر دادن/دلگرمی دادن",
    "back": "reassure sb",
    "examples": [
      "Reassure them that you're behind them 100 per cent."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3dba047c-c560-480a-9021-a2507dd336f0",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing made as a copy of an earlier object or style. (V: reproduce sth).\n**Farsi**: بازتولید/کپی",
    "back": "reproduction",
    "examples": [
      "Reproduction ancient Egyptian statue."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ed94e602-81c7-425a-9226-ed2d3bdf3b20",
    "front": "**Def**: If a person in public life makes a comeback, they start doing sth again which they had stopped doing.\n**Farsi**: بازگشت به صحنه/فعالیت مجدد",
    "back": "comeback",
    "examples": [
      "He still wants to make a comeback."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dc1dcae1-8249-4fca-8eab-92747e9f78f9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you think sb's behaviour is rude or inappropriate. (SYN What a cheek!).\n**Farsi**: چه رویی!/عجب جرأتی!",
    "back": "What a nerve! (INF)",
    "examples": [
      "What a nerve!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1af4ff-8e97-4099-8fc7-78f6c8cde7f4",
    "front": "**Def**: claim that they are rich (= say that they are rich even though it may not be true).\n**Farsi**: ادعا کردن، وانمود کردن",
    "back": "make out that they're rich",
    "examples": [
      "If someone makes out that they're rich, they claim that they are rich."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "bde0ad76-e8db-43be-b11b-dae5935f83e9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to change the conversation to a different topic. SYN by the way.\n**Farsi**: راستی، اتفاقاً (تغییر موضوع)",
    "back": "incidentally",
    "examples": [
      "Incidentally, do you know how Marek's getting on?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dcf56bf2-5cc4-4286-ab66-f07eeb7b035b",
    "front": "**Def**: a written statement by a political party saying what they believe in and what they intend to do.\n**Farsi**: مرام‌نامه، بیانیه انتخاباتی",
    "back": "manifesto",
    "examples": [
      "Independent Party manifesto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "aaae480e-4315-4ee4-8238-6bae24f06685",
    "front": "**Def**: an extra and usually bad effect that a drug has on you.\n**Farsi**: عارضه جانبی",
    "back": "side effect",
    "examples": [
      "Possible side effects may include stomach disorders."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1ee15531-aebb-4bdf-b15b-186fd8a4d678",
    "front": "**Def**: used to add a further comment which is usually a contrast or a surprise, but can also be an explanation. SYN still. (INF)\n**Farsi**: البته، با این حال، اما یادت باشد",
    "back": "mind you",
    "examples": [
      "I'm not very keen on the flat. Mind you, it's better than my last place."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c3e66aa0-7c01-493b-b689-847f22aa408f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce information which is true but surprising.\n**Farsi**: باور کنی یا نه",
    "back": "believe it or not",
    "examples": [
      "He doesn't look rich, but believe it or not, he owns a castle in Bavaria."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a14cadd6-89c2-4891-904d-3de8c3d1a6a8",
    "front": "**Def**: make a part of the body or skin more active.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن",
    "back": "stimulate sth (V)",
    "examples": [
      "Stimulate the skin by gently patting the cheeks."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "8bfa6edd-54b2-4d9a-a342-25d60571bfc3",
    "front": "**Def**: in a very energetic and active way. SYN energetically.\n**Farsi**: پرانرژی، با قدرت",
    "back": "vigorously (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "Massage the scalp vigorously."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "7e6e8483-1290-4a4d-b84e-7b02dd60744e",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant, distinctive smell.\n**Farsi**: عطر، بوی مطبوع",
    "back": "aroma (N)",
    "examples": [
      "The aroma of fresh coffee."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "91c25e64-ad4a-4aa2-990f-c92aa2be7e3a",
    "front": "**Def**: very unpleasant. SYN disgusting.\n**Farsi**: منزجر کننده، چندش‌آور",
    "back": "revolting (ADJ)",
    "examples": [
      "This fish smells revolting."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "158dfeba-76e7-4d0b-aaf1-67d03ef3723b",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of red spots on the skin, caused by an illness or a reaction to sth.\n**Farsi**: بثورات/جوش پوستی",
    "back": "rash",
    "examples": [
      "That's a nasty rash on your arm."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dbe0feae-c821-4198-8d68-3549891ece80",
    "front": "**Def**: mix a solid with a liquid until it becomes part of it.\n**Farsi**: حل کردن (در مایع)",
    "back": "dissolve sth (in sth)",
    "examples": [
      "Tablets must be dissolved in water."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "201d665d-9e58-4194-8268-6e5bf480dde1",
    "front": "**Def**: a quality or feature of sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی/صفت",
    "back": "attribute",
    "examples": [
      "spontaneity is a positive attribute."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "17ff5111-43a9-4515-8bdb-b1c5981fd72a",
    "front": "**Def**: thinking you are very important, clever, etc.\n**Farsi**: خودبین/متکبر",
    "back": "conceited (DISAPPROVING)",
    "examples": [
      "a bit conceited."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "19f4c7d2-2369-4dc3-995c-f3e48fbd1285",
    "front": "**Def**: able to do things by being clever, but not always honest.\n**Farsi**: حیله‌گر/زیرک",
    "back": "cunning (SYN crafty)",
    "examples": [
      "being cunning, or impulsive."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "5ba62fb3-d87d-42cb-97a3-78fdc876f60a",
    "front": "**Def**: very upset.\n**Farsi**: دلشکسته/به شدت ناراحت",
    "back": "devastated (SYN heartbroken)",
    "examples": [
      "I was devastated when she left me."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6110e4f3-a1bf-4db8-b221-5b7357c92287",
    "front": "**Def**: an act of sheer (= absolute) desperation N.\n**Farsi**: استیصال/درماندگی مطلق",
    "back": "desperation",
    "examples": [
      "Jumping into the freezing water was an act of sheer desperation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d29c043d-abb8-49d6-a004-07f6c6e68c3b",
    "front": "**Def**: stop yourself from having or expressing feelings.\n**Farsi**: سرکوب کردن احساسات",
    "back": "suppress your feelings",
    "examples": [
      "unhealthy to suppress your feelings."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "31eebdc0-a3ea-482c-bac9-2d5b284c3ecc",
    "front": "**Def**: used for saying that sth is certain to happen. inevitable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: به ناچار/اجتناب‌ناپذیر",
    "back": "inevitably (ADV)",
    "examples": [
      "inevitably it put a strain on my relationship."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "6a5b1665-6c8b-4e15-9e8b-7fb1042d2cda",
    "front": "**Def**: a mixture of good and bad things in life or a relationship.\n**Farsi**: فراز و نشیب/پستی بلندی",
    "back": "ups and downs",
    "examples": [
      "Vince and I still have our ups and downs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "94432955-eaec-4773-be0b-8062796e7509",
    "front": "**Def**: recognize sth and welcome it. appreciation N.\n**Farsi**: قدردانی کردن/ارزش قائل شدن",
    "back": "appreciate sth (v)",
    "examples": [
      "he appreciates the sacrifices I've made."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9594c23d-4256-4c44-a784-294558a1526b",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb the enthusiasm and desire to do sth. inspiration N. inspirational ADJ.\n**Farsi**: الهام بخشیدن",
    "back": "inspire sb (v)",
    "examples": [
      "she inspired me to devote my life."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "153aa432-8d58-45f6-a271-abfc91b20dc3",
    "front": "**Def**: a person you admire and learn from.\n**Farsi**: الگو/سرمشق",
    "back": "role model",
    "examples": [
      "other role models are less influential."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "677a04e7-cfa3-4256-b428-5988bbb8e8f3",
    "front": "**Def**: work as hard as everyone else in a job or activity.\n**Farsi**: وظیفه خود را انجام دادن",
    "back": "pull your weight (SYN do your fair share)",
    "examples": [
      "Getting messy teens to pull their weight."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "72696f3f-4d17-4e69-9fb5-5983187edf00",
    "front": "**Def**: contributes an equal or expected amount to a task or effort.\n**Farsi**: سهم عادلانه خود را انجام می‌دهد",
    "back": "does her fair share",
    "examples": [
      "She does her fair share."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c16dbb23-2831-4a53-8da4-fa0d70a8099d",
    "front": "**Def**: outstanding; serving as a perfect model (Positive remark, P).\n**Farsi**: نمونه، مثال‌زدنی",
    "back": "exemplary",
    "examples": [
      "His manners were exemplary."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d97f27e9-ef07-40e5-b856-829218f1ae50",
    "front": "**Def**: making people experience feelings of sadness, sympathy, etc. in a deliberate and obvious way.\n**Farsi**: احساساتی (با بار منفی)، آبکی",
    "back": "sentimental (DISAPPROVING)",
    "examples": [
      "It's a very sentimental film."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9c0d5895-7317-4b02-a4e9-a772fc76b112",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely bored.\n**Farsi**: از شدت بی‌حوصلگی (به ستوه آمدن)",
    "back": "bored to tears/death/stiff/out of your mind (idioms)",
    "examples": [
      "I was bored to tears after twenty minutes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "44511cb9-7171-4b79-be33-5020885fb7b5",
    "front": "**Def**: a sports match that is arranged to be played on a particular date.\n**Farsi**: برنامه مسابقات، بازی تعیین شده",
    "back": "fixture",
    "examples": [
      "Check the list of upcoming fixtures."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "863bc2ea-114b-4e63-b458-9609ef1be1f5",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who tries to get into a party without an invitation.\n**Farsi**: مهمان ناخوانده (که خود را تحمیل می‌کند)",
    "back": "gatecrasher",
    "examples": [
      "You don't want gatecrashers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "00821356-257e-4408-bfe8-8c14530fab03",
    "front": "**Def**: change gradually, often from something simple to something more complicated.\n**Farsi**: تکامل یافتن، متحول شدن",
    "back": "evolve",
    "examples": [
      "Democracy has evolved over hundreds of years."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "33bcbf9f-4b9f-4651-9c78-b1f257bc6058",
    "front": "**Def**: a fixed idea of what a particular type of person or thing is like, but which is often not true in reality.\n**Farsi**: کلیشه، انگاره قالبی",
    "back": "stereotype",
    "examples": [
      "they've seen beyond the stereotype."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "ccc9d33f-be9a-4a7e-88c1-6cb90febff80",
    "front": "**Def**: register to join a course, school, etc.\n**Farsi**: ثبت نام کردن",
    "back": "enrol SYN",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from register"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "072f14ae-1910-4bf1-ba1a-2ca2b0294144",
    "front": "**Def**: advice from another person (i.e. not the original doctor).\n**Farsi**: نظر دوم، مشورت با پزشک دیگر",
    "back": "second opinion",
    "examples": [
      "Can I request a second opinion?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "712c6571-51cf-46b2-9f4a-6b8382869ac4",
    "front": "**Def**: the organization that provides local government in a city or area.\n**Farsi**: شورا",
    "back": "council",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from definition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "576a7604-dd79-420e-86bd-0fb8029da0e6",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. make the best use of sth. 2. increase sth as much as possible. OPP minimize sth.\n**Farsi**: به حداکثر رساندن، بیشینه کردن",
    "back": "maximize sth",
    "examples": [
      "designed to maximize natural light"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "40757e99-6a37-4f51-9f4d-bdc3f184265b",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of people with the same culture or race living in a place where most people are of a different culture/race.\n**Farsi**: اقلیت قومی",
    "back": "ethnic minority",
    "examples": [
      "Ethnic minorities make up almost 10 per cent"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "84ba6e32-ae8c-43ea-bf2d-b4496dbcabd2",
    "front": "**Def**: give sth officially to sb/sth for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: اختصاص دادن، تخصیص دادن",
    "back": "allocate sth",
    "examples": [
      "Allocate better funding for youth projects"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d1e5f638-7fd0-4265-8f7f-90f7fff65d98",
    "front": "**Def**: A warrant issued for arrest.\n**Farsi**: حکم جلب",
    "back": "arrest warrant",
    "examples": [
      "Implied from warrant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b8d986e9-b1ff-4cbf-ba68-1f7c67de2c7a",
    "front": "**Def**: good or true reasons for saying or doing sth (reasonable grounds for sth, on the grounds that ...).\n**Farsi**: دلایل، شواهد (کافی)",
    "back": "grounds (for sth) PL, FML",
    "examples": [
      "if they have reasonable grounds for suspecting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "13d37b7f-f7ee-43c7-97db-7f033009a0fc",
    "front": "**Def**: money left with a court to ensure that a prisoner will return for their trial (a judge releases sb on bail/grants bail or refuses bail).\n**Farsi**: وثیقه، ضمانت",
    "back": "bail",
    "examples": [
      "or released on bail."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "52058242-ab15-4cb6-ae18-fb90fa72dc9d",
    "front": "**Def**: a holiday where you cook your own meals.\n**Farsi**: خدمات غذایی بر عهده مشتری (سلف کترینگ)",
    "back": "self-catering",
    "examples": [
      "The management course is based on self-catering."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "99dffffa-790e-4dd1-b593-65b7533ee41a",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially AME) relating to members of the armed forces below officer rank (to enlist is to join the armed forces).\n**Farsi**: سرباز عادی، ثبت نام شده در نیروهای مسلح",
    "back": "enlisted (people or things)",
    "examples": [
      "The enlisted ranks receive lower pay."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "eedb99cb-1aed-4563-965e-5b2433d007c4",
    "front": "**Def**: move (goods) illegally into or out of a country.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق کردن",
    "back": "smuggle",
    "examples": [
      "They tried to smuggle diamonds."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "efdc4e1a-c2de-40f0-81f0-4816a1afdc01",
    "front": "**Def**: crime committed by professional criminals working in large groups.\n**Farsi**: جرم سازمان‌یافته",
    "back": "organized crime",
    "examples": [
      "organized criminal involvement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "dc5a1e1d-c745-427c-bfb1-f3e85fa8d8ec",
    "front": "**Def**: change sth so it is the opposite of what it was before (reverse a decision/trend/policy, etc.).\n**Farsi**: معکوس کردن، تغییر جهت دادن",
    "back": "reverse sth",
    "examples": [
      "They were going to let him go, but they reversed their decision."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "35fde5b9-013b-47ae-b964-458ef4e4cd0a",
    "front": "**Def**: a bowl-shaped pan, used to stir-fry vegetables, meat, fish.\n**Farsi**: وک (تابه عمیق چینی)",
    "back": "wok",
    "examples": [
      "We used a wok to stir-fry the chicken and vegetables."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a3212136-a605-4d3a-878a-20a7f294617d",
    "front": "**Def**: rise suddenly and quickly. SYN rocket.\n**Farsi**: اوج گرفتن، جهش کردن",
    "back": "soar",
    "examples": [
      "Share prices have soared."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "235db595-449d-4fc9-bb22-7159c32b3eb6",
    "front": "**Def**: fall by a large amount. slump N (economic slump OPP economic boom).\n**Farsi**: سقوط شدید، رکود",
    "back": "slump",
    "examples": [
      "The price has slumped to its lowest level."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "da19340e-e8dd-4096-89fb-761fabe452c4",
    "front": "**Def**: a person whose political views are generally not considered to be normal or reasonable (far-reaching).\n**Farsi**: افراطی چپ‌گرا",
    "back": "left-wing extremist",
    "examples": [
      "They classify him as a left-wing extremist."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a7c1f780-1c18-49c9-9e62-3e29980e408b",
    "front": "**Def**: fail or succeed (without help).\n**Farsi**: شکست خوردن یا موفق شدن (به حال خود رها شدن)",
    "back": "sink or swim",
    "examples": [
      "The test will make them sink or swim."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d9fb1761-83ff-4680-b4db-b9d43273de97",
    "front": "**Def**: being watched and examined very carefully (under the microscope).\n**Farsi**: زیر ذره‌بین بودن، با دقت بررسی شدن",
    "back": "microscope",
    "examples": [
      "The trade secretary could find herself under the microscope."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "578acc58-d535-4263-bda3-e99bf0747615",
    "front": "**Def**: the system of rules and acceptable behaviour in a formal situation.\n**Farsi**: تشریفات، آیین‌نامه، دستورالعمل",
    "back": "protocol",
    "examples": [
      "He failed to follow diplomatic protocol."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "76e39a55-e7d7-4541-b4ad-552fa5129ccf",
    "front": "**Def**: put tasks, problems, etc. in order of importance and do the most important first. priority N (high/low/top priority).\n**Farsi**: اولویت‌بندی کردن",
    "back": "prioritize",
    "examples": [
      "Do you prioritize ruthlessly."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "924fcc2f-dbfc-48e7-9bbb-a550ad5d66ab",
    "front": "**Def**: Set is used with many nouns, often meaning to fix something for others to copy, e.g. set an example, set a standard, set a record, set a precedent. It can also mean to decide on something, as in set a date/limit.\n**Farsi**: تعیین کردن (تاریخ/محدودیت/رویه)",
    "back": "set a date/limit/precedent",
    "examples": [
      "Set a date for strikes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "b1e4bb6e-3309-40bb-9996-bd17a9747b4a",
    "front": "**Def**: used to suggest that the way one event leads to another is so obvious that it does not need to be stated.\n**Farsi**: یک چیز به چیز دیگری منجر می‌شود (تسلسل وقایع)",
    "back": "one thing leads to another",
    "examples": [
      "One thing led to another and I found myself the owner of a new car."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1237295e-bd10-4d1e-b2db-01df1af636ee",
    "front": "**Def**: react too strongly to sth, especially sth unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: واکنش بیش از حد نشان دادن",
    "back": "overreact (to sth)",
    "examples": [
      "I realize I overreacted."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "c5d7d6bf-f856-4248-af70-f4385a62d1a7",
    "front": "**Def**: say things that are only partially true (used as a euphemism for 'lie').\n**Farsi**: حقیقت را ناگفته گذاشتن (کم‌گویی کردن)",
    "back": "be economical with the truth",
    "examples": [
      "I was once economical with the truth on a job application form."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a32429ef-118e-45f1-ab25-41c7ae129780",
    "front": "**Def**: If problems confront sb, they appear and have to be dealt with by sb. (SYN face sb).\n**Farsi**: روبرو شدن (مشکلات با کسی)",
    "back": "confront sb",
    "examples": [
      "There are a number of problems confronting the head teacher."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "36516734-9eb4-42cf-b293-c8d51a339b94",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth gets you down it makes you feel sad or depressed.\n**Farsi**: کسی را افسرده کردن/مایوس کردن",
    "back": "get sb down",
    "examples": [
      "Others let it get them down."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "9f6a959e-d29d-49a6-b393-a878723d7d98",
    "front": "**Def**: the most advanced (technology) in the field.\n**Farsi**: تکنولوژی پیشرفته/مدرن‌ترین",
    "back": "cutting-edge (technology)",
    "examples": [
      "cutting-edge technology at its very best."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "f71c07e4-3d68-41d8-bcd5-ed21db450fd5",
    "front": "**Def**: all the verbs describe the process of time; elapse is FML; pass and go by are often used with an adverb to describe how time happens.\n**Farsi**: (زمان) گذشتن/سپری شدن",
    "back": "pass / elapse / go by",
    "examples": [
      "Two years passed / elapsed / went by before I saw her again."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ffc76a-f32b-42c7-92fd-dffa2714d14f",
    "front": "**Def**: be looking at or thinking about something so that you are unable to pay attention to other things.\n**Farsi**: حواس‌پرتی پیدا کردن، پرت شدن حواس توسط چیزی",
    "back": "be distracted by sth",
    "examples": [
      "I won't be distracted by cheap offers."
    ]
  }
]